‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In the last lesson, we have set up our MongoDB database.
‫What we're going to do now is we are going to fill it in with some sample data that we are then going
‫to be querying from our Nestjs endpoint.
‫So for populating the database, we are going to be using a small script that we already have prepared
‫and we are going to be inserting this same data that we have been displaying here on the screen, which
‫is coming from the DB data file.
‫So in order to upload this data directly to MongoDB, we are going to need the script that is available
‫here under the rest API folder.
‫We will see here a file called Populate DB Dot TS.
‫This is going to contain our database population script that we will need to insert our data into the
‫database.
‫Now this is a very simple script that uses the MongoDB client API for inserting the data in the database.
‫You will find here some instructions on how to use this script, but it's actually very simple.
‫You are going to need to build here a connection URL string and you are going to replace it here on
‫this constant.
‫Let's see how we are going to build this string.
‫We are going to switch over here to the MongoDB console and we are going to click here on clusters.
‫From here we are going to click on the button Connect and here we are going to choose one of multiple
‫methods for connecting to the database.
‫Let's click here on Connect Your Application and from here we are going to see the connection string
‫that we are going to need.
‫So as you can see, we have here a URL that has the username that we want to use in this case Nestjs
‫Dash admin, which is our only administrator user.
‫We need to put in here our password.
‫So we need to put the password after the colon sign and before the at sign.
‫So we need to delete this angle brackets.
‫Otherwise this will not work.
‫And here we have the cluster name and a couple more options.
‫So let's copy this string and let's paste it here.
‫In our workspace, we are going to replace this MongoDB connection with the string that we got here
‫from the MongoDB console.
‫So we have here the correct username Nestjs dash admin.
‫We now need to delete here the password and the angle brackets that we saw there and fill in here the
‫password between the colon and the at sign.
‫So you can see here an example of how to fill this in.
‫And as you can see, the password is here between the colon and the at sign without any further characters
‫in between.
‫So please go ahead and fill in your password here.
‫Let's say that your password would be test one, two, three.
‫Then this is how your connection string would look like.
‫If by some reason you forgot your password, you can always change it by switching here to the MongoDB
‫console.
‫We are going to go ahead and click here on database Access and we can select here the user that we have
‫created, Nestjs Dash Admin.
‫We click here on edit and we can change the password using here.
‫Edit Password.
‫Notice that when you click edit password, you can autogenerate here a secure password and if you want
‫to see it, you need to click here on show.
‫So this is not the password that I will be using throughout the course.
‫It's just an example.
‫Once you have your password set up, we are going to click now on Cancel and we are now going to go
‫back to our workspace and we are going to run the database population script.
‫Everything is ready to go.
‫So from the rest API folder that you need to make sure that you are in, you are going to be running
‫the following command NPM run populate dash DB.
‫Let's hit enter.
‫After a while this command is going to start inserting some data on the database.
‫We can see here the different type of data that is getting inserted.
‫We can see the courses and the lessons.
‫We see some of the IDs getting generated.
‫And this should only take a moment at the end.
‫We are going to be creating here some indexes and the process will exit successfully.
‫So if we now switch back here to the MongoDB console, we are going to see the data by clicking here
‫on clusters.
‫And from there we are going to click on collections.
‫As we can see now, we have here a Nestjs course database with two collections in it.
‫We have here the courses collection and we have the lessons collection.
‫So a collection is a group of related documents.
‫We can see here the courses.
‫So as you can see, they all have more or less the same fields.
‫We have an ID for each course, which is unique.
‫We have the description, a long description.
‫ET cetera.
‫And the same thing goes for lessons.
‫So each lesson has its own unique identifier, which is this object ID that we will be talking more
‫throughout the course.
‫We have also here some data.
‫Fields such as the description, the duration, etcetera.
‫And we have the course to which the lesson belongs to.
‫We can see here, for example, that this lesson document belongs to the course with this particular
‫ID.
‫So this is how in mongodb we do a one to many relation.
‫Its by using this object identifiers that we see here.
‫Again, more on this later.
‫Right now as we have data here ready to go in our database, we are now going to see how can we query
‫this data from our nestjs process.
‫Again, throughout the course we are going to be talking about documents, collections, how they relate
‫together, how can we link a document to another collection, etcetera.
‫All of that will be covered later on during the course.