‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In the last few lessons, we have set up our MongoDB database and we have populated it with some data
‫that we will be displaying here on the screen.
‫So the data is coming from this DB data file that contains here some test data with courses and lessons.
‫Now in our courses controller, instead of fetching our data directly from the test file, we are now
‫going to query the MongoDB database.
‫Now we could do this using the MongoDB package that you already have installed.
‫So this is the MongoDB official driver package that allows us to query the database.
‫Now, instead of using the MongoDB package directly, we are going to use a more convenient API.
‫We are going to be using mongoose that you can see at Mongoose Wjz.com.
‫So this is an object modeling package for MongoDB and Node.
‫So what does this do exactly?
‫This is a way of interacting with MongoDB that is closer to what you are used to.
‫If you have been using something such as, for example, an ORM or an object relational mapping library.
‫So this is the equivalent.
‫But for MongoDB, so MongoDB is not a relational database.
‫Instead it's a document database.
‫So the documents that we have here in our collections don't have a fixed structure, unlike typical
‫tables.
‫So if I edit here a document, I could potentially add here a new field that is not any of these fields
‫here.
‫So let's create here a new field called Test Field and let's fill it in with some data.
‫So as we can see, if we click now on update, this particular document in the MongoDB database has
‫a field that no other document contains.
‫So the MongoDB database is schemaless.
‫There is nothing at the level of the database itself ensuring that a given collection only has documents
‫with a certain predefined number of fields.
‫So this has advantages and disadvantages.
‫One of the advantages compared to SQL databases is that we will never run into the problem of having
‫to bring our production database down in order to run, for example, an altar colon statement to add
‫a new column that in a table with, let's say, 70 or 100 million records could take several hours with
‫the MongoDB database.
‫This will never happen.
‫On the other hand, there is the trade off that potentially our program could insert data into the database
‫that is an intended, for example, due to a bug.
‫So let's edit here again this field and let's remove this test field.
‫This is actually quite important.
‫If you don't do this, your program might crash later on because we are going to be adding some schema
‫like capability on the client by using the Mongoose library.
‫So the Mongoose library is going to allow us to write our program, ensuring that objects belonging
‫to a certain category such as, for example, courses or lessons, always follow a given schema so we
‫can get some sort of equivalent schema functionality.
‫But on the client that is querying the database and not on the database itself.
‫Now implementing this on the client does not ensure the security of the data, but it's a great way
‫for avoiding that.
‫Unintended bugs corrupt our database.
‫So let's have a look here at the Mongoose API.
‫When we initialize here the Mongoose package, we need to pass it a connection string.
‫As you can see, it's a promise based API and we can use it for defining data models.
‫For example, here we are defining the cat model, which only has one field, which is a string.
‫So as you can see, we can be very specific.
‫We can say that this field has this given name and this given type and that the cat model only has this
‫field called name and no other fields.
‫This means that if we would try to use the cat model to create here a cat that has any other field besides
‫the name, let's say that we would try to add here a second field called age.
‫This would not be possible.
‫Mongoose would throw us an error here in this code line.
‫Now, Mongoose also follows the active record pattern so we can edit here our kitty variable by changing,
‫for example, the name.
‫And when we are ready to save this back to the database, we can call the dot save method, which will
‫return us a promise that will be successfully evaluated whenever the data has been saved to the database.
‫Mongoose also supports relations between colons such as one to many relations, so it's a very good
‫tool to have in order to interact with the MongoDB database without using its low level API provided
‫by the MongoDB package.
‫So in our program we are going to be accessing our.
‫It was always with the Mongoose object modeling library.
‫In your local workspace, you have already installed mongoose at the beginning of the course, so everything
‫is ready to go.
‫Let's now learn how can we use Mongoose to define the schema of the course entity?