‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to set up the Mongoose object data modeling tool that we are going
‫to be using to interact with MongoDB.
‫We are going to learn how to set it up in our nestjs backend.
‫So the first thing that we are going to do is to define a mongoose schema for our courses entity.
‫So here in our shared folder we are going to see code that is shared between our backend and our front
‫end.
‫And typically this will include data structures such as the course entity.
‫We can see that we have here an ID which contains the underscore ID identifier, which is typical of
‫MongoDB.
‫And we have here a series of other fields.
‫So this type of entity definitions allows us to write our programs in a type safe way.
‫If we want to add a field to an entity, we can easily do so here and the compiler will tell us all
‫the places in our application that we need to refactor.
‫Now we want to make sure that our backend server does not accidentally add any field to a course object.
‫That is not part of this list here.
‫So we want to add a way of adding some sort of schema validation functionality to our backend and that's
‫what Mongoose is going to bring us.
‫So let's then introduce Mongoose in our application.
‫We are going to go to the rest API folder and here inside the courses module we are going to create
‫here a new folder.
‫This folder is going to be called Schemas and it's going to contain all our mongoose schemas.
‫Let's create here a new file.
‫We are going to call it courses, dot schema, dot ts.
‫Now inside it we are going to define the Mongoose schema for the course entity.
‫Let's start by importing Mongoose.
‫We are going to import star as mongoose from Mongoose.
‫Now using Mongoose, we are going to define our first schema.
‫Let's call it the course schema and let's create it by calling new Mongoose dot schema to the schema
‫constructor.
‫We need to pass in a configuration object.
‫This configuration object is going to contain all the fields of this entity.
‫So here we should not add an ID field.
‫That field is going to be implicitly added by mongoose, but there are other fields here that we need
‫to define, such as, for example, the sequential number.
‫We can see that the sequential number should be a number.
‫So let's see how can we define it.
‫We need to define here a property called Segno, which should be of type number.
‫So it's important to use here the capital form of the number type and not the lowercase TypeScript type.
‫So this will not work.
‫You need to use the number type, which is the number constructor of the JavaScript runtime.
‫This is being used by Mongoose to assign a given type to this variable.
‫In the same way that we have defined the sequential number field as being a number, we can also define,
‫for example, the URL field as being a string.
‫And again, it's important to use the capital string type, which is the type provided by the JavaScript
‫runtime.
‫So this is different than the lowercase string type, which is TypeScript specific.
‫We need to use this particular constructor function, otherwise mongoose will not work.
‫And in a similar way to how we have defined these two fields, we can also define the remaining fields
‫of the course entity I have just pasted in here a few more fields.
‫So with these fields defined we are going to make sure that our program does not accidentally insert
‫on the database invalid data.
‫Let's now see how can we take this mongoose schema and plug it into our nestjs backend in order to integrate
‫Mongoose with Nestjs, we are going to be using the Mongoose module.
‫So let's head over here to our application root module from our backend under the rest folder and let's
‫import here a new module.
‫This module is simply called mongoose dot module.
‫So if you check here the import this comes from the Nestjs slash Mongoose scoped package.
‫So this is the correct module that we need.
‫Now.
‫This is the root module.
‫So we are going to be configuring here the root application services.
‫Let's then call here for root.
‫And now we need to pass in here the connection string so that mongoose can connect to our database using
‫the MongoDB package.
‫Now you can grab the connection string here from the populate DB script that you have prepared before.
‫So if you remember here in this constant, you have defined here a connection string that you needed
‫for connecting to the MongoDB database.
‫So that is the same string that we need to use here.
‫I'm going to define it via a constant.
‫I'm going to call it Mongo connection and I'm going to be defining this constant here in a separate
‫file called Constants.
‫Let's create this new file here and inside it, we are going to be defining a new constant called Mongo
‫underscore connection.
‫And here we are going to paste our connection string.
‫Now, at this point, please notice one thing, and this is very important.
‫Notice that the connection string that we copied is currently linking us here to the test database.
‫So this is a special database in MongoDB that is used for testing purposes, but this is not the database
‫that we want to use.
‫Instead, we want to use the database called Nestjs course, if you remember, this is the name of the
‫database under which we have stored the courses and lessons collections.
‫So if you don't edit this and put in here the correct name of the database later on in the course,
‫whenever you are doing database queries, you might be surprised that you are not finding any values
‫even though your database is populated.
‫So we want to avoid that.
‫Please make sure that you replace here the word test by the correct name of the database.
‫That should be Nestjs Dash course.
‫Now we are going to go back here to the application module and we are going to import our constant.
‫So this is a simple way of configuring the connection string in our program.
‫A better way of doing this that you would usually use in a production application would be to fetch
‫this connection string from an environment variable.
‫But here, just for simplicity purposes, I'm going to define it using this constants file.
‫So now we have defined here the root services of the Mongoose module.
‫We now need to go to the courses module, which is a feature module of our Nestjs backend application
‫and we need to configure here the course schema.
‫We can do so by importing here again the Mongoose module, but this time by calling here for feature
‫inside for feature, we are going to be passing in an array of schema definitions.
‫So each schema definition is an object that contains a name which is going to be the name of the entity
‫to which we want to add the schema, in this case, the course entity.
‫And we also need to define here the schema.
‫So the schema is going to be the courses schema constant that we have defined here.
‫Let's then import it here.
‫And with this we have included the courses schema in our database.
‫So with this, the Mongoose module is going to make available a series of services that is going to
‫make it very simple to interact with the course collection using Mongoose.
‫Let's now see how can we use Mongoose to implement a complete Crud example for the course entity?
‫We are going to see how to use Mongoose to query courses from the database.
‫We are going to see how to create new courses, update existing ones and delete them as well.