‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to learn how to use Mongoose to fetch data from our MongoDB database
‫and return it here in this call to this rest endpoint.
‫Now, one way of doing it would be to simply inject here the Mongoose module for the courses entity
‫and use it to query the database.
‫However, we are not going to do that.
‫Instead, we are going to write all our queries for the courses entity in a separate class called a
‫repository, and we are going to name it the courses repository.
‫The reason why we are doing that is because any query that we might write here inside the courses controller
‫might also be needed elsewhere in the application.
‫So we want to write the query only once and reuse the query code whenever we need it.
‫Elsewhere in the application, the repository pattern is a very commonly used pattern in other frameworks.
‫So let's see how this pattern looks like in Nestjs.
‫We are going to start by heading over here to our courses module and here we are going to be defining
‫a new type of service.
‫So we are going to create here a new folder that we are going to call repositories.
‫So this is going to contain the multiple repositories of our Nestjs module, typically one per entity.
‫So at the end of the course we should have here a courses repository and a lessons repository.
‫Let's then create here a new file.
‫We are going to call it courses dot repository, dot TS.
‫Now this file is a plain injectable service just like any other.
‫Let's go ahead and define here a new class called Courses Repository.
‫And let's add it the injectable decorator from Nestjs.
‫Now, before implementing the code for this repository service, let's configure it here in our courses
‫module.
‫So here in our courses module we are going to be using here the providers property to which we are going
‫to assign an array and here we are going to add our courses repository service.
‫So this way the courses module knows about the courses repository.
‫So what type of methods do we find typically in the repository service?
‫Well, we are going to find the typical Crud operations for a given entity or a set of related entities.
‫For example, our courses controller would need here a way of querying a list of courses from our MongoDB
‫database.
‫So we should expect to find here in the courses repository a new method called find all, for example,
‫that would provide as a value A courses array.
‫And let's import here the correct course class.
‫Again from the shared folder.
‫Let's annotate this method with the async keyword meaning that we are going to be supporting in the
‫method body.
‫The async await syntax.
‫Now, what other type of methods should we find here?
‫In the typical repository class, we would find methods for for example, updating an existing course,
‫deleting a course or adding a new course.
‫So the typical Crud operations for this entity, let's then in this lesson implement here, find all
‫using mongoose.
‫For that we are going to be injecting here via the constructor the Mongoose model for the course entity.
‫Let's define here a constructor.
‫And just like in the case of our front end, our back end also works using dependency injection.
‫So we are going to be able to inject here a course model service that is of type model.
‫Of course, now this model is going to be a mongoose model.
‫So let's make sure that we import from the mongoose package, the model type.
‫So this course model service that is getting injected here has been created here by mongoose.
‫So whenever we configured here using forfeiture, the course entity with the courses schema, we have
‫implicitly created a model service specific to this entity that we are now injecting in our repository
‫via the constructor using dependency injection, just like in the front end.
‫Let's now have a look at what type of functionality we have available via the model.
‫Using the model, we have multiple find operations.
‫We can do a find here using the find method, using a series of optional parameters.
‫We can do a find by ID and we can even do things such as find and remove.
‫We also have other methods available such as, for example, update or update one update many for modifying
‫data.
‫And we have all the typical Crud functionalities such as, for example, the ability of deleting courses
‫from the database and of creating new ones.
‫So in the case of our find all method, what we want to do is do a call here to find and because we
‫are finding all the documents in the collection, we don't need to specify here any extra parameters
‫later on in the course.
‫We are going to show how to do a find by adding here some extra conditions.
‫But in this case, because the Mongoose API is promise based, we already have here a promise that emits
‫values which are courses arrays.
‫This means that we have completed here the implementation of our find all query method.
‫So by injecting the courses repository anywhere on the application, we are going to be able to use
‫this query whenever we need it without using directly the Mongoose model.
‫Now, in this case, the benefit of refactoring this query here to the find all method is not large,
‫but in more complex queries with a lot of parameters.
‫This is going to save us a lot of code in order to be able to use the find all method in our courses
‫controller we're going to have to inject here in the constructor the repository.
‫Let's then add here a constructor and we're going to create here a new member variable that we are going
‫to call courses.
‫DB And to wit, we are going to assign the courses repository.
‫So with this we have here the course repository ready to be used.
‫So we can now use it here and call the find all method.
‫So this is going to return a promise of course array that we can return here as the output of find all
‫courses.
‫We are going to explain further on in this course the exact difference between separating our logic
‫between repository classes and controller classes.
‫Right now we want to go ahead and test this new implementation and confirm that the data is now indeed
‫coming from the database as expected.
‫Now, before trying this out, let's fix here a small problem in the implementation of our repository,
‫which has to do with injection here of the course model.
‫So specifying here that this is a model of course would not be enough for the dependency injection system
‫to identify exactly which mongoose model to inject.
‫So besides providing here this type definition, we also need to add here a decorator called inject
‫model.
‫So inject model needs to be imported from nestjs slash mongoose.
‫And we need to provide here the name of the mongoose model that we want to inject.
‫So the dependency injection system is going to be able to determine then that it's this model here linked
‫to the course entity using this particular schema that we want to inject here in our repository.
‫So it's this string course that makes the link between the two things.
‫And with this, we are now ready to test our database query.
‫Let's then open here the terminal and from inside the rest folder we are going to run the command NPM
‫run server.
‫This is going to start the server in hot reload mode.
‫Now we are going to go ahead and open a second terminal and we are going to access the endpoint slash
‫API slash courses which corresponds here to our courses Controller.
‫If we do that, we are going to see here on the screen that indeed we are fetching the data from the
‫MongoDB database as expected.
‫So this data is no longer coming from an in-memory object that we had here in the server at the level
‫of our courses controller.
‫Instead, we are querying the MongoDB database and we are sending back the results to the front end.
‫Let's now continue the implementation of our courses Controller.
‫We are going to be adding the remaining Crud operations and we are also going to be adding common features
‫such as, for example, input parameter validation and error handling in general.