‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to continue our complete grid example for the courses entity.
‫On the previous lessons we have shown how to handle, get requests and retrieve data from the MongoDB
‫database.
‫In this lesson, we are going to show how to update existing data.
‫So whenever we click here on the edit button and edit course dialog is going to show up.
‫Whenever we click on the save button of that dialog, we are going to be triggering an Http post request
‫to the backend.
‫Let's have a look at the code of the edit course dialog.
‫We can find it here on this folder under the courses module.
‫So this is front end code and not back end code.
‫So as you can see in this implementation of this angular component, we are going to be editing the
‫course using a simple form.
‫So if we have a look here at the HTML template of the edit course component, we can see here that we
‫have a form with a couple of fields that correspond to the multiple properties of the course entity
‫at the bottom of the form.
‫We are going to have here a button that is going to trigger the on save method.
‫And if we have a look here at the implementation of On Save, we are going to see that the dialog does
‫have two modes.
‫It can be in update mode or in creation mode, and each of the modes is going to trigger here a different
‫method of the courses Http service.
‫If we have a look at this service, it's a plain angular service that uses the angular Http client for
‫implementing common Crud operations such as, for example, find all courses.
‫So this is, for example, where our application is calling our slash API slash courses get endpoint
‫which corresponds to this find all courses method here in the Nestjs courses controller.
‫Now, in a similar way, our application is also going to contact the backend by calling here update
‫course.
‫So as you can see, this is doing an Http put request to the backend to slash API slash courses and
‫we are going to be appending the course ID at the end of this URL.
‫We are also going to pass as the body of the put http request.
‫What is the changes that we want to perform on the course entity and we are going to get back from the
‫server, the new version of this entity.
‫We are going to see this Http put request in the network console in a moment.
‫Right now this request would not work because our controller is not yet handling put requests.
‫Let's then implement the logic that would handle such a request.
‫Here in our courses controller, we are going to be defining a new method that we are going to be calling
‫simply update course.
‫Let's start by annotating this method with the put decorator that comes from Nestjs.
‫So here we are going to be specifying what is the URL that we want to update.
‫So in our case, the URL would look something like slash API slash courses and then here we would have
‫the course ID appended at the end of the URL.
‫Now we are going to need to retrieve this value from the URL.
‫So let's use here the colon syntax and let's define here a new variable.
‫So this variable here is going to be filled in from this value here at the end of the URL in order that
‫we see that the update course method is getting called, Let's add here some logging as well.
‫Now we are going to be using the Nestjs API to retrieve everything that we need out of the Http request
‫that we got here.
‫So the first thing that we are going to need is to identify which course do we want to update and we
‫are going to be retrieving that from this variable in order to inject the course ID here in our update
‫course method, let's define here a course ID variable.
‫This is going to be a string.
‫And let's tell to Nestjs that this needs to be retrieved from the URL.
‫So for that we are going to be using the param decorator now to the param decorator.
‫We need to pass in here as a string the name of the variable that we need.
‫So in this case we are going to be retrieving here the course ID variable that was identified here using
‫the colon syntax.
‫Now, besides the ID of the course that we need to update, we also need to get the changes that we
‫want to perform on the database and we are going to get that as a Json payload from the body of the
‫Http put request.
‫So let's for that define here a new variable we are going to call it changes and we are going to say
‫that this is a partial course, so not all the properties will be updated each time for the course entity
‫we might receive here only some properties of this course entity.
‫Let's say that for example, we would get only these two properties updated and the others would remain
‫unchanged.
‫So we could potentially receive here a partial version of the course entity.
‫And that's why we are using here the partial class.
‫Now we need to tell to nestjs that the changes variable should come from the body of the Http request.
‫So for that we are going to be adding here the nestjs body decorator.
‫As we can see with Nestjs using these decorators, it's very simple to get everything that we need from
‫the Http request.
‫We can easily inject values in our methods from the URL, from the body of the request.
‫We can even get values directly from Http headers using, for example, the headers decorator that will
‫take here the name of the Http header that we want to read from.
‫We can get values also from URL query parameters using the query decorator as we will see later on in
‫this course.
‫So as you can see, it's really simple to parse the Http request using Nestjs.
‫Notice that under the hood Nestjs is using express, so if by some reason you would need access to the
‫complete express request object, you can also inject it here very easily.
‫So you just have to define here a variable request and then you need to annotate this variable with
‫the decorator at req.
‫So it's an abbreviated name meaning request so that it doesn't conflict with the request type from Express
‫and the similarly named type from many other libraries as it's a very common name.
‫You can also get here the response using the add res decorator from Nestjs and you would get injected
‫here the response express object.
‫So you can even annotate these two variables with the corresponding express types.
‫If you have the express types installed, like in the case of the sample project.
‫So you can annotate the request variable using this type request from Express.
‫You can also annotate here the response using the response from Express as well.
‫And you can now use here Autocompletion for example, to see what we have available.
‫So for example, here we have available request dot body, we have request dot query.
‫So we have all the usual properties of an express request and response object available if we need to.
‫But if we don't need direct access to these objects, then in that case we can use these decorators
‫here to get directly only the parameters that we need from the request in a more declarative way.
‫So here, final courses is not going to be using the request and the response directly.
‫So let's go ahead and delete this and continue the implementation of our update course endpoint.