‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In the last lesson we have implemented the controller part of our update course, Crud Operation Logic.
‫Now let's implement the repository part and see the whole Crud operation in action.
‫So now that we have here everything that we need from the request in order to update the course, we
‫need to call here our courses repository and trigger a data modification at the level of the database.
‫So let's go ahead and call here the courses DB service and here we are going to be creating a new method
‫called Update course.
‫Let's define here what the API of this method is going to look like.
‫We are going to be passing here as the first parameter, the ID of the entity that we want to update.
‫And as the second parameter, we are going to be passing the changes that we want to save on the database.
‫Let's then create a new method on our courses repository with this signature.
‫So the first parameter is going to be a course ID string, and the second parameter is going to be a
‫partial course.
‫Let's also define the return type of this new method.
‫So we are receiving here the course and its changes and we are going to send back a promise of a course.
‫So we are going to emit here in this promise the new version of the course entity.
‫This should contain a course with all the fields, just like they are in the database.
‫So the course that we emit here is going to be the new version of the course in the database after the
‫update.
‫So let's see, how can we get the new version of the course using Mongoose?
‫Let's first perform the update we're going to access here the course model service.
‫And in order to trigger the update of a single entity, we are going to be using the method, find one
‫and update.
‫So it's just one of several methods available via the Mongoose API.
‫So the first thing that we need to pass to this method is going to be the ID of the course that we want
‫to update.
‫We are going to do a lookup by ID and we are going to say that the MongoDB underscore ID property is
‫going to be identical to the course ID that we got here from the Http request.
‫Now the second thing that we need to pass here are the changes that we want to apply to the MongoDB
‫version of this object.
‫So let's pass in here the partial changes that we received from the body of the Http put request.
‫Now the last thing that we need to do is to pass in here a configuration object to this Mongoose API
‫call that is going to say that we want to receive back as the result of this method a promise that when
‫evaluated is going to emit the new version of the course as it exists on the database after the update
‫has completed.
‫So in order to say that we need here the new version of the course, we are going to set the new flag
‫to true.
‫And this is going to get us back the new version of the course in the database After the update.
‫Let's return this as the output of this update course method.
‫And with this, we have completed the repository part of our Crud update operation.
‫Going back here to our controller, we are now receiving here a promise that is currently being ignored.
‫So we should return this promise to Nestjs as a promise.
‫Of course.
‫This way Nestjs knows that when this promise is evaluated, the request is completed.
‫Let's annotate here this method and specify that we are returning here.
‫A promise, of course.
‫And with this we have completed the crud update operation for the course entity.
‫Let's now try everything out.
‫Let's switch here to a larger window and let's trigger the Http put request.
‫So we're going to select here the first course of our list, the Nestjs course.
‫And let's change here.
‫For example, the title.
‫Let's rename the title to simply Nestjs in practice.
‫Now let's keep an eye here on the network log.
‫Let's filter here on slash API and let's click here on Save.
‫So as you can see, an Http put request was issued to the back end.
‫We can see here on the request URL that this is indeed hitting here, the slash API slash courses,
‫endpoint and appending here at the end of the URL, the ID of the course.
‫If we scroll down, we are going to see here that in the request payload we have here the new version
‫of the course object that we send to the back end.
‫Now the back end has saved the data in the database and when the dialog got closed, we reloaded the
‫data from the back end and we get here the new title.
‫So let's switch here to the MongoDB database console and confirm that the new data is indeed in the
‫database.
‫Let's hit here refresh and on the courses.
‫Election.
‫Let's scroll down and look for the correct course.
‫So here at the bottom, we are going to see that the data is now correctly saved on the database as
‫expected.
‫Now, before continuing with the other two Crud operations, delete and create.
‫Let's first remove here some repetition from our controller.
‫You can see that all the requests on the controller are going to start with slash API and in fact any
‫other controller in our application is going to use this prefix.
‫So instead of repeating the prefix here for each of the requests, we are going to remove it and we
‫are going to define it in only one place.
‫So switching here to our back end Main.ts file containing the bootstrap method.
‫And remember there is a similarly named file for the front end.
‫So we want here the main.ts file for the back end.
‫And here using the app instance, we want to set here our global prefix and let's set this to API.
‫So any controller that runs for this application is going to have its end points available under slash
‫API.
‫Next, we need to specify here at the level of our controller that we are handling the courses entity.
‫So we don't want to repeat here the name of the entity each time.
‫Let's remove this then here from the get and the put annotations and let's add it here at the level
‫of the controller.
‫So this controller should handle the courses entity.
‫Let's now try this out and confirm that everything is still working.
‫So if we reload here, our front end, we are going to see that we are still getting back here.
‫The data.
‫Now let's rename the course again to Nestjs in practice course.
‫Let's click Save.
‫And as we can see, we are now getting back the new title again from the database as expected.
‫So as you can see, this way of annotating our controllers, it's a bit more concise and avoids repetition
‫and makes it easier to refactor our URLs if needed.
‫Let's now continue to implement our complete Crud example.
‫We are going to cover the delete and create operations and after that we are going to be adding common
‫features to our endpoints such as error handling, authentication and more.