‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to implement the delete Crud functionality for the courses entity
‫in our Nestjs controller.
‫So here in our user interface, whenever we click on the delete button of a given course, this should
‫trigger a database delete.
‫In order to do that, we are going to be dispatching an Http delete controller to the backend that we
‫need to somehow handle here in our controller.
‫So let's define here a new method, also an async method that we're going to be calling delete course.
‫So we are going to be needing to annotate this method with the nestjs delete decorator.
‫Let's now see what the Http delete request will look like when it's sent from the front end so we can
‫find the logic that handles here our delete button.
‫In the following component we are going to look for courses card list component.
‫So here is where we are going to find the front end logic that handles the deletion of a course.
‫And as we can see, this is simply calling the delete course method in our courses Http service.
‫This is using the Http client in order to issue an Http delete to our back end to this particular URL
‫slash api slash courses course ID.
‫So this is the only thing that we need to grab from the request the course ID, let's then switch back
‫here to our controller and add here like we did here for the case of the update course logic, a new
‫variable that is going to grab the course ID and let's also inject it here as a string on the delete
‫course method.
‫Now let's implement the controller logic for the delete operation.
‫We are going to add here some logging and we are going to just like before access here courses.
‫DB And we are going to call a new method that we are about to create called delete course to delete
‫course method.
‫We simply need to pass the course ID Let's go ahead and define here the method with this signature.
‫So this is going to take here only one variable named course ID just like before.
‫We are going to be using Mongoose in order to perform the Delete we are going to access here the course
‫model and we are going to call delete one to the delete one method.
‫We are going to specify here what is the ID of the course that we want to delete.
‫And let's specify here that the underscore ID property should have the course ID value that we got from
‫the Http request.
‫So with this we have completed here the implementation of our deletion and as usual, delete one is
‫going to return a promise that will be successfully evaluated whenever the deletion occurs on the database.
‫So that's what we want to return here as the output of our delete course controller method.
‫Now an important detail, we are returning here, a promise.
‫So we need to make sure that here in this call to delete one, we return the promise that Mongoose has
‫created.
‫Otherwise we would have been here in our controller, accidentally returning a promise that was not
‫linked to the deletion of the entity from the database.
‫So this way the deletion might not happen as we intended.
‫And with this we are ready to try our Crud delete functionality.
‫Let's switch here to a larger window.
‫Let's open our application and here in our list of courses, let's select here a course to delete.
‫Let's choose, for example, this one, the angular core deep dive.
‫We are going to click here on Delete and let's keep an eye here on the network log of the dev tools.
‫We're going to hit delete.
‫We can see that the delete request has hit this endpoint slash API slash courses and here we have the
‫course ID and we get here a new list of courses reloaded from the back end in the second get request.
‫So if we now scroll down, we are going to see that the angular core deep dive course is no longer part
‫of this list.
‫It has been deleted in the database.
‫If we refresh here in the MongoDB console, our list of courses and we searched through this list of
‫courses, we are going to see that indeed the angular core deep dive course has been deleted as expected.
‫Now, you might be wondering at this point in the course, what is the real difference between the controller
‫class and the repository class?
‫As many times here we are forwarding the parameters directly.
‫Later on in the course, we are going to understand why we are going to be adding here some extra logic,
‫such as validation of the input parameters, error handling that is not going to be part of the repository
‫service.
‫So the repository service only contains the database queries and data modification operations in the
‫database that we want to be able to reuse on multiple parts of our backend.
‫So let's then continue our Crud example and implement the final operation, which is going to be the
‫create course and.
‫Point.