‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to complete our complete grid example for the courses entity by implementing
‫the last Crud operation that we haven't implemented yet, which is going to be the create course operation.
‫So let's add here a new asynchronous method.
‫We are going to call it create course.
‫Let's add here some logging so that we can see on the console that the method is getting called and
‫let's start the controller implementation of this Crud operation.
‫So the first thing that we need to define is which type of Http call is going to trigger this method.
‫And following typical rest conventions, we are going to assign this to an Http post request.
‫So a post to slash API slash courses is going to trigger the create course method.
‫Now let's see what we need in this method.
‫From the Http request we are going to be needing here our course object.
‫So all the properties that we are going to be setting here in the front end for the new course we need
‫to receive here in a course variable.
‫Now this is not going to be of type course because that would require us to define the ID of the course
‫on the front end and we don't want to do that in this case.
‫So instead we are going to be defining this as a partial course.
‫And let's also define the return type of this method.
‫So as usual, this is going to be returning a promise and the value emitted is going to be the course
‫that was inserted in the database, including its identifier generated by MongoDB.
‫So this will no longer be a partial course.
‫It's going to be a full instance of a course.
‫Let's now see how we are going to implement this.
‫We are going to be calling our courses DB service and here we are going to be calling a new method that
‫we are going to implement in a moment.
‫This is going to be the Add course method.
‫So here we are going to be passing the complete course that we have defined here.
‫So to the Add course method, we are going to be passing the partial course that we have received here
‫from the body of the Http request.
‫So this needs that we need to annotate the course variable with the Add body decorator in order for
‫nestjs to know that this contains the content of the Http body.
‫Now Add course does not exist yet on our repository.
‫Let's go ahead and define it now.
‫We could insert a new entity in our database in a similar way to what we were doing here by calling
‫course model.
‫And from here we could call simply the Create method, pass it here, the course that we receive here.
‫And this would take care of the insertion in the database.
‫However, I'm going to take here the opportunity to show you a different way of using Mongoose.
‫So we are going to be using the course model to create an in-memory object that is going to be linked
‫by Mongoose to a database document.
‫We are going to be defining here a new course object, and we are going to create it by calling here
‫course model and by passing it here, the course data.
‫So we have here the partial course data containing, for example, the title, the thumbnail, etcetera.
‫And here we have created using the course model constructor function, a new instance of a course object
‫that only exists for the moment in memory at the server and that it has not yet been saved to the database.
‫So this new course object already has an ID, it already has a version timestamp.
‫It corresponds to a MongoDB document that is ready to be saved on the database, but we have not saved
‫it just yet.
‫So we could use this object and link it, for example, to other objects.
‫We could further modify it in memory.
‫And when we are ready to save it to the database, we are going to be calling new course dot save.
‫Now, the call to save is going to return us a promise.
‫So we need to await for the promise to be resolved before proceeding with our Add course implementation.
‫Let's annotate here, add course with the async keyword so that we can use the async await syntax.
‫So here at this point we already have the new course document saved on the database.
‫So now we need to return it here to the front end.
‫Let's add here a type annotation and say that we are going to return here.
‫A promise, of course.
‫So the value here is going to be the full version of the course with its correct ID in order to obtain
‫it here from the new course object that we have here in memory, we are going to be calling the two
‫object Mongoose method.
‫So this is going to convert this instance of the document in memory into an object that can be easily
‫serialized back to the front end.
‫Let's now return this plain object here as the output of this add course function.
‫So we are.
‫Turning here a plain value and not a promise.
‫But as usual, the async await syntax is going to convert this into a promise for us.
‫Now Mongoose has this notion of version tracking.
‫So whenever we have an object that corresponds to a document on the database, Mongoose is going to
‫keep track.
‫If the version of the document in memory still matches the one from the database, and for that it's
‫going to use an extra version property.
‫So whenever we serialize here the course back to the front end, we want to send just the properties
‫of the object and not any extra properties that only make sense to Mongoose because we are not using
‫Mongoose on the front end.
‫We are only using it on the back end.
‫So here, in order to strip this extra version property from the serialized object, we are going to
‫set here a configuration option.
‫We are going to set the version key property to false, and this is going to make sure that to the back
‫end we only send back the new version of the course as it exists on the database without any extra Mongoose
‫specific properties.
‫Now, going back here to our controller, we need to return this promise that we are getting back here
‫from Add course to Nestjs so that Nestjs knows when the request is completed, the request will be completed
‫when this promise gets evaluated successfully, let's now try out the new Create course functionality.
‫We are going to switch here to a larger window and we're going to click here on the plus button.
‫In order to create a new course, let's create here a new course.
‫Then we are going to call it, for example, the angular testing course.
‫We're going to add here a course test.
‫Let's now define here the URL from the course.
‫I'm going to paste in here a full URL to an image that I already have.
‫You can use any link to any image that you have on the Internet.
‫I'm going to select here a category.
‫Let's select here beginner category.
‫Let's turn a promotion on for this course and let's add here a description.
‫I'm just going to add the same description as in the title.
‫So let's now keep an eye here on the network tab.
‫I'm going to click on Save.
‫As you can see, an Http post request was issued against the backend.
‫You can see that it's hitting slash API slash courses.
‫And we can also see here the content of the body of the Http request.
‫We can see that it contains the properties that we have defined but not the ID.
‫So now as the response to this Http post request, we are going to get back here the new version of
‫this object containing also the ID on the database.
‫This means that if we now scroll down this list, we should see at the end appended a new version here
‫of the testing course.
‫So here it is, the version that we have just created using our front end.
‫And with this we have completed the implementation of our Crud functionality in our courses controller
‫endpoint, but our production functionality is going to be more than that.
‫We need some error handling on these Http requests.
‫We need to be able to validate some of the input parameters that are getting passed here to our controller
‫and we need to make sure that we properly format the error response before sending it back to the front
‫end.
‫So in the next few lessons, we are going to be talking about error handling in Nestjs.