‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to set up our new MongoDB database.
‫Now, we could install MongoDB locally in your development machine, but I think it's going to be a
‫lot easier if you use instead a cloud service.
‫So for that we are going to switch here to Mongodb.com and we are going to register to its cloud service.
‫So this will give you access to a free database that you can use for learning purposes.
‫Let's then hit here the sign in button and let's register with a new account.
‫If you already have a username, you can go ahead and log in.
‫Otherwise we are going to click here on register.
‫Now you need to fill in these details and then click here on Continue.
‫Once you have set up your account, you are going to be asked what type of database cluster do you need?
‫You are going to choose the free cluster that we are going to be using for learning purposes.
‫From here you are going to be choosing your cloud provider and region and you can use the defaults as
‫they will work well for the course.
‫Once you have selected the defaults, let's click on Create Cluster.
‫Notice that your cluster is still being created.
‫We can see that this should take around ten minutes while the cluster is being created.
‫We are going to create a database user.
‫We are going to grant access to our development machine while the cluster is building.
‫Let's go ahead and continue here.
‫The initialization process.
‫We are going to create our first database user.
‫We can do so by clicking here on security database access.
‫And from here we are going to create our first database user.
‫Notice that this is not an end user like, for example, a person that connects to your application
‫and uses it.
‫This is an administrative user.
‫So these users are typically either database administrators or applications that need to access the
‫database in write mode.
‫Let's then create a new administrative user, let's call it Nestjs dash admin.
‫So that is the user name.
‫And let's enter a password by clicking on Autogenerate secure password.
‫We are going to make this user a Atlas admin.
‫So Atlas is the MongoDB Cloud service.
‫Let's click now on Add User and this has created here our first user.
‫The next step is to whitelist our IP address.
‫So what is this?
‫Our server is going to be running in a given address.
‫We want to make sure that the database accepts queries incoming from this address.
‫So it's an extra security protection that the database offers us in production.
‫You not only want to authenticate the username and password of the administrative user, but you also
‫want to whitelist the address from which the query is coming from in case that the password gets lost.
‫Let's then click here on Whitelist IP address and let's now click on Security Network Access.
‫We are now going to click here on Add IP address and we are going to choose the option for the particular
‫case of our course because we are simply using this for learning purposes.
‫We are going to choose the option, allow access from anywhere.
‫So this is not recommended in production.
‫In production, you should have a static IP address for your production server and you should add only
‫that specific IP address to the white list.
‫Let's click here on confirm and we are going to see that this white list request is still on status
‫pending, so we are going to wait for a few minutes while MongoDB sets up our database cluster.
‫After a moment, the white listing of the IP address should be completed.
‫So if we now click here for example, on clusters, we are going to see what is the current state of
‫our cluster.
‫It seems to be up and running.
‫Let's click here on collections.
‫Collections are like database tables in SQL databases, so collections are going to be groups of related
‫documents in MongoDB.
‫So MongoDB is a document database.
‫We are going to be talking a lot more about collections and documents throughout the course.
‫Right now, let's simply add some data to the database and see what it looks like.