‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back to this new section on error handling.
‫So how this error handling work in Nestjs?
‫Let's take here an example for example of the update course method here in our courses controller.
‫So the goal of this method is to update an existing course entity.
‫As we can see, one of the parameters is the course ID identifying the entity that we want to update,
‫and here we receive the properties that we want to modify.
‫Now an important thing in the implementation of this update course method is to make sure that in this
‫properties here of the course we are not receiving a new version of the course ID, so we don't want
‫to accidentally overwrite the identifier of this entity on the database because then the course would
‫become a completely new entity that might trigger data corruption problems in our application in case
‫this ID was being used elsewhere to link to this particular course.
‫So here we want to add some sort of validation.
‫We want to make sure that these changes are not accidentally overwriting the identifier of the course.
‫We might also want to add extra business validation rules such as, for example, the properties of
‫a course should obey certain rules.
‫Let's have a look.
‫How could we trigger a validation error and send an appropriate response back to the client?
‫Taking the example here of the update course method, we want to first check if the ID is being accidentally
‫overwritten so we can do so by accessing here changes and making sure that the ID property is not filled
‫in.
‫If it is filled in, then we have here an error.
‫We can throw an error here from a nestjs controller by using the Nestjs http exception.
‫So let's go ahead and create here a new instance of this exception which should be imported from the
‫Nestjs common package.
‫Now to this exception, we need to pass two arguments.
‫The first argument contains, for example, a message that we want to send back to the client.
‫So let's add here, for example, the message can't update course ID and the second argument that we
‫pass to Http exception is the status code that we want to send back.
‫So in this case, we want to send back a 400 bad request.
‫With this logic in place, if by accident we fill in this property, this error is going to be thrown
‫and the update is not going to be performed.
‫Now this error is going to be caught by a global default nestjs exception handler that is going to send
‫us back a predefined response.
‫We are going to see later on how to override that default behavior if we need to.
‫Now, let's first test this simple error handling logic.
‫In order to do that, we are going to need to form a bad request.
‫Now, a simple way of forming a bad request is to use our application here.
‫So let's go ahead and go to this dialog here, the Edit course dialog where we are trying to edit a
‫course entity and let's add some logic that is going to corrupt our Http request.
‫Let's say that accidentally here we had the bug and besides filling in here the multiple properties
‫of the form, we accidentally also filled in here the underscore ID property, let's say with the value
‫one.
‫So any value that when checked here with this condition would end up throwing the exception.
‫So the value one is a good example of that.
‫Let's also add here a comment so that we don't forget to remove this later.
‫Let's mention here that this is a simulated bug.
‫Let's now try this malformed request here in a larger window.
‫We are going to open here the edit course dialog and let's make here some changes.
‫We are going to click on Save and we are going to keep an eye here on the network log.
‫So if we now click Save indeed we get back here the status code bad request on the put call and here
‫on the response we have our message can't update course ID status code 400 as expected.
‫So as you can see our malformed request triggered here, our validation logic in our course controller.
‫So throwing http exceptions from your controller is a good way of sending back to the client a specific
‫status code and a specific error message.
‫But even better than using directly the Http exception here in our controllers is to subclass it and
‫create our own custom exceptions.
‫For example, for reporting business errors.
‫We are going to see later on in the course how to subclass Http exception.
‫Right now, let's give a couple more examples available on the Nestjs common package of commonly needed
‫Http exceptions.
‫By going over the Nestjs documentation, we are going to see that we already have available all these
‫subclasses of Http exception for common problems such as a bad request exception, which is our case.
‫Unauthorized or not found exception for with an exception.
‫ET cetera.
‫So we already have all these exceptions that return the corresponding status code as per rest conventions.
‫For example, throwing a not found exception is going to send back a 404 not found status code to the
‫client.
‫In the particular case of our existing business validation, what we need here is a bad request exception
‫which comes from the Nestjs package.
‫So this exception, because it models the bad request exception does not need here a status code.
‫This is going to be automatically filled in with 400 and our code is a bit more readable.
‫We know better what is happening here now that we know the basics of error handling with Nestjs, let's
‫see.
‫How can we customize our error response?
‫Let's see.
‫How can we specify different error handling for different types of exceptions?
‫Let's add a fallback catch all exception handler and later on in the course, we are going to see how
‫to use Nestjs to validate our input parameters.
‫Checking, for example, if the values provided here are actually valid properties according to the
‫definition of a course.
‫So we will be able to check, for example, if sequence number is being filled in with a numeric field
‫URL with the string et-cetera, we will be able to do full validation of this interface according to
‫its type definitions.
‫Before doing that, let's learn how to customize the error response sent to the client in the case of
‫a particular error.
‫For example an Http exception.