‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to learn how to customize the error response of nestjs whenever something
‫goes wrong in one of our controllers.
‫So we can define different error responses at the level of a given method of a given controller or even
‫globally at the level of all controllers of our backend.
‫So first, before showing how to do this using a nestjs filter, let's first switch to a better way
‫of testing error handling in our application.
‫So far we were simulating here a bug by intentionally modifying here the code of the edit course dialog
‫of our frontend.
‫We are going to instead be using a small http rest client that runs from the browser in order to test
‫our backend.
‫In this part of the course, the browser client that we are going to be using is called Restlet.
‫It's free and it's a chrome extension.
‫So once you install it, you are going to see an icon here in your top bar to open the Restlet client,
‫which looks like this.
‫Let's then see how can we use Restlet in order to simulate the same error as before?
‫So we were doing here a put call and we were accessing here the URL localhost 9000 slash api slash courses
‫and then we need to pass in here the course ID that we want to update.
‫Let's grab this here directly from our front end.
‫We are going to open here the edit course dialog and we are going to trigger again the same error that
‫we triggered before in our last lesson.
‫So this is the error that we are trying to simulate.
‫We have here a 400 bad request and we can get here from the request URL using the chrome dev tools,
‫the correct identifier of the course that we are trying to update.
‫We are going to take this course ID and we are going to use it here to build our put request URL.
‫So here is the full URL that we want to update.
‫And now we just need to specify here the body of the request.
‫Notice that we are already setting here the content type header to application slash.
‫Jason.
‫Let's then switch back here to the network log and grab the body of the Http request here.
‫From the request payload, we can now use this request body here in the body part of our Restlet client.
‫Let's paste this in and let's format this into proper Json.
‫Once we have the body of our put request, we can now go ahead and trigger here the send button and
‫notice that we are adding here this field which normally we should not be trying to update.
‫So in an update request we should not try to override the ID field.
‫This would be a good example of a bug in our application.
‫Now for that, let's trigger the request.
‫We are going to click here on Send and it looks like nothing happened, but if we click here on this
‫collapse button, we are going to scroll down and see below here the response that we got.
‫So as you can see, we got an error.
‫We got a 400 bad request back from our Nestjs backend and we can see here the body of the response.
‫So from now on, whenever we want to simulate errors, we are going to be using this nice rest browser
‫based Http client.
‫Before going any further, let's switch back here to our program and let's go ahead and remove the simulated
‫bug so that we can use our user interface in other lessons if we need to.
‫And with this in place, we are now ready to continue the error handling section of our course.
‫Let's learn how to customize the body of the error response if we need to using a nestjs filter.