‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to introduce the notion of Nestjs exception filters.
‫So what is exactly an exception?
‫Filter?
‫A filter is a nestjs construct.
‫It's a class that we can write ourselves that it's going to allow us to handle an error thrown.
‫For example, at the level of this update course method that handles a put request in a course entity.
‫If any error is thrown inside the body of this method, such as, for example, this bad request exception
‫that we have coded in one of the last few lessons, then our exception filter is going to catch the
‫error and it's going to allow us to define the error response.
‫There is already a default exception filter that is catching this error.
‫And so with Nestjs in general, we don't have hanging Http requests that were not caught by any error
‫handler.
‫Worst case scenario, we are going to get the default error handler that is already there.
‫But let's say that we would not want to use that default error handler, but instead we would like to
‫have full control over the format of the error response.
‫For that, we are going to need a filter.
‫Let's then go ahead and write one we're going to add here inside our rest folder, not at the level
‫of the courses module, but at the level of the whole application.
‫We're going to add here a new folder that we are going to call filters.
‫And inside it we are going to create here a new Http filter.
‫So this is going to allow us to process any Http errors thrown from inside our controller or repository
‫logic.
‫Let's then create here a new filter.
‫We are going to call it Http filter dot ts.
‫Let's now see what a filter looks like.
‫This is going to be a plain TypeScript class that we are going to call simply Http exception filter.
‫Now this class, in order to be a filter, is going to have to implement the exception filter nestjs
‫interface.
‫And it also needs to be annotated with the Nestjs catch decorator to the catch decorator we need to
‫pass.
‫What exceptions are we exactly handling with this filter?
‫So in our case we are going to be handling the Http exception from Nestjs.
‫So this is the base exception from which we will be inheriting our business.
‫Exceptions thrown at the level of our controllers.
‫And by adding here the Http exception, this is going to catch not only instances of the Http exception
‫itself, but also its subclasses.
‫Let's then implement the exception filter interface.
‫This only has one method which is called catch.
‫Let's then go ahead and implement it.
‫We are going to pass in here the exception argument which is going to be of type Http exception.
‫So this must be the type of the exception that we are catching here.
‫And let's go ahead and import here the arguments.
‫Host type.
‫We are going to see exactly how can we use here this host variable that we are receiving via the catch
‫method.
‫So here is where we are going to add our error handling for learning purposes.
‫Let's just add here some logging so that we can see visually on the log that this catch method is getting
‫triggered.
‫We are going to output to the log http exception handler triggered and we are going to output also the
‫exception object that we received here.
‫Next, we are going to add here our error handling logic.
‫So here what we want to do is to be able to define the content of the Http response that gets sent back
‫to the client whenever this error got thrown.
‫In order to define the response, we are going to be needing the request and response object linked
‫to this Http request which is currently being processed and we can access those two objects by using
‫the Http context that we can obtain here from the host variable that we received here.
‫As the argument of the catch method, we are going to call here, switch to Http and this is going to
‫give us back the Http context.
‫So from here we are going to be able to access, for example, the Http response.
‫We can do so by calling get response.
‫And as we can see, we can also access here the request itself in a similar way.
‫So with this, we have everything that we need in order to build our response.
‫The response is going to be returned here as the result of calling catch.
‫Let's then go ahead and build a response.
‫We are going to return it.
‫This is very important.
‫Otherwise the catch implementation is not correct.
‫We are going to base ourselves on the response object that we have here, and we are going to start
‫by defining here a status code for the response.
‫In the particular case of the Http exception, we don't want to hard code here.
‫A specific Http status such as, for example, 500 internal server error.
‫Instead, we want to grab the status code here.
‫From the exception itself, let's remember that whenever we define the Http exception, we also need
‫to define a status code.
‫So accessing the exception we are going to call, get status and obtain here the status code that we
‫are going to use to build our error response.
‫Now, besides specifying the status code, we are also going to specify the body of the response that
‫we are going to be building by calling here.
‫Jason So we are going to send back an error payload.
‫One of the things that we can do is to add here a status variable and add the status code also here
‫directly on the body of the returned payload.
‫This might be useful for the client.
‫And another thing that would be useful for the client would be a property called error message.
‫We can obtain the error message also from the exception we are going to access here the message property,
‫which is actually a Json object that was passed on to the Http exception.
‫And from there we can access, for example, the message property again to retrieve the text.
‫So this second message property is going to be a string.
‫And with this we have specified here a simple error payload to send back to the client if any Http exception
‫gets thrown in order to make it clear that this error message is being created here by our Http exception
‫filter, let's add here an extra property called created by and let's add here as a string the source
‫of this error response.
‫This is going to be useful for troubleshooting purposes in case that you have a series of different
‫exception filters for different types of errors that produce similar output results.
‫And with this we have completed the implementation of our Http exception filter.
‫So now we simply have to tell Nestjs about it.
‫Right now, Nestjs does not know that this class can be used for handling errors.
‫In order to plug this into the Nestjs framework, we can use, for example, the use filters decorator.
‫We can apply this decorator at multiple parts of our application.
‫Let's start by applying it here directly to this particular method.
‫So this decorator used filters is going to take in here as an input parameter, an array of filter instances.
‫So I'm going to be calling here new on the Http exception filter class that we have just created.
‫And with this I have added this filter as an error handler to this specific update course method and
‫nowhere else on the application.
‫Let's then trigger again our bad request exception and see the new exception filter in action.
‫We are going to switch again to the Restlet interface and we're going to click on Send and notice that
‫whenever we scroll down, we are getting here not a response generated by our exception filter, but
‫this is still the default Nestjs exception filter.
‫So what's going on here?
‫I simply submitted here a payload with invalid Json and that caused the default exception filter to
‫get caught so the error was not thrown from inside the controller.
‫The error happened instead, whenever Nestjs was still trying to process the inbound request by taking
‫the content of the body and converting it into Json.
‫So we need to turn this body into valid Json by adding here the commas in order to avoid the error message
‫that we saw here in the error response.
‫And notice the specific error message and expected token see in Json at position three.
‫This is because we are passing in here the category name without wrapping it in commas.
‫So without this we won't have valid Json.
‫Let's go ahead and fix all the fields so that we can submit this request to our back end.
‫So now here we have a payload with valid Json.
‫Let's then go ahead and click send.
‫We're going to scroll down and we are going to see that this time around because it's valid.
‫Json Nestjs managed to process the body of the incoming Http request and it tried to pass this payload
‫body to our controller.
‫Our controller then triggered the bad request exception which ended up being handled by our custom Http
‫exception filter.
‫So as you can see using exception filters, we can customize easily The error response is sent to our
‫clients going back here to our code base.
‫Notice that this type of exception handling is very common and there is really no good reason to apply
‫it only to the update course method.
‫So the other methods here in our controller would also benefit from the same error logic.
‫So if we want to apply this to all the Http methods of our controller, we can apply.
‫Use filters instead here at the level of the courses controller class.
‫This way the exception filter is going to be valid for create course final courses.
‫Update course and delete course.
‫Let's see this in action.
‫We are going to switch here to the Restlet client.
‫Let's click Send and we're going to see that still the exception filter is working as expected.
‫Now we might want to go one step further and make this a global exception filter that would be applied
‫not only to the courses controller but to any controller in general in our whole rest backend.
‫In order to make this a global exception filter, we are going to remove the use here of the use filters
‫annotation and instead here in our main.ts whenever we are initializing our nestjs backend, we are
‫going to use here our application instance and we're going to call here use global filters.
‫So to this we need to pass in an array.
‫Let's go ahead and pass in only one element, which is going to be our Http exception filter.
‫So as usual, we need to pass in here an instance of the filter built using the new operator and not
‫the name of the class.
‫Let's then try out this new configuration.
‫We are going to switch to the Restlet interface.
‫Let's hit on send and as you can see, our Http exception filter is now active globally.
‫Let's now continue exploring error handling in Nestjs.
‫Let's learn what would happen if we would try to submit a payload to the server containing a Json payload
‫with the correct property names, but an invalid type for a given property.
‫Let's see what type of error this would trigger in our backend and how to best handle it.