‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to see how our Nestjs backend is going to react if we try to pass
‫it.
‫Some invalid data from the point of view of the Mongoose schema definition.
‫So if we open here our courses schema, we are going to see that for each property of a course object
‫we are defining here an expected type.
‫So if we pass in to Mongoose an object that does not follow this particular schema, mongoose is going
‫to throw an error.
‫However, this schema validation done by Mongoose works in a different way than what you are probably
‫used to with SQL databases.
‫For example, in Mongoose, if the type of the sequential number variable is a string instead of a number,
‫mongoose is not going to automatically throw an error due to that.
‫Instead, Mongoose is going to try to cast the string into a number.
‫If the cast is successful, the result is still going to be written in the database only if the cast
‫between the string and the number fails will then mongoose throw an error.
‫Another important difference is what happens if we provide to Mongoose an extra property that is not
‫specified here on this list?
‫So in the case of a SQL database, if we try to save to a column that does not exist, we are going
‫to get an error.
‫However, with Mongoose, what will happen is that any properties that are not specified here on this
‫schema are going to be ignored.
‫But the save is still going to go through and the data is still going to get persisted on the database.
‫And those are the two main differences between Mongoose schema validation and the schema validation
‫performed by a SQL database.
‫For example.
‫Let's then try to trigger some schema validation errors and see what is the current behavior of our
‫backend.
‫We are going to go here to the courses controller and instead of using the update course method that
‫we have been using so far, let's instead use create course.
‫So here we are going to do an Http post and we're going to be providing a list of properties for a course.
‫Let's switch then to our Restlet interface and here I have already selected here the Http post method.
‫I'm going to hit here slash api slash courses without an ID appended to the end.
‫Now here on the body of the payload, we need to provide some valid Json for a course object.
‫Remember the URL property needs to be unique every time that we are creating a course.
‫So make sure that you append here some sequential number, for example, in case that you try out this
‫request multiple times.
‫Let's remember this is a creation request.
‫So a new document is going to be inserted in the database if the request is successful.
‫Now, notice that in the payload of this course creation request, we have here a series of properties
‫that are known to the schema and have a valid type.
‫But we also have here a property called Unknown, which is not part of the course schema.
‫So let's see what happens whenever we submit this payload.
‫Let's also add here an extra modification.
‫Let's say that this promotion Boolean field, instead of having here a valid false Boolean value, let's
‫instead put in here, for example, the zero value instead.
‫So to small issues here on this payload.
‫Let's see how Mongoose handles this.
‫We're going to click on Send and we are going to see a bit to our surprise maybe, that the request
‫went through.
‫And we have here a new course that was created on the database.
‫Let's go to the database and first confirm that indeed the course is there.
‫We are going to grab this URL and we are going to use it to query the courses collection.
‫We're going to switch here to the user interface of our cloud database and using here the filter.
‫We are going to provide here a filter that tries to find the URL that we have just inserted.
‫So the URL with test course dash ten, let's run this query by clicking here on Find and we're going
‫to see that indeed our object was inserted in the database and we might not have expected that.
‫So first of all, notice that Mongoose ignored the unknown property.
‫So if a property is not whitelisted in our schema, then that property is going to be ignored and it's
‫not going to be persisted on the database.
‫Now, for the case here of the promo field, what happened is a bit different.
‫So we took the input value, which was a numeric value zero, and we have casted it into a Boolean.
‫So zero is a falsy value.
‫So it was casted to false and we ended up having the value false on the database.
‫So if the value can still be successfully casted to the target type, Mongoose is still going to save
‫the data on the database.
‫Notice also that some of the fields are missing, for example, the sequential number type, which we
‫would expect.
‫To be mandatory is not present, and we end up inserting a course on the database without a sequential
‫number.
‫So if we want to avoid that here in our schema definition, we are going to go here to the sequential
‫number field and we are going to add here a configuration object.
‫We are going to define the type of the sequential number field as being a number.
‫But besides that, we are also going to mark it here as required.
‫So fields in Mongoose by definition are not required now that the sequential number field is required.
‫Let's go back here to Restlet and let's try to create here a new course with a different URL, which
‫is a unique property in the database, and let's try to create it again without the sequential number
‫field.
‫So if we click here on Send this time around, we are going to receive here an error.
‫And if we inspect here the content of the error response, we are going to see that this is the default
‫error response from the fallback Nestjs built in error handler.
‫So if we go back here to our workspace and we check the server log, we are going to see that we now
‫have here a stack trace in our server saying that the sequential number field is required.
‫Now to further understand how schema validation works in Mongoose, let's add here the sequential number
‫field, but let's add it as a string instead of a number.
‫So let's add here the sequential number property and make sure to add here the comma so that you get
‫a valid Json payload.
‫And let's add here, for example, the sequential number 20, but under the form of a string and not
‫a number.
‫Let's now click on Send.
‫And this time around the request went through and the document was created on the database.
‫Now let's see, what type does this sequence number field have on the database?
‫Switching back here to the database console, let's search for the course with this URL.
‫Let's hit find and we are going to see that our sequential number field was indeed correctly inserted
‫into the database.
‫But as you can see, this has been cast into a number.
‫So this is no longer under the form of a string.
‫So let's remember Mongoose tries to cast the fields to the target types.
‫Only if the cast fails, we are going to get an error.
‫Let's then try to provide a value that would trigger the cast error.
‫Let's say that we try to add here a new course course 12 and this time around, instead of adding here
‫as a string, a valid numeric value, let's instead add here some string that cannot be casted into
‫a number.
‫Let's see what would happen this time around.
‫We are going to click on Send and this time around we do get an error.
‫So going back here to our workspace and checking the log, we can see that again.
‫We have a long stack trace and we have the message cast to number failed for value error for the field
‫sequential number.
‫So as you can see, Mongoose is validating the schema of the new course object, but is doing it in
‫a slightly different way than you might be used to.
‫Let's then summarize and keep in mind for this lesson the following points All mongoose fields are optional
‫by default, so we need to specifically mark them as required.
‫Mongoose will try to cast the value of the fields to the target type that we are defining here.
‫And only if the cast fails will Mongoose throw an error.
‫Mongoose will also ignore any fields that are not part of this list.
‫So a field that is not part of this list is not going to trigger a mongoose error.
‫Instead, that property is simply going to be ignored.
‫Now that we understand how Mongoose schema validation works, let's then catch these type of errors
‫with a new exception filter and let's send a more useful response back to the client.
‫Let's remember that so far we have been sending this generic error message status code 500 internal
‫server error.
‫Let's learn how can we catch this type of mongoose schema, validation errors and any other type of
‫similar backend errors that were not explicitly thrown via code?
‫And let's see, how can we send back to the client a better error response?