‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In the last lesson we saw what happened in our back end.
‫Whenever we cause a schema validation error triggered by mongoose.
‫Now, the reason why the Http exception filter did not catch the schema validation error is because
‫the error thrown by mongoose is not an Http exception.
‫So we would like to add to our application a global exception filter that catches everything that was
‫not caught by more specific exception filters such as, for example, the Http exception filter.
‫This is going to be sort of a catch all exception filter that is going to be our fallback exception
‫filter.
‫So only if all the other exception filters did not match the thrown error will then this global default
‫exception filter then be triggered.
‫So this global exception filter is going to override the existing global catch all exception filter
‫that is already installed by default by Nestjs.
‫Let's then implement our fallback filter.
‫We are going to go here to the courses folder and here inside the filters folder we are going to add
‫a new file that we're going to call fallback dot filter, dot ts.
‫Inside it, we are going to be creating a new class that we are going to be calling fallback exception
‫filter as usual with a Nestjs filter we are going to be implementing here the exception filter interface.
‫We are also going to be annotating this class with the catch decorator, but this time around we are
‫not going to add any type here inside parenthesis.
‫We are going to leave this empty.
‫So this will indicate to nestjs that this filter is meant to catch any error.
‫Let's then implement here the catch function.
‫And because we are handling here any exception type, let's add here the type any and let's handle here
‫the error response first.
‫In order to make it easy to see that the exception filter is being correctly triggered, we are just
‫going to add here some simple logging.
‫So we are going to log to our server console that the fallback exception filter has been triggered and
‫we are going to output here.
‫Also the value of the exception.
‫Now all we have to do is to prepare the response that we are going to send back to the client.
‫So first let's grab here the Http context by calling here, switch to Http and let's also grab the Http
‫response from the context.
‫With this, we are now ready to build our response.
‫So let's call here response dot status.
‫Let's pass in the status 500 internal server error and let's pass a Json payload as usual with exception
‫filters.
‫We are going to be returning here.
‫The response that we have created and let's also fill in here a couple of useful properties.
‫We are going to add here a status code property of 500 and we're going to add here, just like we did
‫before a created by property.
‫And we're going to fill this in with fallback exception filter.
‫This way, if we see this exception in a log in the network devtools, we know where it came from in
‫the back end.
‫Now, we are also going to add here an error message property that we are going to try to fill in from
‫the exception.
‫So let's see if the exception has a message property.
‫If so, we are going to be using this message property.
‫Otherwise we are going to be providing here a default error message.
‫Let's say an expected error occurred and with this we have completed the implementation of our fallback
‫exception filter.
‫Let's then add it to our back end.
‫So we are going to pass it here using use global filters.
‫So this takes in an array.
‫So the first element of our array is going to be our new fallback exception filter.
‫As usual, we need to pass in an instance of the filter and not the name of the class.
‫And also, please bear in mind that the order of the filters is important.
‫The filters here should be specified from the most generic, such as the fallback exception filter to
‫the most specific, such as the Http exception filter.
‫We are going to see in the next lesson an example of when the order of the filters that are specified
‫here becomes important.
‫Right now let's run the new version of our backend and see how it handles our schema validation error.
‫Let's switch again to our Restlet client and let's trigger again the same error that we were triggering
‫before.
‫So let's remember this payload here on our post call is valid.
‫Jason But as we can see, the sequence number property, which should be numeric as here a string.
‫So this should trigger an error in our backend.
‫Let's see the new behavior we are going to click on send.
‫The request has been sent and if we scroll down we are going to see that we got again a 500 internal
‫server error.
‫But this time around we got here a response that was created by.
‫A fallback exception filter.
‫So as you can see, we got here an error message cross validation failed.
‫The sequential number field was not valid because the cast to number operation failed for value error.
‫So as you can see, this is a very specific message that is going to help us a lot to troubleshoot the
‫problem.
‫Now this way of handling schema errors is already much better than before.
‫And also this is going to work to any error thrown by our backend in general, not just for mongoose
‫exceptions for the case of schema validation exceptions.
‫In the next lesson, we're going to see an even better way of handling this specific type of errors.