‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to quickly create our first Nestjs endpoint.
‫So we are going to be doing the typical Hello world example in Nestjs.
‫So for that we are going to be doing our development always inside the rest API folder.
‫So here is where everything happens.
‫We are going to be defining our multiple endpoints inside this folder.
‫Now the rest of the application that you see here, for example, the source folder here at the root
‫of our repository is going to contain the front end application that we are using here.
‫On the right part of our screen, we will be querying our Rest API using the sample application.
‫But the Nestjs part that we are focusing on in this course is going to always be inside the rest API
‫folder.
‫So it's here that we need to do our Hello world example.
‫Let's then start by creating here a new sub folder which is going to be the source folder.
‫Inside it.
‫We are going to write the entry point of our application, which is going to be the file called Main.ts.
‫And it's important that you use this exact name inside here we are going to bootstrap our rest back
‫end server using Nestjs.
‫For that we are going to be needing here a new function that is going to return a promise.
‫So we are going to mark it as an async function and we are going to be calling this function simply
‫bootstrap.
‫Let's go ahead and call it here directly.
‫So whenever our program starts up, we are sure that the bootstrap function is going to get executed.
‫Now here is how we are going to initialize our application.
‫We are going to call the class nest factory and from here we are going to call the static method create.
‫Here we are going to be providing the root module of our Nestjs application.
‫Now what is the root module?
‫It's something very similar to the root module of our front end application.
‫So going here to the front end part of our application, we are going to see that.
‫We also have here an application root module called app module.
‫So our backend is going to follow a similar structure as our front end.
‫It's also going to be using dependency injection just like we are doing here with the Angular framework
‫and it's also going to have a root module.
‫We are also going to be able to split up our backend into multiple feature modules like we usually do
‫in our front end.
‫Going back here to our rest API folder, this means that next to the Main.ts file we are going to be
‫creating here a new file that we are also going to call App.module.ts.
‫So this file is going to contain the root module of our Nestjs application.
‫Let's then define here a new class and we are going to call it app module, just like we did in the
‫front end.
‫Now we need to annotate this class and mark it as a nestjs module.
‫Now it's very important that when you import the module decorator that you import it here from the Nestjs
‫common package.
‫So if you apply here, the module decorator from Angular, this will not work.
‫So the module decorator from Nestjs implements a similar concept to the module decorator in Angular.
‫It allows us to define units of our application that are self-contained, but it's a different decorator
‫coming from a different package.
‫It just happens to have the same name because it implements the same concept.
‫But on the backend.
‫Now here we are going to be providing a configuration object that we're going to be populating later
‫on in the course.
‫This configuration object takes the same properties as an angular frontend module such as imports,
‫exports, providers, etcetera.
‫And we also have here a special property named controllers that we are going to be using in a moment.
‫Right now we want to take this application module and we want to use it to bootstrap our application.
‫So we are going to pass this root module here to the call to create.
‫Now notice this because there are similarly named files both on the front end and on the back end.
‫It's important that you always import the correct file.
‫So I want to import the app module file from the same directory where I have here my main dot ts file.
‫If we would import the module from the angular front end, our program would not work.
‫So please always double check your imports throughout the course.
‫Now here in the return from the create call we are going to receive here the express instance of our
‫application.
‫Let's assign it here to the app variable.
‫So if you don't know express, it's a web framework that is used under the hood by nestjs.
‫Notice that you.
‫Don't need to know express in order to use nestjs.
‫Now, the return here of the Create call is going to return a promise.
‫So in order to get here, the app reference we need to await here for the result of this promise.
‫If we have a look here at what we have available under the app variable, we are going to see that we
‫have, for example, app dot use, which is an express specific API.
‫We could use it here, for example, for defining custom express Middlewares.
‫ET cetera.
‫So this is just something to bear in mind.
‫But in this course we are not going to be using express APIs.
‫We are going to do everything using the Nestjs object oriented APIs.
‫Now that we have here a reference to our application, we just need to start our rest backend server.
‫So here we are going to be calling app Dot Listen and we are going to specify a port number.
‫We are going to be using port 9000 and it's important that you use this specific port number.
‫We are going to await for the result of this promise to resolve to make sure that our server is running
‫whenever the bootstrap function returns.
‫So this means that here at this point in the program we are going to be listening here for Http requests
‫incoming on Port 9000.
‫And with this we have the initial version of our server.
‫We have not yet implemented the Hello World functionality, but we are now going to compile our server
‫and we are going to run it just to make sure that the setup on your machine is correct.
‫So let's head over here to the terminal and we are going to make sure that we are in the correct directory.
‫So everything in this course is happening inside the rest API directory.
‫So make sure that you are inside this specific directory.
‫So here we are going to be compiling our server code by running the command NPM run build.
‫When we run this command, we are going to be running this build configuration file which is going to
‫output the result of the compilation happen inside this dist folder here.
‫So it's the dist folder inside the rest API.
‫Inside this specific folder we are going to find here, the result of the compilation of our server.
‫We can see here that we have a source directory and inside it we have a main.js file.
‫So this is the entry point of our program.
‫If we now see the into the this directory and from here, if we do a CD into source directory, we are
‫going to get here a main.js file.
‫You can see that we also have here the source maps and the TypeScript type definitions for the files.
‫This is normal and expected.
‫So what we want to do here in this folder is to run the main dot JS file.
‫Let's use Node and let's run main dot JS.
‫So once we run this command, we are going to see that our server is now running.
‫We have here a Nest application running on port 9000.
‫Let's see if indeed we have here something running.
‫We are going to open here a second tab and we are going to access port 9000.
‫So as we can see, we have indeed here an Http server running.
‫We are now getting the default reply from Nestjs whenever something is not found, which is a status
‫code of 404 not found and the default message cannot get the root URL.
‫This is normal because we have not yet defined any controllers for our application and we're going to
‫do that in the next lesson.
‫Notice that if you don't have a plugin in your browser in order to display Json in a nicely formatted
‫way, you are going to receive this response.
‫Instead, in plain text I advise you to install the same plugin as I have installed here for viewing
‫Json in your browser.
‫It's this plugin, the Json formatter Chrome plugin, and with this we have confirmed that the initial
‫version of our server is indeed working correctly.
‫Let's for the moment stop it and start implementing our first rest endpoint.
‫We are going to be writing our first Nestjs controller.