‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to complete our Nestjs Hello world example.
‫We are going to be writing here our first nestjs controller.
‫So we already have here a server up and running.
‫So we now just need to define our rest endpoint.
‫Now our Nestjs application, just like an angular application, can be subdivided into multiple modules
‫that are isolated from one another.
‫So each module might have its own set of services and functionality that is not necessarily publicly
‫visible to other modules of the application.
‫Let's then structure our application like that.
‫We are going to be defining here a new module that is going to be containing all the functionality related
‫to courses in our application.
‫Let's then define here a new folder and inside it we are going to be defining a new feature module that
‫we are going to be calling the courses module.
‫For that, let's create a new file with the name courses App.module.ts.
‫Inside it.
‫We are going to be defining here a new class that we are going to be calling courses module.
‫And just like before, we are going to annotate this with the module decorator of Nestjs, we are going
‫to be defining the configuration of the courses module later.
‫Right now let's take this new feature module and let's import it here in our application root module.
‫We can do so by using here the import property of the module configuration.
‫Here we are going to be providing an array with all the modules that we are importing into the application
‫root module.
‫So let's go ahead and import here.
‫The courses feature module.
‫Again, please make sure that you import the correct file.
‫As you can see, there are two files with similar name one on the front end corresponding to the front
‫end functionality of courses containing a series of angular components and services and on the back
‫end we have the corresponding module, which has the rest end points that we are going to be calling
‫from those same screens.
‫So let's import here the correct module from this specific path with the courses module in place.
‫Let's now go ahead and define our first rest controller.
‫So a controller is responsible for receiving an Http request on the server and for providing the corresponding
‫Http response.
‫The name controller comes from the terminology model view controller.
‫So the model is going to be our data.
‫The view is going to be the response returned to the client.
‫In this case, typically a Json payload and the controller is what glues the two things together by
‫processing the incoming request and providing an outgoing response, let's then define here our first
‫controller inside here, the courses folder.
‫We are going to define a new folder called Controllers where we are going to be writing the multiple
‫controllers of our module.
‫Now, in our first example, we are going to be providing here a list of courses.
‫So let's go ahead and define here a controller for that specific courses entity, which is going to
‫be called courses, dot controller, dot TS.
‫Inside this file, let's go ahead and define a class with the same name courses controller and let's
‫decorate it with the controller decorator from Nestjs.
‫Now, before implementing this class, let's go ahead and plug it into Nestjs.
‫We need to define it as being a controller.
‫So here in our courses module we are going to use here the controllers property.
‫We are going to be providing here an array containing all the controllers of our application.
‫And with this we can now specify our first endpoint.
‫So our endpoint is going to be receiving an incoming request and providing the Hello World string as
‫a response.
‫So let's define here a new function.
‫We are simply going to call it Hello World, and we are going to annotate this function with the add
‫get decorator from Nestjs Common.
‫So this is going to mark this function as the handler of a particular incoming Http request.
‫So in order to specify the path of the incoming Http request, let's say that, for example, we want
‫to handle the requests slash API.
‫Hello dash world.
‫So an incoming get Http request with this URL would be handled by this function.
‫Now, typically the processing of an Http request happens asynchronously.
‫We want to, for example, query a database and get back a response.
‫So let's go ahead and mark this function as being an asynchronous function.
‫This means that the function will either explicitly or implicitly always return a promise.
‫Let's return here.
‫Our result we are going to be returning.
‫Hello world.
‫Now notice that even though we are returning.
‫Here's a plain string and not a promise.
‫The async functionality is going to take this plain string and it's going to automatically wrap it in
‫a promise for us so we don't necessarily have to return here a promise each time the return type of
‫this function is going to be implicitly promise of string.
‫And with this we have specified here our first controller with the slash Hello world rest endpoint.
‫Let's see this in action.
‫We are going to switch over here to the terminal and we are going to build again our backend.
‫So here from inside the rest API folder, we are going to run the command NPM run build.
‫This is simply going to compile our code and output it into the dist folder.
‫In a moment we are going to show you how to automate these steps so that you can run your back end server
‫on hot reload mode in development.
‫But right now let's simply run again the new version of the server using Node.
‫So we want to run node and access inside the dist folder, the source directory.
‫And here we want to run the file main.js that contains the new version of our server.
‫If we now start Node, we are going to see that this time around we have here a bit more of output in
‫our console.
‫We can see that we have started the Nestjs application and that we have mapped here the slash api slash
‫hello world URL for get requests into the courses controller.
‫Let's now see our new rest endpoint in action.
‫We are going to open here a second tab and instead of trying to access the root path of our server,
‫we are going to instead be accessing slash API.
‫Hello dash world.
‫Let's then try this new URL and as you can see we get here the output.
‫Hello world.
‫So we have now just built our first rest endpoint using nestjs.
‫So now that we have here our Hello world example up and running, let's now turn this controller into
‫the controller for the courses entity and let's return instead here a list of courses.
‫We are also going to show you how to run our back end in hot reload mode so that you can easily deploy
‫new versions of our back end in development.