‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to implement the first rest endpoint of our application.
‫We are going to implement our endpoint using some data that we have here available in a TypeScript file,
‫and we are going to serve the data to our application and see it displayed on the screen.
‫Let's go ahead and start by removing this Hello world example that we built in our last lesson.
‫So as we have seen in this class, we are going to be managing the courses entity which corresponds
‫to this list of courses that we see here on the screen.
‫Let's then define here a new method that we are going to call, find all courses.
‫This is going to be returning an array of courses that will be displayed here in our home screen.
‫Now let's add here a type annotation for the return of this function.
‫This is going to be returning a promise of course, array.
‫We are going to be importing here the course entity from the shared folder in our application.
‫So if you notice here at the root of our application, we have here a shared folder containing a couple
‫of entities.
‫We have the course entity and we also have the lesson entity.
‫So these are the entities that we will be using throughout this course.
‫Now going back here to the course controller, we are going to be annotating this function with the
‫async keyword, meaning that this is expected to return a promise.
‫Notice that the course entity is going to be shared between the front end and the back end.
‫So that's why we put it here on this particular folder.
‫Let's now define this as being a rest endpoint by adding here the get annotation, just like we did
‫before.
‫And let's say that this endpoint is going to be available under the URL slash API slash courses which
‫corresponds to common rest conventions.
‫Now all we have to do is to return here some data.
‫We are going to be getting our data here from the rest API folder from the DB data file.
‫Later on in this course we are going to be fetching the data from a MongoDB database.
‫But right now we just want to quickly return some data for test purposes.
‫As we can see in this file, we have several types of data defined we have here users, we have courses
‫and we also have lessons.
‫And the data is available under the form of these maps.
‫So as you can see, the test data has here an ID, which is the ID of the entity, and the value here
‫is going to be the entity itself for the corresponding ID.
‫So we have courses, lessons and we also have here a series of utility functions to quickly manipulate
‫the data.
‫So let's go ahead and use this, find all courses function and let's quickly use it here inside our
‫courses controller in order to return here some data.
‫So let's return this as the output of this function.
‫And with this we have implemented here our first courses endpoint.
‫We are returning here a full list of courses from our test file DB data.
‫Now before trying this out, let's find a better way of building our application.
‫So far we are running the compiler manually and restarting our node process again each time.
‫So let's find a better way of running our code using a hot reload mode.
‫Let's see how we are going to do that.
‫We're going to head over to the terminal and we are going to be stopping our server.
‫Now make sure that you are on the rest folder from here.
‫We are going to clear the content of the dist directory.
‫So in order to do that we are going to run the command NPM run clean and this will delete the dist folder.
‫Now in order to build our application and restart our node server with each code change, we are going
‫to be using the following utility TSC watch.
‫So this is a dependency that we have installed in our Package.json that is going to allow us to recompile
‫our code each time that we make a code change.
‫And it will also allow us to restart our server whenever the compilation finishes.
‫Let's have a look at how we are going to do this.
‫We are going to open here the package.json that we have available here inside the rest folder.
‫So it's this one here under rest API and not the package.json that you have here in your angular application.
‫So in the correct package.json we are going to find here a couple of tasks that are going to make our
‫lives easier throughout the course and that you can also implement in your own project.
‫You can clear here the content of the folder using NPM run clean and you can also start your server
‫locally using the TSC watch command to this command.
‫We simply have to pass in the option minus P and using this option we are going to pass in the configuration
‫of the TypeScript compiler which is available under this file.
‫With this command highlighted in blue, we would be.
‫Running our compilation each time that we make a code change.
‫So TSC watch is going to wait for our changes to stabilize and using it each time that we hit command
‫or control.
‫S in order to save our file in the file system, that is going to trigger a new compilation of our code.
‫Now, after the compilation completes successfully, we want to then start our server.
‫So we are using this option here minus minus on success.
‫So whenever the compilation ends successfully, we are then going to be running this command.
‫We are going to be calling Node that we have installed globally in our command line and from there we
‫are going to be running the Main.js file inside the Dist folder.
‫If you have been following along the course and you have imported here the course class inside your
‫courses controller, this is going to be the path where you find your main.js file.
‫So make sure that you are using the correct path which is already filled in by default to avoid errors.
‫So with this command here, start local, we will be able to start our server in hot reloading mode.
‫Now we want to combine this task, start local with the clean task.
‫What we want to do is whenever we start our server the first time, we want to make sure that we clear
‫the dist folder and from there we want to listen to new changes as we go along.
‫So in order to achieve that, we are going to be using the server task.
‫This is using a utility called NPM Run.
‫All that provides a couple of command line utilities such as, for example, Run S, which allows us
‫to run tasks sequentially one after the other.
‫This is unlike Run P, which is another utility that you have available that allows us to run tasks
‫in parallel.
‫So here we want to use run s for running tasks sequentially.
‫We want to clean the content of the dist folder first and once the directory is cleaned then we want
‫to start our server in hot reload mode.
‫So from now on and until the end of the course, each time that you want to start your server in development
‫mode, you are going to run from inside the rest folder.
‫The following command NPM run server.
‫This is going to clear the dist folder and it's going to start your back end in watch mode.
‫Let's then try this out.
‫We are going to open here a second window and see if the new version of our controller is up and running.
‫So the URL that we want to access is slash API slash courses.
‫Let's then head over to Port 9000 and access this URL.
‫So after a moment we should see that we have here all our data getting served via this get request as
‫expected.
‫So we have here a course with an ID, a description, a long description, etcetera, all the data that
‫we need in order to display here, this list of courses.
‫Now let's confirm that our application is at this moment already fetching the data from the backend.
‫We are going to open here a second terminal while our backend is still running.
‫And from the Nestjs course folder we are going to run the following command NPM start and it's important
‫that you use NPM start and not NG serve in order to configure NG serve with the correct proxy settings.
‫After a moment our application is going to be running on port 4200.
‫So let's head over there and reload the application we have here, the login page.
‫Let's use the side menu and go to the courses component.
‫So as we can see, we have here the component that is correctly displaying the data.
‫If we open here, the chrome dev tools and we head over here to the network tab and we reload again,
‫the application we are going to see here in the network log.
‫If we filter by slash API a call to slash API slash courses.
‫So this is hitting our backend server as expected.
‫So the angular CLI is proxying.
‫Everything that starts with slash API to our backend server via the configuration that we have here
‫on this file proxy dot Json.
‫So as you can see, the angular CLI is sending any Http requests starting with slash API to our backend
‫server.
‫So in order for all of this to work, it's essential that in your main.ts file you are listening here
‫on Port 9000, so your backend server needs to be running in this port and it's important that you start
‫your application with NPM start and not NG serve.
‫Otherwise the proxy configuration will not be in place and you will get here a 404 not found or another
‫similar error.
‫If you are curious to know what is the component in the Angular application that is displaying this
‫list of courses, we are now going to have a look at it.
‫This is called the home component.
‫So the home component corresponds to this component here that you see on the screen that gets displayed
‫by the angular router whenever.
‫We access the slash courses URL.
‫So as you can see, this component is loading the data from our backend at component initialization
‫time via the NG on init lifecycle hook.
‫Here we are using an Http service that is getting injected here via dependency injection that we will
‫also be using in our nestjs backend.
‫And here we are calling our courses via the find all courses method from the Http service.
‫If we have a look at this implementation, we are going to see that we are using simply the Http client
‫in order to access slash API slash courses, which is the endpoint that we have just built here.
‫Using the courses controller, we have defined how to handle the slash API slash courses get request.
‫And with this we have implemented the first version of our rest controller and we have shown that this
‫is indeed correctly integrated with our front end application.
‫We have a way of hot reloading our code.
‫So what we are going to do next is we are going to implement this endpoint, not using here some dummy
‫data that we have retrieved from our data file.
‫We are going to instead be serving the data from a database.
‫We are going to be using MongoDB in this course.
‫So our next few steps are going to be we are going to learn how to debug this code if we need to.
‫Then we are going to set up our MongoDB database and we are going to populate it with some data.
‫After that, when we have our database ready, we are going to come back to this controller and we are
‫going to read the data from the database instead of from our test file.
‫This is all coming right up in the next few lessons.
‫Let's now first start by learning how to debug our Nestjs code if needed.