‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to quickly learn how to debug our Nestjs backend.
‫We are going to do this using the same debugger that we usually use for the front end the chrome dev
‫tools.
‫Now your IDE could also have a custom built debugger such as, for example, Webstorm or even Visual
‫Studio code.
‫But I would recommend that you always use the Chrome debugger because this way you can use the same
‫debugger for your front end and your back end.
‫It's the same tool independently of the debugger that you choose.
‫What you want to do is the ability of triggering, for example, programmatic debug breakpoints such
‫as, for example, the ones triggered by the debugger keyword.
‫You also want the ability of setting a breakpoint by clicking here on the lateral bar of the debugger.
‫So let's see how can we do that in our nestjs backend?
‫So we are going to open here a terminal and we are going to see that for debugging our nestjs process.
‫We simply need to call the node executable.
‫We need to pass in this special parameter minus minus inspect broker.
‫So this is going to run node in debug mode.
‫And after that we simply have to pass in the path to the file that we want to run.
‫In this case we want to run the dist slash rest API slash source main.js file.
‫So this command here would start our node process in debug mode.
‫Now, in order to avoid typing this each time, we already have here a task ready for you in your package.json.
‫So here you have a task right below the task that you used for running the server in normal development
‫mode, which is the start colon debug task.
‫So this is also going to use TSC watch to run our TypeScript, build in watch mode, reloading the server
‫each time that we complete a successful compilation.
‫But here in Onsuccess, yes, we are passing this extra option here to the node process.
‫So this means that if we go here to our command line and from here the rest slash API folder, we are
‫going to run the following command NPM run, start colon debug.
‫If we run this command this time around, we are going to be starting our back end in debug mode and
‫also in a hot reload mode as usual.
‫So whenever our process starts up, you are going to see this special message saying that the debugger
‫is listening on this port.
‫Now if you try to load now some data from the backend using, for example, this slash API slash courses,
‫you are going to get here, an error like the server is not yet running and that's because we have started
‫the process in debug mode.
‫So the process is currently frozen and waiting for us to attach a debugger to it before we attach the
‫debugger.
‫Nothing will happen.
‫Now what we need to do is to attach the Chrome debugger dev tools to this running process.
‫So the chrome dev Tools debugger is the one that you can access here by inspecting the page and accessing
‫here the sources tab.
‫Here we have a full JavaScript debugger ready to use.
‫So that's the debugger that we want to attach to this process.
‫In order to do that, we are going to open here a new chrome tab and from here we are going to type
‫the chrome colon inspect.
‫So this is going to attach the chrome debugger dev tools to this particular running process running
‫on this port.
‫9299.
‫Let's enter this URL and as you can see, the process has already been detected.
‫So you could have here multiple remote targets and configure here the correct ports.
‫But in this case, it's not necessary.
‫We are simply going to click here on this inspect link and this is going to open our debugger dev tools.
‫So as you can see, we get here a message saying that the debugger is currently paused.
‫So this means that our program is not yet running and the process is still frozen.
‫So in order to initialize the process, we are going to click here on play.
‫And this is going to allow our backend process to actually start.
‫So if we switch back to our workspace, we are going to see that now our process has indeed started.
‫So we have here below the debugger initialization message, the usual nestjs specific messages that
‫we get, such as, for example, that our slash API slash courses URL is mapped to the courses controller.
‫ET cetera.
‫So this means that if we now hit this endpoint, our controller is going to get triggered and we should
‫see this breakpoint get triggered.
‫Let's see if that's the case.
‫We are going to go back here to this window that previously was not working because we had not yet attached
‫the debugger to this running process.
‫We are going to refresh this call here to slash API slash courses and.
‫This time around, we are going to see that this immediately triggers our debugger breakpoint.
‫So from here we can inspect the content of any variables.
‫We can add extra endpoints.
‫ET cetera.
‫Just like you usually do with your front end.
‫You can also add here a second breakpoint.
‫For example, we are going to click here to resume the script execution, and we can see that the second
‫breakpoint has been hit.
‫So we don't need to use programmatic breakpoints in order to debug our code.
‫We can simply define them here using the dev tools.
‫Let's release the second breakpoint.
‫And now if we go back to our workspace, we are going to see that we get the data as usual.
‫So as you can see, it's very simple to debug our process using the chrome dev tools if necessary.
‫Now I would recommend throughout the course that you only run the process in debug mode whenever you
‫are troubleshooting something.
‫So right now we are going to stop here our process and we are going to be using NPM run server throughout
‫the rest of the course.
‫Let's now also quickly clear here this debugger breakpoint that was only there for demonstration purposes
‫and let's now continue the course.
‫So here we were retrieving our data from a file that we have here on the file system, just containing
‫here some test data with some courses and lessons.
‫Let's now instead get our data from a database.
‫We are going to be using MongoDB.
‫So in the next few lessons, we are going to be setting up our MongoDB database.