‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new section of the Nestjs in practice course, we are going to be adding common security features
‫to our backend, such as authentication and authorization.
‫We are going to be basing our solution around Json web tokens.
‫So let's break down how we are going to approach this.
‫First we are going to be implementing starting from the front end, the login screen.
‫So currently if you click here on the side menu and you click on login, you are going to be redirected
‫here to this login page.
‫Now the login page corresponds to the login component and it's not implemented yet.
‫We are then going to start implementing our authentication starting at this screen.
‫Whenever the login button gets pushed, we are going to see that we are going to call the login method
‫and here is where we are going to start our implementation.
‫So how are we going to do this?
‫We are going to call a new endpoint in our Nestjs backend, which is going to be the slash API slash
‫login endpoint to that secure backend endpoint.
‫We are going to be passing the username and the password that we are going to retrieve here from the
‫login form.
‫Now our backend is going to receive the username, which will be the email and the password and the
‫backend is going to validate to make sure that the user password is correct and indeed corresponds to
‫this particular user.
‫So how is our Nestjs backend endpoint going to do that?
‫Our login endpoint is going to be able to do that because here going back here to our database, we
‫are going to have here a user's collection that was created whenever you run the Populate DB script
‫at the beginning of the course and you are going to see that in this collection you already have two
‫users ready to use.
‫So you have here the student at Angular University, Ohio User, which is a regular user that has only
‫read Access to the data and you have here an administrative user which can also edit the data.
‫Besides the email, you also have here a password hash stored in the database.
‫Now if you look at this, it's a strange looking string.
‫It's the password essentially, but it has been transformed by a hashing algorithm.
‫So the hashing algorithm that we have used has turned the password and also a unique random number that
‫is unique to this user, and it has used it to produce a password digest.
‫This is a new form of the password that can only be derived from the original password and the unique
‫salt random number associated to each user and that it's safe to store in the database.
‫Now why is it safe to store the password in this form on the database?
‫This is because it's essentially computationally impossible to get the password back from the hash.
‫So the hash is an irreversible process.
‫So if by some reason a malicious attacker managed to put his hands on our user's collection and grabbing
‫all the password hashes of each user, that same attacker would not be able to obtain the actual passwords
‫from the user and use them to log in to the website and impersonate a given user.
‫If you are curious to learn how these password hashes were generated from the original password, these
‫were created using this particular NPM package, password, hash and salt.
‫So this is a simple and easy to use node package that uses internal APIs from Node in order to hash
‫our password in a secure way by using secure defaults.
‫So as you can see, the hashes have been generated using this algorithm which is considered safe for
‫password storage and we have hashed it 10,000 times.
‫This means that we hash the password once through this algorithm, then we take the output and we hash
‫it again.
‫ET cetera.
‫Until we do that 10,000 times, we get the output of that process and we store it in the database in
‫the following format.
‫So here we have a dollar separator between the multiple components of the string that we have stored
‫in the database.
‫We can see that this is the algorithm that has been used.
‫We can see here the number of iterations.
‫This is the hash output and this is the salt.
‫So this is a unique random number that is unique per user.
‫This means that if two users have used exactly the same password, then even though the password is
‫the same, the string that gets stored in the database is going to be different due to the use of the
‫random salt.
‫This means that if an attacker manages to identify the password of one user, you will not know what
‫other users in the user list share the same password because all the hashes stored on the database.
‫Are going to be unique, even if the passwords are identical.
‫So going back here to our program, here is what we're about to do.
‫We are going to take the email and password and we're going to send it to our backend using the authentication
‫service.
‫We are then going to create a new rest endpoint that is going to validate the password by using the
‫digest on the database.
‫And if the password is then valid, that same login backend service is going to create what is known
‫as a bearer token.
‫This is a small Json payload known as a Json web token that uniquely identifies the user.
‫So anyone in possession of that bearer token is going to be identifiable by our backend in a secure
‫way.
‫Let's then get started with our authentication implementation.
‫We are going to start by implementing here the login logic in our login component.
‫This is coming right up in the next lesson.