‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to start the implementation of our login backend controller.
‫So the first thing that we are going to do is starting with our front end.
‫We are going to send the email and the password back to the client.
‫So here whenever we click on login, we are going to be triggering here the login method in the login
‫component.
‫At this point, the first thing that we are going to do is to retrieve the user email and password from
‫the form we are going to grab here.
‫The current form value by accessing this dot form dot value.
‫Now, using the current form value, we are going to send this back to the client using the authentication
‫service.
‫Let's have a look at how this service is implemented.
‫So as you can see, we only have here one method, which is login.
‫It takes two parameters, which is the login and the password, and it performs an Http post call to
‫our backend to this endpoint slash API slash login.
‫And in the body of the Http post call we are going to be passing the email and the password.
‫Let's then call this service.
‫Going back here to our login method, we are going to access here the authentication service and we
‫are going to call the login method.
‫We are going to then pass in here as the first parameter, the email, and the second parameter is going
‫to be the password value of the form.
‫So the name of the parameters come here from the form configuration.
‫Now in order to trigger the request to the backend, we need to subscribe to this observable, otherwise
‫the request will not be triggered.
‫Let's add here a couple of handlers to our subscribe call.
‫So let's add here a success handler and here, whenever the login occurs successfully, we want to redirect
‫the user back to the courses page.
‫So let's use for that.
‫The router that we already have injected here in our constructor.
‫Let's use the API, navigate by URL for example, and let's redirect the user to slash courses.
‫So this will display then the list of courses to the user.
‫Let's also add here an error handler just in case that something goes wrong.
‫We are going to grab here the error.
‫We are going to log the error to the console and we are going to show a simple pop up to the user alerting
‫the user that the login has failed.
‫And with this we have sent an Http request to our backend containing the email and password.
‫So let's now create here a new controller to handle the login request.
‫We are going to create here a new module for our backend which is going to be isolated from the courses
‫module.
‫It's going to contain its own set of separate services.
‫So let's create here a new directory and we are going to call this model off.
‫So this is going to contain everything related to authentication and authorization in our backend.
‫Inside this directory, we are going to be creating here a new controller which is going to be the off
‫controller.
‫Now this controller is going to be part of a new module.
‫So let's create here a new separate file that we are going to call off, App.module.ts.
‫So it's important to bear in mind that there is a similarly named file in our front end that contains
‫the login component.
‫So this module here needs to be added to our back end inside the rest API folder where all our backend
‫is.
‫Let's then write here the definition of our module.
‫The module as usual is going to be a plain TypeScript class that we need to decorate with the module
‫decorator from Nestjs.
‫Let's go ahead and add here in the controllers property, our new controller that we are going to be
‫defining in this file that we have just added the authentication controller.
‫Let's define here the skeleton of a class and let's annotate this with the controller decorator from
‫Nestjs.
‫So this controller is meant to target the requests to the slash API slash login.
‫So let's add here simply login so that we are sure that we can grab this request.
‫We are going to create here a new method that is going to be called login and we are going to annotate
‫this with the post decorator from Nestjs.
‫We are going to see later how to implement this method and how to grab everything that we need out of
‫the Http request.
‫Right now, let's set up this class as a controller that belongs here to our authentication module.
‫So let's add here the authentication controller to the controllers property.
‫And with this we have an initial version of our authentication module.
‫Now all we need to do is to plug this in as a feature module in our backend.
‫So this file here, App.module.ts inside the rest API folder contains our root module for our Nestjs
‫application.
‫So let's go ahead and add here on the imports our new authentication feature module.
‫And with this we have the skeleton of our authentication module in place.
‫Let's then start implementing step by step our login controller.