‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson we are going to implement here, the login logic in our authentication controller.
‫So at this point we have received in our backend an Http post call that targets the slash API slash
‫login endpoint.
‫The request contains in its body a Json payload that contains two properties the email and the password.
‫So we need to grab them here in our login method.
‫For that, Let's start by defining here two parameters the email and the password.
‫And to make it clear that this is not the hashed version of the password, let's rename this variable
‫to plaintext password.
‫So this is the password exactly as the user has typed it in the password input box.
‫Now how to retrieve this from the Http body?
‫We are going to be using the nestjs body decorator.
‫So the body decorator is meant to fetch either the full body into a property or only properties of our
‫Json payloads.
‫So in this case we want to fetch in here the email property and here in the case of the plain text password,
‫we want to grab the password property.
‫So as you can see, we can give a different name to our input variable then the one that we have used
‫in our Json payload.
‫So here at this point in our program, we have both the email and the password.
‫So we are ready to start validating the email and password combination.
‫For that, we are going to be needing to query the database and fetch the password hash from the database
‫in order to query the database.
‫We are going to need a new entity which is going to be the user entity.
‫Let's add it directly here to our authentication module.
‫We are going to be adding here a new schema file that we are going to be calling users dot schema,
‫dot ts.
‫Going back here to our MongoDB database, this user schema is going to correspond to the users collection
‫that we see here.
‫So as you can see, we have here a couple of properties.
‫We have the email, we have a list of roles that if we open we can see that the student user has only
‫the role student while the admin user has the admin role.
‫So each user might have multiple roles, each role with different permissions, and each user also has
‫a unique password hash.
‫So this is the entity that we want to read from the database.
‫Let's then go back to our program and add here a schema for this entity.
‫We are going to be defining here a new variable that we are going to call users schema and we are going
‫to make this a new Mongoose schema.
‫Let's pass it a configuration object and here we are going to be adding three properties.
‫We are going to be adding the email as a string.
‫We are going to be adding the roles as an array and we are going to be adding the password hash as a
‫string.
‫So as you can see, this corresponds to the three properties that we saw on the user's collection on
‫the database.
‫Let's now plug in this schema into our authentication module.
‫For that, we are going to be using a Mongoose module as usual.
‫Let's add it here to our imports.
‫We are going to add here a call to Mongoose module for feature because the authentication feature is
‫also a feature module.
‫And in here we are going to be passing an array of schemas.
‫So let's add here a configuration property.
‫We are going to be specifying here a name.
‫So the name that we need to give here is the name of our entity, which will be user and the schema
‫property needs to be our user schema that we have just defined.
‫And with this we are now able to read users here from our authentication controller.
‫Now we could create here a separate repository service, but in the case of this particular controller,
‫because we want to focus on the authentication aspects and because the controller is going to be very
‫simple, we are going to go ahead and inject directly here the user model.
‫Let's define here a new property.
‫We are going to call it user model and let's apply it with the inject model decorator.
‫So to the decorator, we need to pass in here the name of the entity that we want to inject here.
‫So let's inject here the model for the user entity.
‫And with this we are now able to query the users collection from the authentication controller.
‫Let's then go ahead and do that here at the beginning of our method.
‫So the first thing that we need to do in order to validate if the login is correct or not is to fetch
‫the user from the database.
‫Let's access here the user model and let's use the find one method to.
‫Fetch the user from the database.
‫So the user is going to be found by using the email property.
‫We are going to await for the evaluation of this promise to go through and in order to be able to use
‫the async await syntax, we need to annotate this method with the async keyword.
‫So now at this point in the program, we should have here a valid user that does exist in our database.
‫Let's check if that is the case.
‫So if there is no user that corresponds to this email, this means that the user has not been created
‫yet.
‫So we can't login the user.
‫Let's add here some logging so that we can see on the console log that the error did occur.
‫And let's throw back to the client an error saying that this user is not authorized to access the application.
‫In order to do that, we are going to be throwing here a new Http exception that already exists in the
‫Nestjs common package.
‫This is going to be the unauthorized exception.
‫So this is going to send back to the client an Http status code of 401 unauthorized.
‫So with this, we are sure that there is indeed a user in the database that corresponds to this email.
‫So all it's left to do is to validate if the password that we got here is correct.
‫If the password is correct, we need to be able to create a new Json web token that is going to uniquely
‫identify this user.
‫For that, we are going to be using a couple of NPM packages that we are going to be introducing in
‫the next lesson.