‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to finish the implementation of our authentication controller.
‫We are going to finish here the implementation of login by validating the user password and by creating
‫a Json web token, which is going to be our bearer token.
‫So as the name indicates, anyone that can present to the server this token that we are about to emit
‫will be able to prove its identity to the server.
‫Let's see how this works.
‫So in order to validate our plaintext password against the password hash that we have read here from
‫the database, we are going to be using again this small package called password hash and salt.
‫So the advantage of this package is that it uses only internal node APIs in its implementation.
‫So this means that this will always work in any node version because this algorithm, for example,
‫that is getting used by the package for generating the hash comes from the node engine itself and not
‫from a third party package.
‫So in order to avoid all installation issues, we have chosen to use a package that simply uses node
‫internal modules.
‫This way this will always work independently of the node version.
‫Now, in order to be able to validate our password hash against a plain text password, we need to use
‫here the verify against API from the password hash and salt package.
‫So going back to our program, let's see how this works.
‫The first thing that we need to do is here in our import clauses to go ahead and import the password,
‫hash and salt package.
‫With this package in place, we are now ready to validate the plain text password.
‫So we are going to be using here the password function that we have imported from the password hash
‫and salt package.
‫We are going to be passing to this function, the plain text password.
‫So the password, just like the user typed it in the password input form.
‫And we are going to be calling here the verify against API.
‫This API call is going to take a couple of parameters.
‫So the first parameter that we are going to be passing is the user password hash coming from the database.
‫And the second parameter that we are going to be passing is a callback.
‫So this callback is going to be called whenever the verification of the password has completed.
‫So the first parameter as usual in node callbacks is going to be an error if the error has occurred.
‫And the second parameter is going to contain the information if the password has been correctly verified
‫or not.
‫Now let's first handle the case when the password was wrong.
‫So if the password has not been verified, then in that case we need to immediately throw back to the
‫user an unauthorized exception in a similar way to what we did here.
‫Whenever the email was not found in our database.
‫Now notice that at this point we need to return as the output of this method, a promise that should
‫be successfully evaluated if the password is valid and we manage to create a Json web token.
‫But it should also throw an error in case, for example, this password is wrong.
‫Now, in this case, because this password package has a callback that cannot be easily converted to
‫a promise based API.
‫The best way to handle these cases is to create our own custom promise and return it here as the output
‫of this method.
‫So for that we are going to be using the Promise constructor, which is a very convenient way of creating
‫a custom promise.
‫So this constructor takes here a couple of standard parameters.
‫One is the resolve function to be called whenever the promise is successfully evaluated and the reject
‫function that should be called whenever the promise gets rejected.
‫So here inside the body of the promise construct here we are then going to be calling here the password
‫verify against call.
‫So now all we need to do is to take this logic that verifies if the password is correct or not, and
‫we are going to paste it in here inside the body of our custom promise.
‫So here, if the password has not been verified, meaning that the password that the user typed on the
‫login form is wrong and does not match the password stored on the database, then on that case we should
‫reject this custom promise so we can do so by simply calling here reject and by passing the value emitted.
‫So in our case, we want to add here as the rejection value, a new unauthorized exception.
‫Now here we have verified that the password is correct.
‫So at this point in the program, all we need to do is to create a Json web token that is going to uniquely
‫identify these.
‫Use it.
‫So that's what we're going to be doing in our next lesson.