‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to finish the implementation of our login controller.
‫So here we have already validated the user plain text password against the password hash stored in the
‫database.
‫So now at this point in the program, what we want to do is to create a Json web token that will allow
‫to prove that the carrier of the token is indeed a given user in our system.
‫So how does having this token prove that a request comes from a given user?
‫Well, because our service that we are writing here only creates a token.
‫If the password is correct, then this proves that the carrier of the token is also the user because
‫only the user should have known the user password.
‫This of course assumes that the user did not lose the password, that the attacker did not manage to
‫guess the user password and that the password was not stolen by some means, such as, for example,
‫using a compromised network where the user was suffering a man in the middle attack, etcetera.
‫Going back to our program at this point in the program, we want to be able to create a Json web token
‫that identifies the user.
‫So what is a Json web token and what does it look like?
‫Well, if we go here to this website, JWT, dot IO and we scroll down, besides being able to read
‫here some documentation on Json web tokens, we also have here a live example.
‫So you see this string here highlighted.
‫This is an example of a Json web token, its URL friendly in the sense that you can paste it as a URL
‫parameter without any escaping being necessary.
‫And it's a plain text string that is divided on three parts and we can identify the different parts
‫of the string via the dot separator.
‫So the first part here is the header.
‫We can see it decoded here.
‫It provides some information about how to decode the Json web token we have here, the algorithm used,
‫etcetera.
‫The second part is going to be the payload.
‫So here is where we are going to identify the user.
‫And the third part is going to be the signature.
‫So this is a cryptographic signature that proves that the token is valid in the payload of our Json
‫web token, we are going to be adding both the user identifier so that we can know that the token is
‫associated to a given user.
‫But we are also going to be adding the user roles such as administrator student ET cetera.
‫In order to be able to create a Json web token like this and send it back to our front end, we are
‫going to be using the Node Json web token library from zero.
‫So this is an open source library that allows us to quickly create new Json web tokens.
‫We have already installed it here in our program.
‫So in order to be able to use it, we simply have to generate a unique secret that we are going to be
‫installing in our server.
‫With that secret, we are going to be able to easily create new Json web tokens by calling JWT dot sign
‫here.
‫We are going to be passing the payload of our Json web token.
‫And here in the second parameter we need to add our secret.
‫Let's then start by quickly adding a new signing secret to our program.
‫We are going to open here our constants file where we have stored here, our MongoDB connection, and
‫here we are going to be adding a new secret that we are going to be calling JWT secret.
‫We are going to paste in here a unique password that have generated before using a password generator.
‫So here we are, defining this as a constant in our program.
‫In your application, you probably would like to import this as an environment variable so that if you
‫want to change your secret, you would not need then to redeploy your program here.
‫For simplicity purposes, we are simply defining it as a constant.
‫Now we are going to go back here to our controller and we are going to be importing here the JWT library
‫that we already have installed.
‫Now that we have here a reference to the Json web token library, we can use it to create a new Json
‫web token.
‫We are going to do so in the following way.
‫We are going to call JWT dot sign and we are going to be passing here a payload.
‫So this is going to be the payload of our Json web token.
‫We are going to pass in here a unique user identifier.
‫Let's say that we are going to be using the email for that and we are also going to be passing here
‫the user roles.
‫So the Json web token is going to be the basis both of our authentication, but also of our authorization
‫solution here.
‫Here on the Rolls property.
‫We are going to pass in the user rolls.
‫Now, in order to sign this Json web token, we are going to be needing the signing secret that should
‫not be made available to the front end.
‫So this is something that only the back end should have access to.
‫And with this we have created here a sign Json web token.
‫We can now assign the output of this call here to a new constant that we are going to be calling of
‫JWT token.
‫So this property here is a string that looks like what we have seen here in the jwt.io website.
‫So this is a Json web token that is currently assigned here to this constant.
‫So now all we have to do is to send this back to the client.
‫The client will then use this to prove the identity of the user that is currently using a given instance
‫of our front end.
‫In order to send this back to the client, we need to call here the resolve function from our custom
‫promise and we need to pass it the value that is going to get emitted whenever the promise gets resolved
‫successfully.
‫So this is going to be a Json payload, which is going to contain only one property, which is going
‫to be the of JWT token property.
‫So this property will be a string, which is a Json web token and we are going to see what this payload
‫looks like in a moment when we test our new implementation of the login service which is now completed.
‫Let's now see our authentication controller in action.
‫We are going to switch here to a larger window where we have here the network tab.
‫Let's clear here the network log and let's head over here to the login page using our side menu.
‫Here we have a couple of pre-filled in valid values student at Angular University, Ohio.
‫That's our user.
‫And we also have a pre-filled invalid password.
‫So this is just for simplicity purposes so that you can quickly log in and test the functionality.
‫Now before going ahead and clicking on the login button, let's test the cases where the login should
‫fail.
‫So let's say that we use here an email that does not exist, let's say does not exist at Angular university.io
‫we fill in here any password, we click login and take a look here at the network log we have here.
‫Login failed as expected because we got back from our backend a 401 unauthorized response.
‫So we have sent here in the body of our request two properties, the email and the password.
‫And we got back, as expected, a 401.
‫Unauthorized error.
‫Now let's clear here the network log and let's now try this with a valid email that corresponds to a
‫user that indeed exists in our database student at Angular University, Ohio.
‫But instead of providing here a correct value, let's just type in here any random value.
‫So if we now click log in, we are going to get back again from the backend login failed and a 401 unauthorized
‫error reply as expected.
‫So so far a user with an invalid email and an invalid password did not manage to log in to our backend
‫as expected.
‫Now let's clear here the password field and for this particular email let's simply type the word password,
‫which as you already know well, is a bad example of a password.
‫This is just for simplicity purposes to make it easy for you to type in the correct password.
‫So we have entered here our correct password that you can also obtain simply by refreshing here the
‫login page.
‫Again, let's click on login and this time around we have here a 201 created response.
‫We got redirected to the courses page and we even called here the courses endpoint to get the list of
‫courses as expected.
‫Let's have a further look at this call to slash API slash login so we can see that we got here in the
‫response a Json payload containing one property of JWT token.
‫And here we can see this long string separated by dots.
‫This indeed looks like a Json web token.
‫Let's take the value of this string and let's go here to jwt.io.
‫We're going to clear here this text box and we're going to paste the JWT that we have just created.
‫So we did not manage to validate here the signature, but we can see here that the payload is indeed
‫the email of the user and the roles of the user, which in this case is only the student role.
‫So this shows that we have indeed created a valid Json web token in our back end.
‫Now in the next few lessons, we are going to learn how to use this Json web token to.
‫Notify the user in subsequent requests to our backend, such as, for example, in this second request
‫to slash API slash courses that was immediately sent after the login.