‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to learn exactly how should our front end application handle the authentication
‫Json web token that it receives after a successful login.
‫So whenever we trigger a login to the server using the login component, this is the controller that
‫is going to get triggered in our backend if the login is successful, meaning that the user and password
‫combination was correct and matched the content of our database, then we are going to send back to
‫the client application and Json payload containing our authentication Json web token.
‫Now somehow we need in our front end application to find a way to store this token somewhere where it
‫can be reused whenever subsequent Http requests are made to the same backend.
‫So whenever we do a second backend request after a successful login, we want to somehow attach to each
‫new request.
‫The Json web token.
‫This way whenever the request hits the backend, our backend is going to be able to inspect the content
‫of the Http request.
‫Look for the authentication token, validate its cryptographic signature and confirm that indeed the
‫request belongs to a particular user and no one else.
‫Let's then start by determining where the authentication token should be stored in our front end.
‫So whenever we do a login request from our login component using the login method of the authentication
‫service, we are going to then do a back end request to slash API slash login and we are going to get
‫back a payload containing the authentication token.
‫Now we are going to receive here the payload.
‫Let's give this a name.
‫We are going to say that this is the reply that we got from the backend.
‫Let's add it a type.
‫In this case we are going to use the type any.
‫And here under this Json reply, we are going to have here a property called off JWT token and this
‫is going to contain a string which is our Json web token.
‫Now we need to somehow store this string in our front end so that we can use it later on.
‫Now in our case, we are going to be storing our string in local storage.
‫So this is a great place to store data if we want the data to survive browser refreshes, which is our
‫case, we want to make sure that if the user refreshes the browser, it can still be correctly authenticated.
‫So we don't want just to store the Json web token in memory.
‫Instead, let's place it in local storage.
‫So local storage is a key value pair that only takes strings as stored values.
‫Let's define here the key under which we want to store our authentication Json web token.
‫Let's give it the exact same name as we have here of JWT token and let's pass in as the second argument
‫to set item the value of the Json web token taken from the reply.
‫So now the JWT will be stored in local storage and it will be available to get attached later on to
‫subsequent Http requests that our application might make.
‫Besides storing the authentication Json web token after a successful login, it's also important to
‫delete it after a log out, so the log out in our application is performed using here the log out button
‫that is implemented here using the application component.
‫So here the log out method is going to get called Whenever we click on the log out button, let's then
‫implement our log out logic.
‫So the first thing that we are going to do is access local storage and we are going to remove from local
‫storage our authentication Json web token.
‫Also to give some visual indication to the user that the log out happened correctly.
‫Let's go ahead and navigate here to the login page.
‫So for that we are going to be needing here the router.
‫Let's go ahead and inject it here in our construct here and with the router we can call here, navigate
‫by URL and redirect the user to the login page.
‫So with this we have our log out logic implemented.
‫So now the only thing that we need to do is to attach our authentication Json web token to every Http
‫request made after the successful login.
‫We are going to be doing that using an angular Http interceptor.
‫So if we open here, our route application module, we are going to notice that here we have configured
‫a class called an authentication interceptor.
‫This class is going to contain some logic that is going to get called with every Http request that we
‫make to our backend.
‫So this logic here is going to intercept the outgoing request and it's going to potentially modify it.
‫We can see that our authentication interceptor, what it's doing here is checking in local storage if
‫the authentication.
‫Json web token is present or not.
‫If it's present, then we are going to clone the outgoing request and we are going to add an extra Http
‫header called authorization and we are going to set as its value the Json web token itself.
‫On the other hand, if the authentication Json web token is not present in local storage, then we are
‫going to let the request go through without any further modification.
‫So we only clone the Http request and add the extra authorization header if we have a Json web token
‫to attach to it.
‫And in this way every request that is done after the initial login request will now contain a new header
‫containing our authentication Json web token.
‫Let's have a look at this in action.
‫We are going to switch to a larger window and we are going to perform a login.
‫So if we just reload the application and use the default values here, we should get the correct login
‫using the student user.
‫Let's keep an eye here on the network log.
‫So our login happened and as we can see here, as the result of the login request in the response we
‫got back here, a Json web token.
‫And now let's confirm that indeed this Json web token was stored in local storage.
‫We are going to open here the application tab and we are going to click here under the storage section
‫on local storage.
‫Let's click here, the Arrow dropdown, and let's click on the local host domain.
‫As we can see, we only have here one key stored in local storage.
‫It's our authentication Json web token, and we can see here that this indeed corresponds to the value
‫of our JWT.
‫Next in our network log, we have the request that was done after the successful login, which is the
‫request here to slash API slash courses.
‫So this is the request done here by the courses screen in order to fetch this list of courses from the
‫backend.
‫If we click here on this Http request and we select here the headers section, we are going to scroll
‫down and we are going to see that here in the request header section.
‫We have here an authorization header containing the Json web token attached to it as expected.
‫So as we can see, our interceptor already took care of attaching the JWT to the request that was done
‫immediately after the login.
‫So everything is working as expected.
‫So our next step now is to go to the backend and verify that the user is indeed correctly authenticated
‫by inspecting the authorization header.