‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to introduce a new notion.
‫We are going to talk about Nestjs middleware.
‫So we are going to learn exactly what is a middleware, when to use it and why we are going to be using
‫it in the context of authenticating a user request.
‫So if you remember in our previous lessons we have built here in our backend a login endpoint that after
‫validating the user password sends back to the client an authentication Json web token that can be used
‫to prove that a request belongs to a user.
‫Now the client application is going to store the authentication Json web token in local storage and
‫it's going to make sure to attach it to any other subsequent Http requests made by our client to our
‫backend.
‫Using the Json web token, our backend is going to be able to validate incoming Http requests and enforce
‫functionality such as, for example, making sure that only authenticated users can view here the list
‫of courses.
‫So this is a very common functionality that we are going to be implementing in the next few lessons.
‫Let's start by opening here, our root application module in our backend and seeing what services exactly
‫do we want to protect.
‫So we have here two different modules the courses module and the authentication module.
‫The authentication module only contains the authentication controller, which only contains the login
‫method.
‫Now this method we want to make sure that it's available to unauthenticated users because we want them
‫to be able to log in.
‫So for the particular case of the login endpoint, we don't want to add any logic that validates if
‫the Json web token is present or not.
‫On the other hand, for our courses module, we have here a series of services under the form of the
‫courses controller and the lessons controller.
‫For example, the courses controller has here a find all courses method that corresponds to this list
‫of courses that we see here on the screen.
‫And this is a good example of a rest endpoint that we want to be able to secure.
‫So in the particular case of this get endpoint, we want to make sure that only authenticated users
‫can perform this get operation further on in the course.
‫We are going to learn also how to ensure that the data modification operations in this controller,
‫such as, for example, create course can only be done by a certain type of users, administrative users
‫that have the admin role for all these use cases.
‫The first thing that we want to do whenever a request gets to our backend is to check if it contains
‫a valid Json web token or not.
‫So we are going to be doing that using a Nestjs middleware.
‫A middleware is a function that can be executed before our rest endpoint code gets executed.
‫So the middleware is going to get executed from the moment that the request hits the back end.
‫And before calling here the controller logic, this middleware function is going to have access to the
‫request and response objects and it will be able to change both of these objects before the controller
‫code gets executed.
‫So middlewares are applied in a chain one after the other.
‫So if you have multiple middlewares in your application, the order is going to be important in our
‫particular case to protect here the all courses endpoint.
‫We want to write a middleware that retrieves the user information from the request.
‫So let's see how we are going to do that.
‫We are going to go here to our root folder and from here we are going to create here a new folder called
‫Middleware.
‫We are going to be creating here a new file called Get User Middleware.
‫So this middleware is going to decode the Json web token attached to the request and it's going to save
‫the user information from the Json web token into the request object so that it can be used further
‫on in our application.
‫For example, to allow or deny access to a given endpoint, let's then implement our middleware.
‫This is going to be a plain TypeScript class, let's call it get user middleware and let's go ahead
‫and annotate it with the injectable decorator from Nestjs.
‫In order to make this a nestjs middleware, we need to implement the Nest middleware interface.
‫This interface needs to implement one method called use.
‫So use is going to receive here the request object and this is the express request object we are going
‫to receive here also the response express object.
‫And we also have here a function called Next that we need to call in order to allow the request to be
‫processed by further middlewares up the middleware chain or by the rest endpoint itself.
‫If this is the last middleware in our chain, it's here in the.
‫Worthy of the use method that we are going to decode our Json web token and we are going to retrieve
‫the user information and store it in the request object.
‫We are going to do that in the next lesson.
‫Right now in this lesson, we are going to see how to plug this middleware into our backend.
‫To configure these middleware, we need to go to our application root module, the app module, and
‫we need to have the application module class implement the Nest module interface.
‫This interface is going to have one method, which is going to be the configure method.
‫The configure method takes here as an input argument, a middleware consumer that we are going to see
‫how to use in a moment and returns one of two types either a middleware, consumer or void.
‫Let's have it return void in our example.
‫So here inside the configure method is where we are going to configure our middleware chain.
‫We want to make sure that the get user middleware only gets applied to certain endpoints of our application.
‫Let's say that, for example, we want to make sure that the get user middleware is only applied to
‫the controllers in the courses module.
‫Then in that case we can define the following configuration consumer dot apply and here we are going
‫to specify what middleware do we want to apply.
‫In this case it's going to be the get user middleware.
‫And now we need to specify to which controllers do we want to apply these middleware to.
‫So we are going to use here the method for routes and we are going to pass it here.
‫An array of controllers, let's say for example, that we want to use here, the courses controller
‫and also the lessons controller.
‫With this configuration in place, we are sure that this middleware is only going to get applied to
‫the endpoints defined in these two controllers and nowhere else in our application and more specifically
‫our authentication module.
‫For example, with this configuration, we are sure that our authentication controller containing our
‫login endpoint is not going to have the get user middleware applied to it.
‫This is only going to be targeting these two controllers specifically now that we have plugged our get
‫user middleware in our application, it's now time to implement the use method.