‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to implement our get user middleware.
‫So this middleware is going to decode our Json web token.
‫It's going to validate its signature and it's going to retrieve from it the user profile information
‫and attach it to the ongoing Http request object.
‫So in order to parse our Json web token, we are going to be needing the Json web token library that
‫we have imported here and we are also going to be using here our Json web token secret.
‫Now with these imports in place, we can now go ahead and grab the authentication Json web token from
‫the request object.
‫So the request object has here a headers property and we want to access the authorization header.
‫If you remember, this is the header that our front end is using to send the Json web token back to
‫the back end.
‫Let's go ahead and assign this Json web token to a variable we are going to call it of JWT token.
‫So now we have here a plain string containing our Json web token.
‫Let's then go ahead and check if the Json web token is present or not.
‫So if the Json web token is not present, then this means that this is an unauthenticated Http request.
‫Now the question here is should we go ahead and deny access to the targeted endpoint here immediately
‫at the level of the get user middleware?
‫Or should we allow this request to go through?
‫Now?
‫The responsibility of the get user middleware class is only to fetch the user profile from the request
‫if it's present.
‫If that information is not present, we consider that this is an unauthenticated Http request and we
‫are going to allow the request to go through this middleware later on during the processing of the request.
‫We are then going to decide if the request should be allowed to reach the code endpoint or not.
‫Right now we want to make sure that if there is no authentication Json web token, we are going to allow
‫the request to go through.
‫Let's then call next here, which means that the request is allowed to go through either to the endpoint
‫or to the next middleware in the middleware chain and let's return from this method.
‫So if the authentication Json web token is not filled in, this middleware is essentially going to be
‫bypassed.
‫And this point here of our code is never going to be reached.
‫On the other hand, if the authentication Json web token is present, then this means that this is an
‫authenticated request.
‫So we want to try to get the user information from the Json web token.
‫Let's then decode the Json web token.
‫We are going to use the JWT library that we have imported.
‫We are going to call here the method verify and we're going to pass it the token that we want to verify.
‫So the verify method is going to check if the signature of the Json web token is valid.
‫And for that we need to pass it the signing secret that we have imported here from another file.
‫So the output of the verify method in case that the verification is successful and the signature is
‫valid, the output is going to be the payload of the Json web token, which in the case of our authentication
‫Json web token, it's going to be the user profile containing the user email and the user roles.
‫For example, the user can be a student, an admin.
‫ET cetera.
‫So now we have here the user profile information so we can then now store it in the request object.
‫Let's check if the user information is present.
‫So if we have here some user information, we are going to add here some logging so that we can see
‫on the server console what is going on.
‫We are going to say that we found the user details in the Json web token and we are going to log here
‫the details.
‫And now we are simply going to attach the user profile to the request object we are going to use here
‫the square brackets notation.
‫We are going to be filling in the user property and we are going to assign it here, the payload of
‫the Json web token.
‫Now this is what happens if the decoding of the Json web token went through successfully.
‫If by some reason an error occurs, then we are going to catch it here.
‫Let's add here an error variable and let's add here some logging so that we can see in the console what
‫went wrong.
‫Now, with this code in place, we are sure that independently of the fact if the verification went
‫through correctly or not, our middleware is not going to crash and we are not going to end up with
‫a hanging Http request.
‫So after this code here, we are going to be calling the next function so that we allow our request
‫to go through in the middleware chain or to reach the end.
‫Point that it was targeting.
‫And with this we have completed the implementation of our middleware.
‫Let's now switch here to a larger window, perform a login and see the middleware in action.
‫We are going to go here to the login page and we're going to perform here a user login.
‫Let's keep an eye here on the network tab.
‫So we have hit login.
‫We got back here a response from the login endpoint with a new authentication Json web token that we
‫have sent back to the client in this new slash API slash courses rest call.
‫We can see here the Json web token in the authorization header.
‫Now switching back here to our ID, let's open here the server terminal and let's confirm that indeed
‫we have here the logging in our get user middleware saying that we found the user details in the Json
‫web token.
‫We have found that the user that performed this Http request has this particular email and that it has
‫the role of a student.
‫So this is the logging statement that we can see here in the implementation of our get user middleware.
‫As you can see, the Json web token was decoded correctly.
‫So now that we have decoded the token and we have attached this information to the request, we can
‫now use it to perform decisions in our backend.
‫We can, for example, allow or deny access to a given endpoint depending on the presence of a user
‫profile in order to allow or deny access to an endpoint, we are going to be introducing a new Nestjs
‫concept.
‫We are going to be talking about Nestjs guards.