‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to take an existing Nestjs rest endpoint and we are going to secure
‫it by making it only available to authenticated users.
‫We are going to take this particular rest endpoint, which is part of the courses controller.
‫The find all courses endpoint, which is an Http get endpoint.
‫So this is the endpoint that gets triggered whenever we load here.
‫The all courses screen In the previous lesson we have added to our back end a get user middleware that
‫is going to extract the user profile from the Json web token attached to the request if the user is
‫authenticated.
‫So now all that we need to do is to add the logic to our back end that denies access to this endpoint
‫in case that the user profile is not present.
‫We are not going to add this logic directly here in the get user middleware because there could be different
‫types of back end endpoints in our application that might need the user information while still being
‫publicly accessible by unauthenticated users.
‫So we want to separate the functionality of allowing or denying access to an endpoint from the functionality
‫of extracting the user profile from the Http request in order to allow or deny access to a rest endpoint,
‫we are going to be introducing a new Nestjs concept.
‫We are going to use the notion of a guard.
‫So a guard is a service that has only one responsibility, which is to allow or deny access to a particular
‫endpoint.
‫So guards in our system are going to get executed.
‫After all, the middleware chain has completed and before the code of the endpoint gets executed, let's
‫then write our first guard, which is going to be the authentication guard.
‫And because this is generic functionality that might be used in any module of our application, we are
‫going to add our guards here directly on the root folder of our backend.
‫Let's create a new directory called Guards and let's create here a new file called Authentication Guards.
‫Let's now define our guard service, which as usual is going to be a plain TypeScript class annotated
‫with the injectable decorator from Nestjs.
‫A guard needs to implement the Can activate interface.
‫Let's go ahead and import this interface and make sure that you import the correct can activate interface
‫from Nestjs common and not from the angular router.
‫So again, this is a similar concept to what we have in the angular front end, but this time around
‫we are reusing it in our back end.
‫The can activate guard only has one method which is called can activate.
‫It's going to receive here as an input parameter and execution context and we are going to be returning
‫here several types of values.
‫We can return a promise, we can return a Boolean, we can return an observable.
‫In our case, we are simply going to be returning a boolean value.
‫That is going to be true if the endpoint can be reached by a given Http request.
‫If the access to the endpoint is denied, then we need to return here the value false.
‫Now this guard is not going to be applied to all the endpoints in our application.
‫We are going to learn further on how to selectively apply it to only certain endpoints that we want
‫to protect.
‫Let's then implement our authentication logic.
‫We are going to start by retrieving here the host from the execution context.
‫And from here we are going to grab a reference to the ongoing Http request.
‫Now, with the request, we can go ahead and see if we have a user profile attached to the request or
‫not.
‫We are going to define here a constant named user and we are going to access the request object.
‫And from there we are going to grab the user property.
‫Now, if there is no user property defined, then this means that this is an anonymous Http request
‫with no authentication information attached to it.
‫We cannot know from which user this request is coming from now because the authentication guard should
‫only grant access if the user is correctly authenticated, then in this case we are going to prevent
‫access to the protected endpoint by throwing here a new unauthorized exception.
‫Let's also add here some logging so that we can see in the console what is going on.
‫Notice that here in the authentication guard we are not again validating the JWT checking the signature.
‫ET cetera.
‫That was already done here in our implementation of the get user middleware.
‫So the middleware is going to run before the authentication guard.
‫So if we got here and there is a user property.
‫Present, then we are sure that this is a valid user profile coming from a correctly signed JWT token
‫that could only have been granted to the user if the user provided the correct password to our login
‫endpoint.
‫At this point in the program, after this if condition, we know that the user is correctly authenticated
‫and that it can access the protected endpoints.
‫So let's go ahead and add here some logging saying that the user is authenticated and we are going to
‫allow access and to allow the access we need to return here.
‫The value true now that we have our authentication guard in place, we just have to apply it here to
‫our endpoint.
‫So one way of doing it is to use the use guard's decorator from Nestjs and to it we can pass several
‫guards.
‫Let's go ahead and pass here the constructor function of our authentication guard.
‫If we use the decorator here at the level of the method, then this guard is going to get applied specifically
‫only to this endpoint If we want instead to apply this guard to the whole controller, then we can apply
‫it here at the level of the class instead.
‫Let's now have a look at this guard in action.
‫So we're going to switch here to a larger window and we are going to log out our user.
‫So this is going to remove the Json web token from local storage and we will now have to log in again.
‫Now, before logging in, let's go ahead and confirm that our endpoint is protected and only accessible
‫to authenticated users.
‫So we are going to click here on the courses screen and let's keep an eye here on the network log.
‫We can see that a loading indicator is still spinning, so that's a good sign.
‫It means that something went wrong.
‫We can see here that the slash API slash course is get request got back a 401.
‫Unauthorized as expected.
‫So as we can see, the access to this endpoint is denied to an unauthenticated user.
‫Now let's confirm that this is still visible for logged in users.
‫We are going to go to the login screen and we are going to click here on login.
‫So as we can see after the login, we got back a new Json web token that got attached to this request
‫sent to the backend.
‫And this time around our request went through and we have here the list of courses.
‫So as you can see, our authentication guard is working correctly as expected.
‫Next we are going to learn how to take this a step further.
‫Besides handling authentication, let's also handle authorization.
‫We want to make sure that certain endpoints are only accessible to users with certain roles.