‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to take the security of our backend one step further.
‫Besides handling authentication, we are also going to take care of authorization.
‫So authentication is about identifying a user and making sure that a request belongs to a given user.
‫Authorization, on the other hand, is about ensuring that the user has the right security privileges
‫to perform the operation that it's trying to perform.
‫So attached here to the Json web token, we also have the user roles.
‫This could be the student role for accessing the data in our application in a read only way, But the
‫user could also have, for example, the admin role, which means that the user is an administrator,
‫which has the ability of editing the data.
‫In order to implement these authorization features, we are going to be building an authorization guard.
‫So the guard will allow access to the endpoint if the user has the right set of roles and it's going
‫to deny access.
‫Otherwise let's then open here our guards folder and let's create a new file that we are going to call
‫authorization dot guards.
‫Let's now start the implementation of our authorization guard.
‫As usual, this is going to be an injectable nestjs service.
‫Let's have this class implement the can, activate Nestjs interface.
‫Let's now override the can activate method and let's have this return a boolean value.
‫Just like in the case of the authentication guard, we are going to start here at the beginning of the
‫can activate method by retrieving a reference here to the request object.
‫Next, we are going to be retrieving here a reference to the user profile which is currently attached
‫to the request under the user property.
‫So this user property was filled in by the get user middleware in case that the user is logged in to
‫the system.
‫Now, with the user profile, if we access the property user dot roles, we are going to get access
‫to all the roles associated to this user, such as a student admin.
‫ET cetera.
‫In order to determine if the user has access to the endpoint, we need to then compare the user roles
‫with the allowed roles that are authorized to get access to the endpoint.
‫So we need somehow to configure this authorization guard class with a list of allowed roles for which
‫access to the endpoint is allowed.
‫Let's then pass in here in the constructor of the authorization guard, a property that we are simply
‫going to call allowed roles.
‫This is going to be an array of strings, so each string being a role that is authorized to access the
‫endpoint protected by this instance of the authorization guard, we are going to have multiple instances
‫of an authorization guard, each one with its different set of allowed roles.
‫Now, in order to determine if the user can access the endpoint, we just need to compare the user roles
‫with the authorized roles.
‫And in order to do that, we are going to be creating here a new function that we are going to call
‫is allowed.
‫This function is going to take here as input a list of user roles, which is going to be an array of
‫strings.
‫Now this method needs to return true if the access is granted and false if the access is denied so that
‫we understand better what is going on, we are going to be adding here some logging to the console.
‫We are going to list here the allowed roles first and the user roles next.
‫Let's assume to start our implementation that the user is not allowed to access the endpoint.
‫So this is a safe default We are going to be defining here a Boolean flag allow that we are going to
‫initialize to false and we need to return this as the output of this method.
‫Now we are going to compare the allowed roles with user roles and see if the user should be allowed
‫access to the endpoint.
‫Let's start by looping through the list of roles we're going to call here.
‫User roles for each and each of the elements of this array is going to be a user role.
‫Now let's quickly add here some logging so that we can see what is the user role being checked for access.
‫Now let's add here an if condition.
‫We are going to see if the allowed roles that were passed in here to the constructor of the Guard include
‫this particular user role.
‫So if that is the case, then the user should be allowed to access the endpoint.
‫So let's set allowed to true.
‫Now, at this point, we would like to break here.
‫This loop now for each is going to continue to loop through the user roles, even though we might have
‫already determined that the access is allowed.
‫So we are only going to do this check here if the access has not yet been allowed.
‫And with this we will have the allowed flags set to true if at.
‫Least one of the user roles is listed here as being an allowed role for the authorization guard.
‫Let's then now use the Is allowed method.
‫We are going to create here a new constant that we're going to call allowed and we are going to assign
‫it.
‫The output value of calling is allowed.
‫Let's pass here the user roles that we can retrieve from the user profile.
‫Let's now add here some logging so that we can see if the user was allowed or not.
‫And let's now implement our authorization logic.
‫So if the user is not allowed, then we are going to add here some logging so that we can see that the
‫user was denied the access in the log and we are going to throw a new forbidden exception.
‫So this will give us a different status code.
‫We are going to get in the client, the status code 403 forbidden.
‫So this means that the user is authenticated.
‫But despite the fact that it's authenticated, it still does not have access to the endpoint because
‫it does not have the proper authorization role.
‫On the other hand, if the user was allowed to access the endpoint, then we're going to add here some
‫logging and we are going to return the value true, meaning that the endpoint code can then be executed
‫for this request.
‫And with this we have completed the implementation of our authorization guard.
‫So we are now going to plug it into our backend and apply it only to certain endpoints.