‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to apply our authorization guard only to certain endpoints of our
‫application.
‫Let's say that, for example, we would like to apply this guard only to the data modification endpoints
‫of this controller.
‫Well, for that we could try to pass in here just like we did with the authentication guard, the constructor
‫for the authorization guard.
‫However, this would not work because our constructor needs one argument containing the list of allowed
‫roles.
‫So a simple way of solving this is to create a subclass of this authorization guard.
‫Let's call it the admin guard because it's meant to guard endpoints only accessible by admin users.
‫We are going to call this new file admin dot guards.
‫Let's then implement our guard.
‫We are going to define here the TypeScript class.
‫We are going to make this a nestjs service and we are going to have this extend the authorization guard.
‫Now here in the constructor of our admin guard, we are going to be calling here the super constructor
‫of authorization guard and we are going to be passing here an array of allowed roles.
‫So in this case the admin guard is guarding routes that are only supposed to be accessed by administrators
‫with the admin role.
‫And with this we have defined here a guard that we can now apply here, for example, to our courses
‫controller.
‫Let's say that, for example, we would like the create course to be protected by this guard.
‫Let's then apply here the decorator, use guards and let's apply it, the admin guard.
‫We are now going to apply this same guard to the other data modification operations of our controller.
‫We are going to apply this to update course and also to delete course.
‫So to summarize, all the endpoints of this controller are being protected by the authentication guard,
‫but only certain endpoints are protected by the admin guard.
‫Let's now have a look at this new version of our backend in action.
‫So we are going to log in using the student role and we are going to be redirected here to the courses
‫page where we can see that we can still access here the list of courses.
‫So this endpoint is still reachable by us.
‫But let's, for example, scroll down here in our course list and let's try to delete one of the courses.
‫So this is a data modification operation protected by the admin guard.
‫So we would expect this to fail and that is indeed the case.
‫We have here a 403 forbidden in our network log.
‫If we go back here to our application and we open the terminal, we are going to open here the backend
‫terminal and we can see that even though we managed to retrieve the student role from the user profile,
‫whenever we were comparing the roles, we got the conclusion that the user should not be authorized
‫to access this endpoint, which is correct.
‫Now let's switch back to our application and let's log out after log out.
‫Our user profile is going to be deleted and now we are going to log in.
‫But this time around with the admin user, let's switch here.
‫The username and the password remains the same and it's the word password for simplicity.
‫So it's the value that is filled in by default in this password field.
‫Let's click here on login.
‫So we are now logged in with the admin user that also exists in our MongoDB database.
‫But this time around, if we try to do a data modification operation of one of these courses, let's
‫say that for example, we would like to change the name of this course to simply rxjs course.
‫Let's click Save.
‫This is going to reload here our list of courses.
‫And as we can see, the data was correctly updated in the database.
‫And if we now click here on delete, this is going to trigger the deletion of this course that no longer
‫shows here in our refreshed list.
‫And with this we have finished the implementation of our backend and we have also reached the end of
‫our course.
‫So congratulations for finishing the Nestjs in practice course.
‫Let's now run the some key conclusions and takeaways.