‫Hello everyone.
‫Welcome and congratulations on completing the Nestjs in practice course.
‫In this lesson we are going to highlight some of the key takeaways of this course.
‫First, let's summarize what Nestjs is.
‫So Nestjs is a node based backend development framework with an object oriented API, which is decorator
‫based and that is very similar to other popular backend development solutions with the difference that
‫many of the concepts in Nestjs are also the same concepts used for building our angular front end.
‫So if we work in a project that uses an angular front end, Nestjs is a very natural fit for building
‫our backend as well.
‫With Nestjs, we can very easily split up our backend into controllers and repositories, which is a
‫very common design pattern.
‫So controllers are responsible for parsing the incoming Http requests and extracting everything that
‫we need from the Http request in order to process the request.
‫Controllers are also responsible for data business validation and for building the Http response.
‫On the other hand, repositories are separate services that encapsulate only the database access logic,
‫meaning both queries and data modification operations.
‫So these operations can typically be reused across multiple related controllers With Nestjs, we can
‫also do decorator based data validation, which is also a very popular pattern in other backend development
‫frameworks.
‫So with decorator based validation, we can define via the use of decorators certain business constraints
‫for our data, such as, for example, a given string field must have the format of a phone number.
‫Now the best place in our program to apply these business validation is, is just when the request arrives
‫at the backend and before triggering the controller logic.
‫So before triggering any logic, we are going to perform all our validations and we're going to send
‫back to the client in case of an error the list of fields that need to modify.
‫And what was the problem in each of the fields with an error.
‫So this is going to allow us in our client to display the necessary error information to the user for
‫it to correct the request and send it again back to the server.
‫This approach of validating our data upfront using controllers also has the benefit that it simplifies
‫the code in our controllers.
‫For example, we can avoid certain conditions like checking for null or undefined values.
‫All of those checks have already been done upfront by the data validation solution for the database
‫layer of our solution.
‫We have used MongoDB, which is a NoSQL schema less database like the name says, this type of database
‫does not have the built in notion of a schema, unlike SQL databases, for example.
‫So how do we ensure the data integrity of what we store in the database?
‫Well, in our case, we have opted by defining a schema at the level of our backend and not at the level
‫of our database.
‫So our schema was defined using Mongoose, which is an ODM library or an object to document mapping
‫library.
‫With Mongoose, we can create objects in memory in our backend server that are directly linked to database
‫documents.
‫We can create these new object, we can edit its properties, we can link it to other documents.
‫And in the end, by calling Save, we are going to have everything persisted transparently to the database
‫by following the schema rules.
‫So if some of the properties do not respect the schema that we have defined in our backend, we are
‫going to get an error in.
‫We can also do custom error handling.
‫We can define more generic catch all mechanisms that handle all sorts of errors by default, but we
‫can also define next to those more specific error handling mechanisms that target only certain types
‫of errors, such as, for example, data validation errors for securing our backend.
‫We have used the solution based on Json web tokens.
‫So a Json web token is a small Json payload, which is cryptographically signed, and it's usually used
‫to prove that the bearer of a given token is a well identified user.
‫So whenever our backend receives a request, it will find a Json web token attached to it.
‫By using a Nestjs middleware, we can then validate the signature of the Json web token and retrieve
‫its payload.
‫So if the signature is correct, then we know that that request comes from.
‫That user and that user Only when we have extracted the user profile from the Json web token, we can
‫then attach it to the Http request and make the user profile information available to the rest controller
‫endpoint layer.
‫Now, whenever we want to protect an endpoint from unauthenticated use, we can use a nestjs guard.
‫The guard can check for the presence or absence of the user profile in the request and decide if it
‫should grant or deny access to the endpoint.
‫In a very similar way, we can also implement authorization for our backend.
‫So together with the user ID information, we also have available the list of authorization roles that
‫the user has assigned in the Json web token.
‫A user can be, for example, a student user, an admin user.
‫ET cetera.
‫So each different type of user has a different set of roles.
‫Those roles are present in the Json web token.
‫So if we want to grant or deny access to certain functionality in our backend according to different
‫roles, we can do so also by using a nestjs guard.
‫In summary, in this course we have covered everything that you need to know in practice in order to
‫use Nestjs effectively in a real production application so you now know how to build a complete Crud
‫example using nestjs and you know how to add authentication and authorization to your backend.
‫So I hope that you have enjoyed the course.
‫Let me know in the comment section below if you have any questions about the course or suggestions for
‫future courses.
‫I want to thank you for watching and I will see you next time.