In the lesson protecting
our routes with a guard.
After we validated the
incoming access token.
We decided to Ottawa's
sign the Dakota payload
and put it in the requests
user property
but.
How can we grabbed this object
from within are protected routes.
How can we determine
who the identity of the
current a p i request is.
Let's grab this request object
in learn how we can
get the user information
and utilize it
and her coat.
But switch over to our ID
and open up the
coffee's controller file.
Or example sake let's say would like to
retrieve the object representing the active
user aka a currently
logged in user.
Inside of the find
all get 'em point.
For demonstration purposes let's add
a new method argument called request.
An annotated with
the wreck decorator.
Next within the method body
was at a simple console log
and log out request dot user.
Let's save our changes
and head over to insomnia.
Let's call the coffee's get route again
just so we can trigger this console log.
Now if we switch back to our ID.
And open up our terminal.
As we can see
our decoded payload got
logged in the console here.
Now even though this works this
approach seems to be far from ideal right.
First off taking the
entire request object
as an input argument
of our method.
Makes it harder to test as the request
interface is generally quite broad.
Another problem.
That it requires an
understanding of the access token
guard implementation which
assigns the Dakota payload.
The request user keep.
In some people might
not be aware of this
especially newcomers.
People who joined the
project at a later stage.
We simplify this
whole situation.
Let's create a new
puram decorator
who handle a few things for us.
Inside of the i am folder
let's create a new directory
and call it decorators.
Inside this new folder
let's add a new file
and name it.
Active dash user
dot decorator dot ts.
I the file.
Must declare a new
active user decorator
but the help of create
puram decorator utility
exported from nastiest comment.
If you're unfamiliar with the
create puram decorator function.
Recommend looking at the bonus
create custom puram decorators lesson
from our fundamentals course.
Next up let's pass the
following function to
the create puram
decorator as an argument.
The code can be found
below the course video.
Now let's break everything
down to see what we're
doing here to get a better
understanding of everything.
In the first line here.
Are grabbing the request object from
the execution context using switch to http
and calling the
get request method.
Next
from that request object were
selecting the decoded user payload
and assigning it
to the user variable.
Lastly
if a field parameter was
passed into the decorator
and we want to grab that corresponding
field property from the user object.
Otherwise we return
the entire user object.
Okay so the code here is
straightforward enough so so far
but will end up saving us a
lot of boilerplate code and time
in the future.
So let's save our changes.
At back to the coffee's controller
and instead of using the wreck object.
Let's now make sure to use our new
active user decorator that we just created.
But everything in place
let's save our changes
i'd ever do insomnia
and click send again.
Once we receive the
response back if we switch
back to our ID and open
up our terminals again.
We'll see we'll get logged into the
console and as we can see again.
Are accustomed decorator works
as intended and we no
longer have to inject the
entire request object
into her handler great.
As we mentioned earlier.
Now that we're not using the request
itself this will help keep tests simpler
is will be easy to mock
out our new decorator.
Back to our code.
There is one last thing
we could improve here.
So far
we haven't declared what the
actual shape of our jwt payload is.
Which and our case represents
the decoded user data.
That a make
things strongly type.
Let's create a new file
inside of the i am
slash interfaces folder
and name it.
Active dash user dashed data.
Not interface that to yes.
Inside this file let's start by adding
the active user data interface.
Inside this interface
let's declare to properties.
Tub
and email.
In our case stub
represents the user ID
that granted this token.
While email
is just an extra user
specific prop forty
we provided in the authentication
service when generating the token.
Pwt beauty payload
contains a few other
properties which we've seen
when we logged the
user object in the console.
For example e x p.
Which is the exploration
timestamp of the token
or a u d
which is the audience we passed
then when generating the token.
As these are irrelevant to
the user and this interface we
won't be adding them to the
active user data interface you.
All right with
everything here in place.
Let's save our changes
and make use of this
newly defined interface.
First up.
Let's switch back to the active
user decorator would just created.
Here we could start by strongly
typing the field perimeter.
Using the key of active
user data expression.
And next we can also specify
the type for the user variable
as follows.
Perfect.
Now
let's navigate to the
coffee's controller
and use the active user
data interface there as well.
Which can be found
in the user perimeter.
Of our find all method.
And lastly.
Let's open up the
authentication service
and make sure that the payload we pass to
the jw tea service when signing the token.
Fulfills the active
user data interface.
Rate
now we are fully type-safe
and we've simplified
how we can access
current user data and our
points.
All of which will come in
handy in future lessons.