Now that we have our sign in and
sign up and points implemented.
We can move on to protecting other existing
and points for example the crud user and
points regenerated
in previous lessons.
Which of this.
Will create a guard
that will check for the
presence of a valid Judah
beauty as a bearer token.
Any protected row
handler with this guard.
Will only be invoked if the user
has been successfully validate it.
All right so let's head over to our
terminals in generate a new guard via
nest g guard.
And let's plays it within i am.
Authentication
and put it with and a new guards
folder calling it access dashed token.
Let's open of this
newly generated file
and start by adding the
required dependencies.
First
lesson check the jwt beauty
service into our constructor
that we're going to use to
decode and coming jwt tokens.
For this will also need the
jwt configuration again so
that we can pass the secret
key down to the decode method.
Perfect.
Before we can
validate an incoming
jwt token
we first have to extract
it from the request object.
Depending on what your strategy is and
whether you're sending access tokens as part
of the authorization
header as we are now.
Or you decided to use the
http only cookies approach
that we presented in
the previous lesson.
The implementation here
will vary just a little bit.
In this lesson
will assume that the token will be included
in the authorization header which is
generally a very common
widely used pattern.
Though let's start by
declaring a new method.
And name it extracts
token from header.
This method.
Will accept one parameter which is
the platform specific request object
in our case express js request.
Make sure to import at the request
interface from the express package.
Next.
Inside of this method.
Let's grab the token from
the authorization header.
The reason why use split here
is that the bearer token
should have the bear
prefix which we can
ignore at this moment.
We want the token part
that comes or right after it.
All right with this method
in place let's grab the
reference to the request
object in our can activate method
using the execution context.
Note for graft your
applications you'd have to use
the rapper graft your
execution context here instead.
Next up let's extract
the token from their quest
object using the method
we just declared in our class.
And in the case the
token is not present.
Let's throw the
unauthorized exception air.
In case the token is available.
Let's use the jwt service
verify async method
to verify and decode it.
In order to use a
weight in our method.
We also need to align
the method signature.
It as a sink
and update the return type
as it can't contain bullion an
observable bullying and him.
Since verify async
may throw some
custom errors like
Jada beauty expired
that are not auto recognized
by the nest js framework.
We must wrap it
in the try catch blocks and re
throw an unauthorized exception.
Note to improve debugging
experience here we could log
the original message down
just for development purposes
or converted to a user friendly
message and pass it as an argument to the
unauthorized
exception constructor.
Perfect.
And lastly.
Let's assign the decoded
payload to the request user property
which has a very common
practice in the know js community.
This way we can access the user
objects later on in our and points
or other subsequent guards.
However
doing this here without
defining the user key as
a constant can lead to
some unexpected behavior.
Let's go ahead
and create the i am
duck constance file.
In the i am folder.
And inside of it export request
underscore user underscore key constant.
Making an equal
to the string of user.
Now back to our guard
let's use it inside.
Let's also temporarily at a console log
just a verify Howard decoded object looks.
All right let's save our
changes and before we
bind this guard to any
routes in our system.
Let's head over to insomnia
to grab a valid access token.
Let's call the sign in
and point again and make
sure to copy the access
token to our clipboard.
Next let's switch
back to our ID.
Open up the i am module
and register access
token guard globally
using a dedicated app
underscore guard token.
Note that we could have
binded access token guard to
individual routes that
sort of doing this globally
using the use guards decorator.
But since it's rather a tedious process we
decided to auto protect all and points we
have in our
application by default.
This is also eight
recommended best practice.
As it mitigates the risk
of some one forgetting
to annotate a newly added
and point with discard.
Now instead every new one point
will automatically become protected.
Since there are certain
routes from which we want to
intentionally skip the
authentication requirement.
We will implement a new decorator that lets
us exclude those routes in the next lesson.
Back to our task at hand.
Let's say of all our
changes switch back to
insomnia and try to
hit the coffee's endpoint
the one that was auto generated by
the resource schematic a few lessons ago
mr see what happens.
As we can see
we received the four
o one error saying that
were unauthorized
to access this resource
rape.
Now let's click
on the headers tab
and add the authorization
header so we can
send the access token
as part of our request.
For our key let's call it
authorization with a capital a
and for the value
let's paste are access token
prefixed with the bearer
string we copied a moment ago.
The click send.
Should now see that
everything works great.
We received the
this action returns all
coffee string which is
exactly what our coffees
controller route returns.
Our guard
was able to verify and
decode our jwt access token
and allowed us access
into the application excellent.
Let's switch back to
our ID he real quick
just to verify what was locked at
the console for our user payload.
And there we have it.
Already decoded user payload that will be
passed down with our Jada beauty tokens.
As we mentioned earlier.
This could be
used in other routes
other guards.
Or anywhere in application where we
might need this user specific information.