Jason web tokens
or gw teas.
Are an open standard used to share
security information between two parties
a client
and a server.
Each Jada beauty
contains encoded jaison
objects including a set of claims.
Data beauties are signed
using a cryptographic algorithm
to ensure that claims cannot be
altered after the token has been issued.
Be a ts can be
signed using a secret.
With the age Mac algorithm.
Or a public private key pair
using our essay or a c d s a.
If you're new to jiddah beauties don't worry
of all this seems a bit confusing right
now we'll be diving into
everything here in much more detail.
In their compact form Jason web tokens
consist of three parts separated by dots.
Which are the header
payload.
In signature.
Therefore a jwt typically
looks like the following.
Let's break down the different parts
so everything makes a little more sense.
The header.
Typically consists of two parts.
The type of the token
which is jwt.
In the signing algorithm
being used such as h Mac
sh a to fifty six
or our essay.
The second part of
the token is the payload
which contains the claim mps.
Claims are statements about
an entity typically the user
and any additional data and
application wanted to pass down with it.
To create the third
party signature part.
You have to take
the encoded header.
The encoded payload
a secret and the algorithm specified
in the header and digitally sign all of it.
In authentication
when the user successfully
logs in using their credentials.
A jaison web token
will be returned.
Right now our application
just returns a boolean.
Whenever the user wants to
access a protected row or a resource.
The user agent
should send their jwt.
Typically in the authorization
header using the bear schema.
The content of the header should
look something like the following.
Authorization Colin
bear and then the token.
If you're curious to learn even
more about Jada beauties in general.
Make sure to check out the
website Jada beauty dot io.
Now that we understand the high
level and specifics of Jada beauties.
Let's switch back to our ID
and see how we can start implementing
them into our own application.
Before we start.
Let's install two additional
dependencies first
that will be using
and our project.
Is our nestorius slashed jbt
and nestorius slash config.
Nest has slashed jwt is a wrapper
around the jaison web token package
which exposes methods
for encoding and decoding.
A beauties.
And nastiest config which was already
introduced in the fundamentals course.
Will continue ahead here since we already
have these packages installed but if you're
following along just pause the video
and come back when everything's finished.
Once the installation
process is complete.
Let's open up our app module t s
file and head over to the imports array.
Let's import the config module
from the nastiest
slush config package
and add it into our
imports array here.
Next let's initialize the module
by calling the for route method.
But this and place
we can now create
a local dot mv file
where we store our private
environment variables.
This is where will store
a secret that will be
used for encoding and
decoding are jwt tokens.
Know that it's very
important to never keep
or push secret keys
up to your repository.
The nestle i already has
dot envy files included.
In a good ignore file to
ensure that this never happens.
Though
let's create our dot dmv file
in the root directory.
An inside of it.
As add the following variables which
you can also find below the course video.
Jwt secret represents
our secret key.
It should be hard
to guess and long
and usually the
longer the better.
V w t token audience identifies the recipients
at the jwt is intended to be used for.
Next we have jwt token issuer.
Which identifies the principle
that issued the j w duty.
And lastly.
Ada beauty access token t t l
which is the access
token time to live a k t t l.
And we have the set to thirty
six hundred seconds meaning.
Every issued token will
automatically expire after one hour.
You can of course a justice setting to
whatever you think is best for your project
but we suggest keep a low
meaning to a short time to live.
Note that environment variables we
sat here are essential to our applications
starting up and
running properly.
Since our application
depends on them.
We need to make sure we have
all the required variables we need
so we can connect to
the correct databases etc.
It is a best practice to throw an
exception during application startup
if any required
environment variables
have not been provided.
Or if they don't meet
certain validation rules.
Will learn more or if you
need a refresher about
environment variable
validation and nes Jess
check out the schema validation
lesson from the fundamentals course.
All right so let's make
sure to save this file
and create a new directory
inside of our i am folder
called config.
Inside this folder.
Let's create a g w t
dot config dot t s file.
With this violent place.
We can register a new configuration
namespace under the Jada beauty token.
We've already covered config namespaces
features in the fundamentals course so check
it out if you need a
refresher but essentially.
Were just scoping
or name spacing.
All of these configurations
under the Jada beauty namespace.
Next up let's open
up the i am module.
And add the jwt module
to the imports array.
Making sure to imported
from ness Jess slashed jwt.
Let's now called the
register a sink method on it.
And as an input argument.
We can pass in the jwt config.
Not as provider method
where jbt config is our
namespace configuration factory.
You haven't seen
as provider before.
This method converts a factory to match
the expected a sink modules configuration
object with imports
use factory etc.
It's essentially
just a time-saver.
In prevents us from entering in
unnecessary boilerplate code here.
Let's not forget to also
import the config module
and register the jwt
config factory so it can
be injected by the
authentication service.
Right we have no error so far.
Now with the Jada beauty
stuff configured and loaded
we can navigate to our
authentication service file
and filled the gap we've
left in our sign in method.
Let's start by
injecting the jwt service
making sure to imported
from the nes js
slashed jwt package.
We have the ability to inject
this service as we imported the
beauty module into
our i am module.
Now let's inject that jwt
configuration we created.
Using the inject decorator.
Giving us the ability to easily grab those
Jada beauty configuration key values here
within or
authentication service.
With this and place.
Let's scroll down to the sign
in method implementation
and replace that to do comment
we left with the following code.
Here we're calling
the sign a sink method
of the jwt service to generate
a new jwt access token.
We're passing in the payload
object as the first argument.
And the Jada
beauty configuration
as the second one.
Which instructs the jwt service
what the expiration time.
Is your audience etc is.
We'll worry about the payload
object and decoding it later on
when we create an authentication
guard in future lessons.
Back to our code here
you may have noticed in the first argument
that we chose the property name of sub
to hold our user ID value.
It's a good practice to do this to
remain consistent with jwt standards.
We also decide added to include the user's
email address here in the signs token
but this is totally optional.
We can pass down whatever
we'd like in Djibouti tokens
but it's a best practice to keep
them very lightweight and small
and only include things
that are absolutely essential.
Or the second argument
we passed the jbt
configuration object
passing down the
audience issuer etc
from our namespace configuration
and we set the expires and property
equal to our access token teeth yell.
Next.
Let's update the return statement
so that instead of returning true.
It sends an object containing
the access token property.
Great
with this and place.
Let's make sure to
save our changes.
At back to insomnia and test
our site and endpoint again
making sure we pass in valid
credentials in the request body.
And as we can see on our screen.
We received the
access token back
great.
Are sign an
point is now fully functional.
Note.
There are safer alternatives than
sending the access token as a pure text
for example by using the http
only and secure cookies option.
Let's switch back
to our ID eero quick
that we can showcase
this safer approach as well.
Let's open up the
authentication controller
and let's focus on
the sign in method.
Here.
As at a new parameter
named response
and annotated with
the rest decorator.
Setting the pass
through property to true.
Then
let's replace the body
of this method with the
following code that we can
find below the course video.
Let's also make sure
to flag our method
as a sink.
Great so let's save our changes.
Had ever do insomnia again
and call the sign-in
and point once more.
As we can see.
The response bodies now empty
and that's what we actually expected.
But let's open
up the cookies tab
and as we can see.
There's our access
token in here perfect.
Just to make things easier
to understand in this course
will be continuing on with the
first approach which was so.
As tokens inside
of the request body
but we just wanted to make sure you're
aware of any potential risks they're.
In provide you with and
even safer cookie approach
if that's something your
application required.
So.
Let's make sure to
switch back to our ID
and revert these changes we
made in our authentication controller.
Save everything
and we'll be ready
to continue forward
in the rest of this course.