One benefit of gw beauties or Jason
web tokens is that they are stateless.
That means we don't have
to query a central database
to validate the token on
each incoming request.
As long as the token
signature is valid
and the token has
an expired itself.
We can authenticate the request in
associated with the corresponding user.
This poses a challenge though.
Let's say we want to invalidate a leaked or
compromised refresh token to prevent the
attacker from logging
into our system.
Or let's say the admin has
updated the users roller permissions.
They should be
automatically logged out.
In case a user's roles were
embedded into the token themselves.
The how can we accomplish
and fix any of these issues.
Well
since our current tokens are
stateless we cannot revoked them
as they're not stored in the database unless
we remove the principal or target user
but usually
that's not what we want to do.
But what about if we store
tokens in the database.
With this approach we
could check which tokens
are valid in which ones
have to be revoked.
Based on whether there
are still in the database or not
but.
This makes Jada
beauties stateful
and behave similarly
to credentials.
Essentially
in order to make that idea work.
We would have to keep a list of all
issued tokens in a dedicated table
or in the existing users table.
Then the guard we implemented would have
to query the database on every incoming
request just a check of
the given token is included
in the list of stored tokens.
I think you could imagine
that this would have a
negative impact on our
applications performance.
Who as you can see.
This approach is not ideal.
In this lesson.
Will showcase something we
consider a nice middle ground solution.
First will implement
a mechanism.
Old a refresh token rotation.
Whenever he refresh token was
used to issue a new pair of tokens.
Will invalidate the original one
or old refresh token so it cannot
be used again in the future.
To do all of this
you're going to add a
red is database to our
stack but feel free to use
any database you want.
You could even leverage
our existing postgres database
and just added dedicated
table if you'd prefer.
We decided to use read
us because it's a lightweight.
E-value storage system that
provides great performance
and it's all we need to
accomplish the task at hand here.
But let's head over to our ID
and open up our docker compose file
and let's add a reddish service in there.
Next up
let's install the io read his package
which has a robust read his client.
Was open up our terminals
and type in and p m i.
I yo read us.
Let's also make sure to
start our newly added read his
service with the docker dash
compose up dash d command.
Next up.
Let's generate a refresh token ids
storage class using the following command.
Nest g class
i am slash authentication
slash refresh dash
token dash ideas dot
storage but this in place
let's now navigate to the
i am module and register
refresh token ids storage
as a provide wider.
Now onto the refresh
tokens ID storage class itself.
First.
Let's annotated with the
injectable decorator as always.
Next up.
Let's implement
to interfaces
that led us hook into our nest
applications a life cycle events
these are an
application bootstrap.
And an application shut down.
Our ID he will hint to us to
implement these interfaces
let's go ahead and do it.
Inside of the an
application bootstrap hook.
Let's add the following code you
can find below the course video.
As you could see
in the comment here
ideally we should have registered a
separate rattus module that encapsulates the
his client
and ties itself to the
applications life cycle.
However
as in this course who want to primarily
focus on authentication and authorization.
We decided to take a
shortcut here as we don't want
to spend too much time on
things we've already covered
in the fundamentals course.
Don't worry this
approach is still okay
we just wanted to
remind you that in an ideal
world we'd would want
to separate the south.
Okay so next
let's move on to the an
application shut down method.
In here.
Let's add just one line.
Read his client
dot quit.
In this method
when our application
shuts down the reddest
connection will be
terminated which is ideal.
As we want to make sure we
always clean up our resources.
Rate.
With our read
his client in place.
Let's add for methods in this class
now to set up our business logic.
Insert.
Which will use to insert
new entries into the red
database.
Validate
which will validate the token ID passed
in and depending on the validation we
implement will
return true or false.
Invalidate which will
help us invalidate the
token by removing the
ID entry from our database.
And lastly
the private method
get key
which constructs the entry
ID based on the user identifier.
Let's start by first implementing
the get key method.
Inside the get key method
let's simply return
the stringify to user ID
with the user dash prefix.
This will be helpful so
our key entries in our read
estate of base have a
nice uniform look and feel.
Next
inside the insert method
let's add the following logic.
This code were using
the reddest client to insert
be at the set method.
A new token ID entry into our
database under a specified key.
Now
onto the validate method.
Here we retrieved the Stuart ID from
the database and compare it to the second
argument passed
into this method.
Which might be either different
or undefined.
Basically
we're ensuring that a token
ID this method received
matches what we have
stored in our database.
And lastly.
Invalidate.
Which will solve one of our problems
we mentioned at the start of this lesson.
In this code.
Were using the Dell
method of our read his client
to delete a specific
entry from our database.
This way if someone tried to use
the refresh token that was once valid.
Our validate method
will return false since the
user ID doesn't exist in
our database anymore.
And there we have it.
Our refresh token ids
storage class is all set.
We now have all the
logic and place that we
talked about in the
beginning this lesson.
Okay so we'll all of that done.
Let's open up or authentication service
and eject our new storage class they're
using the standard approach.
Now.
Let's scroll to the generate tokens
method and make use of our provider there.
First.
Before we sign our token.
Let's generate a
unique refresh token ID
using the random
you you ID generator.
From the native cryptography
library named crypto.
Now that we have this
in place let's pass this ID
as an extra payloads property
of this signed refresh token.
Ideally
we should add an interface here describing
the refresh token payload structure
but since we have so many
important things to build here.
We're going to admit it for now
but feel free to
make one for yourself.
As in general this
is a best practice.
Now
once our tokens are signed.
Let's make sure we insert
this ID into our read estate
of base using the refresh
token ids storage provider.
Calling the insert method we
created a few moments ago.
And that's it.
Our generate tokens
method as all set.
Now if we scroll down to
the refresh tokens method.
Let's make a few important
additions here as well.
Let's first start by
updating our type argument.
Next up.
Was grabbed the
refresh token ID property.
After we fetch the
user entity in our code
let's validate the
refresh token ID.
Passing it to the refresh token
ids storage validate method.
Alongside user ID.
Now if it is valid
we have to invalidate it so it cannot
be used for any subsequent requests.
This technique is called
refresh token rotation.
If it is invalid.
We want to make sure we
throat the corresponding air
indicating that the refresh
token is no longer valid.
Let's save our
changes had ever do.
Here and see if everything
we've done so far works.
Let's start by hitting the sign in
endpoint to retrieve a fresh set of tokens.
Let's copy that
generated refresh token
and try to regenerate tokens passing
the refresh token to the authenticate
slash refresh dash
tokens and point
as we have done previously.
Let's click send
and as we can see
it worked.
We received a new set of tokens.
Now let's click send again
and this is when we'll see the new
mechanism we just put together do its job.
And voila.
Refresh token we just
used a moment ago
has been invalidated and can
no longer be used after its first use.
So as we can see.
This new ability gives
us an additional layer of
security and took minimal
effort for us to put together.
Let's continue forward
and dive into a new topic called
automatic reuse detection.
Automatic reuse detection
is a key component
of any solid refresh
token rotation strategy.
In fact.
We already have this detection
functionality implemented in our code
at the moment though
we'd just don't react
differently in any case where
the old refreshed hogan
was attempted to be reused.
So let's switch over
to our ID he once again
and open up the refresh
token ids storage class.
Inside the valid method.
If distort ID is undefined
that means the refresh token
has already been invalidated.
So let's kick things off by first declaring
a new dedicated except ocean class.
Let's grow up in above our
class let's add another tiny class.
Note that ideally we should put
this new class in a dedicated file
but once again since best practices
like this were already covered in the
fundamentals course will
focus on the task at hand
and just continue ahead
with the two classes in one file
but go ahead
and put it in its own.
Want to keep things clean.
Back to our code.
Let's scroll back to
our validate method
and in the case where stored
ID does not match the token ID.
Let's throw the
exception we justified.
Great.
Now.
Let's switch to the authentication service
and in our refresh tokens catch clause
let's add a new
condition here as well.
And that's it.
At this point with the
code we've just added.
Our system is now aware when and
invalidated refresh token is being used.
Now he will be up to you in your systems
needs on whether this is a moment to either
log such information somewhere
let's say for security purposes.
Or maybe even notify the user
that their log in may have
been potentially compromised.
We have you gone
to our next topic.
As we've mentioned at
the beginning of this lesson.
Storing all tokens
including access tokens
in the database has
some serious implications
and so we typically
recommend not to do this
unless you're one hundred per
cent aware of what you're doing.
If your application requires
stateful authenticate then.
Perhaps instead of jw tease
you should consider implementing
a more stateful mechanism
like for example sessions.
Still with what we did so far it's feasible
to almost ensure up to date data in our
gw teased by making
access tokens very short lived.
For example.
If you set the access
token lifetime to five minutes
and on the you i side of your
application be at mobile web etc.
You implement a background process that
periodically refreshes the access token.
An attacker or
just a regular user
only has a maximum five
minute window of opportunity
to invalidate a so
called user session.
You could simply invalidate
it's corresponding refresh tokens
and so the user would be automatically
logged out in a Max of five minutes.
As his current access
token would auto expire.
So as we can see there are
many different approaches
and strategies to
handling token invalidation
so make sure to think about
whatever is best for your application
and how high of a level
of security you really need.