In this lesson
will be implementing routes that are essential
to our authentication workflows being
sign-in.
Which will authenticated
user by verifying
their credentials such
as username password.
Or an identity token
from an identity provider.
In manage authenticated
state by issuing a portable token.
Much as a dj w t.
In lastly sign up.
That will let users
register into our system.
All right so let's switch to our ID
and start setting everything up.
Let's start off by generating
a new authentication
controller in our existing i
am module using the nest
see ally.
With nest g controller i
am slash authentication.
Note we're generating this controller in
the new dedicated authentication folder.
Just so we can have a clear
separation between the authentication
and authorization related files.
It will be working
on in future lessons.
We will also need an authentication
service so let's generate that as well.
The at nest g service i
am slash authentication.
Great.
Before we start adding methods
to our authentication service
in implementing the sign in
and sign up functionalities.
Us generate
the dt o or data transfer
object classes for to
endpoints points we plan
on exposing in our application.
Being.
Signed in detail
in sign up detail.
Next we're going to
install to packages that
will be using to validate
any incoming requests.
You may remember these from the fundamental
course as there are an essential part of
almost every nest
js appliques Haitian.
Let's enter in
and p m i class dash
validator and secondly class
bash transformer.
We'll be continuing ahead
as we already have these
installed but if you're
planning on following along
just pause the video and come
back when everything's finished.
Now with everything installed.
Let's open up our main ts
file and add the following line.
Up dot use global pipes and
let's pass in new validation pipe.
Making sure to imported from
j a slash common.
With our validation pipe in
place we can move on to our
to your classes now.
Let's start with the sign up and point that
will let users register into the system.
Register a new user
will need credentials
let's add email and password
properties into our sign up detail class.
Next let's apply some
validation annotations.
Like his email for
the email property.
Which will validate if the
specified email is in fact
an email.
And for the password property
let's add men length ten
as we don't want to accept passwords
that are less than ten characters long.
All right with our
validations and place we
could now switched to
our authentication service.
In order to create new users.
This service will need
to use the user repository.
Bullets injected into our constructor
using the inject repository decorator.
Know that before we
insert a new user row
we have to make sure to have
hashed the passwords we receipt.
Which Eve this
lets inject the hashing service
we created in the previous lesson.
With these dependencies injected we can now
declare a new sign up method in our class.
This method will
take the sign up.
O instance as an input argument.
In sight of this method.
We can start by creating a
new user entity instance like so.
Since we flagged the
email column as unique.
As crests may throw the
unique violation constraint or
just in case there's another
user already registered
in our users table.
Let's make sure to wrap
this code into a try catch block
to handle this exact scenario.
Note.
As a best practice ideally
we should have declared the pg unique
violation Erica constant in a dedicated file.
It can be reused
elsewhere in our code base
but just to keep things
in this lesson simple
will leave it as
it is for right now.
With sign up wrapped up.
Let's move on to the
sign-in side of things.
First let's open up the sign in detail
class and add some missing properties.
The sign in a user will
have to provide us with
an email address and
they're valid password.
Let's also apply the
same set of validation
constraints we did in
our sign up detail class.
With our class last updated.
Let's switch back to the
authentication service again
and define a another
method right below the sign up
and name it sign in
or log in if you prefer.
This method will take
just one argument.
Sign in d t o
which is our credentials
object containing the email
and password that the user
will send over the network.
In the side of this method.
As add the following code
and bring it down the line by line.
Earth
we have to check to see if a user with the
given email address exists in our system.
Afterwards
we can use the hashing service
to check if the provided password
matches the hash diversion
we stored in our database.
If any of these two
to operations fail
we throw an
unauthorized exception
otherwise we return true
as they have been
properly authenticated.
Note that in the next lesson
will be improving this
even further by returning a
jwt access token instead
of returning a boolean value.
Okay so what the corresponding
service methods in place.
Let's switch over to the authentication
controller class and inject our service there
but the standard dependency
injection approach.
Inside our controller.
Let's define to methods.
One
for the sign up route.
And another for
this sign en route.
The sign and route will
have one subtle difference.
In this method
we want to use the http
code annotation to instruct the
nest framework betting case
of a successful operation.
We want the http
status to be two hundred
instead of two hundred and one.
Which is the default
for post routes and nest.
The lastly.
Let's open up her i am module
and first create
and imports array inside
of the module decorator.
In this imports array.
Let's add type or ramped
up for feature passing
an array with our
user entity inside of it.
And just like that.
We made the user
repository available
to our authentication service.
Now that we have this and place
we can switch to insomnia
and test out these 'em points.
First.
Let's try to sign in
using invalid credentials
which right now will
always be the case
as we haven't
created and users yet.
As we can see we received
the four o one response that says
unauthorized which is
exactly what we should expect.
Now let's call the sign up and point
passing in the exact same user body.
And create a user
in our database.
As we can see
we received the to a one
status code back which means of
the user was successfully
created in our database great.
Just to make sure our conflict detection
mechanism works as we intended.
Let's call the say poi again passing
in this same set of credentials.
Excellent it works
we received the conflict error message
back as we know this helps prevent us from
having duplicate
users in our database.
One last thing.
Let's switch back
to the sign in route
and call it passing credentials
of the user we just created.
And as we can see
it works now.
Since the user is now
within our database
and were passing in
the correct password.
We're now able to
sign in successfully.
Let's try calling this a p i again but
this time with an incorrect password.
Excellent.
We received the
for one unauthorized
just as we should.
Although they response skimmers
of our end points are not ideal yet.
We have the
authenticate shim part
working well so far
but were far from done
will keep on improving
everything more and more
in the upcoming lessons.