Authorization.
Which is often confused or combined with
the concept of authentication which we've
been discussing
so far in this course.
Is the process of
giving a user permission
to access a specific
resource or function.
For example
an administrative user
is allowed to create
edit
and delete coffees.
Whereas as a non administrative
user is only authorized
to view coffees.
Authorization as orthogonal meaning
that it is independent from authentication.
However as we have already
mentioned in previous lessons.
Authorization does require
an authentication mechanism
which luckily we've
implemented already.
Role-based access control
or rb a a c as a policy
neutral access control
mechanism defined
around roles and privileges.
When using role-based access control you
examined the needs of your users and group
them into specified roles
based on shared responsibilities.
For example.
Let's say we have a
coffees catalog application.
Users with the admiral
can manage costs please
add edit or remove
them from the catalog.
On the other hand.
Regular users can only
navigate through the
list of coffees and
view individual coffers.
We might even have a
supervisor or super admin role
that in addition to
managing coffees
can even create
edit and remove existing users
including those with the role admin.
They might even have
the ability to promote
a user from being a
regular one to an advert.
Essentially.
A role is a collection of permissions
that you can apply to users as.
Using roles makes
it easier to add delete
and customize permissions
as opposed to assigning
permissions to every user individually.
In this lesson.
We will define a role enum
that will represent all of the
role supported in our project.
And our case we're just
going to make these static
values that aren't coming
from a database or anything
but in certain situations.
We would want these roles stored
in a database and even better.
Maybe we'd want
to have a dashboard.
Where we could create new roles
and assign them to existing users.
If you wish
you could generate a new roles
resource using the nastiest July.
Implement the karate and
points declare a role entity.
Establish a relationship between
the user and the role entity etc.
But since all of that is outside of
the scope of this specific extension.
Will proceed uh-huh head with a
predefined and static list of roles.
So back to our code.
Let's switch to r ID and start
by adding a new directory
and side of the users
folder and call it ninos.
Inside this folder.
Let's create a new ina
named role da enough that t s.
In this file
let's declare the following
static enough that will use.
This ina consists of two values.
Regular
which represents a regular user
and admin.
Which indicate someone who
is capable of managing coffees.
As we have mentioned earlier
depending on what application you're about
to build you could add more and different
roles to this as we
mentioned earlier baby
you'd even want to
have been in a database.
Next up let's open up our
user entity class and at a new
role column there.
Great.
There's one caveat here though.
Our existing user doesn't have
the role assigned as it was created
before we introduced this com.
Let's update all of our
users using the new nests
rebel feature.
Rebel.
Is a simple interactive environment
that takes single user inputs.
Executes them
and returns of result back.
The rebel future
lets you inspect your dependency graph
and call methods on your providers and
controllers directly
from your terminal.
Note that we're using the
rep of feature here mainly
for ease of use as we're
learning new concepts
in dealing with our services
and database in this course
but you wouldn't want to use
this in any production setting
or anything like that.
It's just a fantastic option
during development time.
Or general application introspection
to see how everything's working.
All right so let's create a new rebel t
s file alongside of our existing main t s
file and entering
the following code.
We will be diving into
exactly was happening
here as it's outside of
the scope of this course
but there's a link below
the video with more
information about
rebel if you're interested.
Now in our terminals let's start
the rebel with the following command
and p m run start.
Dash dash dash dash entry file
and in the word rebel.
Once it's initialized.
Let's use the users repository
to update our user entity
calling the update method.
Grabbing the user by ID one.
And setting the role
to the string of regular.
Perfect.
Now let's retrieve all
the users just a double
check that the role
was properly updated.
Right and as we
can see it worked.
We have only updated one user here because
it's all we had in our database but you
made his do this with other
users if you have more in yours.
Of course in the real
world who wouldn't use the
rebel to make these kinds
of updates of migrations.
Back to our task at hand.
We now need to implement a decorator
that would lead us indicate what roles are
required to access
specific and points.
Though inside the i am folder.
Let's start of by
creating a new directory
called authorization.
Where will keep everything related
to our upcoming off authorization work.
Inside this new folder let's create a
directory named decorators and create a new
roles dot decorator
got t s file there.
Following what we've already did with
the ot decorator and previous lessons.
Will once again use
the set meditate or helper
a will grab roles that are
passed into the decorator.
Rate
with this and place
we can now generate a new guard
slots open up our terminals and
in a separate terminal window.
Use the necessary
osceola to created.
Nest g guard i am slash
authorization splash guards slash roles.
Let's open up this file
and let's first inject the reflector class
we've seen in previous lessons as well.
Now onto the can activate
method of our guard.
Let's serpa retrieving
the required roles for
the target endpoint using
the reflector provider.
Making sure to look
both in the handler.
If the decorators used
methods and at the class level
if used on an entire
controller resolver class etc.
In the case there
are no rules required
we assume that this handler
doesn't require any additional
validation and we let to
request proceed right away.
Otherwise
me to grab the act of user
data from the request object
that we assigned in
the access token guard
and check if it has one
of the required roles.
Rate.
One issue though.
As you can see the role property is
now highlighted and we're getting an error
stating that property role does
not exist on type active user data.
Let's go ahead and
fix this real quick.
First let's navigate to the
active user data interface.
And add the missing
role property here.
Next.
We need to open up
the authentication service
scroll up to the
generate tokens method.
And make sure that we
are passing the user dot role
alongside the
email for the payload
of every sign access token.
Perfect.
All right with our guard all set
we should be able
to register at globally
similarly to what we did
with the authentication guard.
Was open up i am module
and provide the app guard.
Utilizing the use class syntax
and we can pass in
our roles guard here.
Rate with our guard
register globally now.
The only thing
that's left for us to do
is to entity methods that require specific
roles with our new roles decorator.
Will stretto and open
up our coffees controller.
Unless annotate create
update
and delete operations.
With the roles decorator
setting their required
role all to roll dot admin.
Which will set our application so that
only admins can access these and points.
With these roles
decorators applied.
Let's save our changes
head over to insomnia and
test out our create slash
coffees post endpoint.
And as we can see.
We received the four o three
forbidden resource air back
just as we should expect.
From now on.
Users that don't have the admin
role assigned won't be able to create
edit
or delete coffees perfect.
Now let's switch back to our ID.
Open up our terminals
switch back to the rebel
window and execute the
same up the inquiry
with one subtle difference.
Instead of using
regular as the role
let's now set it to admin.
As we can see.
There was one entity
affected which means our
user should have the
admin role now great.
Let's head back over to insomnia once again
to test if we can access that endpoint
now that we're an admin.
First.
We have to re authenticate
ourselves as the users
role is embedded in the
Jada beauty access token.
Let's go ahead at
and sign in again.
Once we receive the response.
Let's copy the newly
generated access token
and update the authorization header
in our post slash coffees endpoint tab
and click send again.
And voila
r a p i returned back successful
with a to a one created
this action adds a new coffee.
As we can see.
Now that we are admins
our guard is working just
as intended and owning
allowing us access if
we are an authorized role.
We covered a lot in this lesson
but as you can
see we've let out out
all the foundations for
authorization itself in from here.
There are many additional ways or directions
we can go in terms of authorization.
Just depends on what we need
and are given applications.