In a be a key
is a unique identifier used
to connect to or perform and
a p i call.
Apia keys
can be used to either
access your application
without any principal identity.
Or to create secondary
credentials so that you
could send requests on
behalf of a specific user.
In the first approach as.
A PR keys will be useful for
accessing public data anonymously.
It'll be used to associate
a PR requests with your project.
In the latter approach
Apia keys will represent
secondary credentials of users
that have this same or lower access
rights depending on the defined scope.
These two variance it's
are not supposed to
be used interchangeably.
Whether you should use the
former ord the latter approach
greatly depends on what
your application needs.
Or example
if you're building a sas product where
customers can create their own projects and
you would like to
expose a mechanism.
That lets users interact
with those projects
on behalf of a third
party tool anonymously.
And you should likely
choose the first variant
were Apia keys can be
used without any principal
and are simply tied
to specific projects.
However
if you're building a
social network application
or let's say something
similar to get hub
it may be beneficial to let
users create their own a PR keys
which will allow them
to build custom maps that
interact with your applications a p i
but without using your
front and application.
Essentially
a user could generate in a
key that can be used
from a third party tool.
Which will allow them to
access user specific information.
Or perform actions
on behalf of that user.
Such an ape yankee could have a specific
set of scopes in the user could control what
exactly can be accessed
through that specific Apia key.
If you've worked
with get up stripe
or other st case
that offer a pie keys.
This all should sound familiar
but if not don't worry
we'll be diving into
everything in much more detail
and it should all
make sense soon.
In these next few lessons were
choosing to implement the second variant
as we already have
the user entity in place
but just so you're aware.
Implementing the first approach should be
almost identical to what we're about to do
so don't worry if
you're interested in
implementing or learning
about that first approach.