In this course will be
building a simple coffee
application that
consists of two resources.
Users
and coffees.
As we've already
mentioned in the first lesson
will assume that you're
familiar with everything
we've covered in the
fundamentals course.
All right so let's start by building or
application and head over to our terminals.
And create a fresh
nest application.
By entering in the
nest new command.
The
the ally is going to
prompt us as always
asking what name we want
to use for this new project.
Let's call it off
dash extension.
Once everything finishes.
Let's cd or change directory
into our newly created
application by entering
cd off dash extension.
Next let's generate to resources
coffees and users.
Help speed up this repetitive
process the necessary
or seal i provides us with
a generator or schematic.
That automatically generates
all of the boilerplate code.
Help us avoid doing
all this manually and to
make the developer
experience that much simpler.
Was use it by running.
Nest g resource
and let's call it coffees.
This command will
prompt us asking what
transport layer we want
to use at our project.
Will choose arrest a p i.
As for the next question
would you like to generate
crud entry points let's
say yes and have some
endpoints of generated for us.
Which we will protect
later on in this course.
As you can see on the screen
the resource schematic generated
a module to keep code
organized and establish
clear boundaries grouping
related components.
A controller with
nest g controller
to define crud routes
a service with nest g service
to implement an
isolate business logic
and entity class to represent
the resource data shape
and lastly
data transfer objects
or inputs for graft you'll applications
to define how the data will be sent
over the network.
Now let's generate the users
resource using the same commands.
Via nest g resource
and let's call it users.
With our to resources
in place let's start up or
application to make
sure everything's working.
Let's fire up the app and development
mode with n p m run start Colin deaf.
Great
everything works so far.
In our terminal we can
see that both users module
an coffees module were
successfully initialized.
We can even see some
endpoints registered in our project.
Great.
What's open up the users service file real
quick and see what we have in their so far.
As we can see the seal i generated service
classes are not tied to any specific r m.
Or data source.
This makes the generator generic
enough to meet the needs of any project.
By default
all methods will contain placeholders
as we can see on the screen.
Allowing us to populate the service with
the data sources specific to our project.
In this extension
similarly to what we did in the
fundamentals course will be connecting our
application to a
postgres database.
With the help of
the tibor m library.
Remember.
In your project you can use
any data source you wish.
Any r m you prefer.
Be at mongoose next
micro or m et cetera.
You could even use
database drivers directly
and run plane sql queries
anything or applications new.
We are specifically using
type or am here in this course
but just know that you
are not limited to using
type r m in your future
applications by any means.
Since we don't want to
spend too much time explaining
all the configuration
related pieces again.
If you're unfamiliar with
everything or just need a refresher
please check out
lesson number three.
Add post-grad
sequel with type or him
from our fundamentals course
to learn more about docker
type are a module and so on.
Back to our code.
Let's get some of the same set about of the
way in our application here and start by
creating a docker dash
compose dot yaml file
in the projects root directory.
Inside this docker compose file
let's define a database container
in gamble format.
You can find the code to copy
paste here below the course video.
Now.
Let's bring our container up
using docker compose.
In our terminal.
Make sure we're at
the project root directory
and let's enter in docker
dash cam pose up.
Dash d.
Note.
Make sure to have docker itself up and
running in the background before running us.
Rate.
We now have a postgres
database running in the background.
Now for the nes
js type r m portion.
Let's get the necessary dependencies
installed for her application.
Which are at ness
js slashed i ballroom.
Type bahram
and pg.
Posts gross.
Remember.
Type or m can integrate
with many other databases.
Will be using post-crash
as it's powerful efficient
and free.
Once the installation
process is complete meet.
Let's open up our
app module t s file
and head over to
the imports array.
In here let's import the type
or a module from the nest
js tibor and package and
add it into our imports array.
Necklace initialized this module
by calling the for route method which lets
us configured the connection to type r m
as well as a few additional
tools available to integrate it
with ness jas.
Let's enter in the following configure
aeration options that we set up in our docker
compose file and
we should be all set.
Remember you can find the code to copy
paste for this arrival of course video.
With docker and type
r and portion all set up.
Let's open up our user energy file that was
already generated by the resource schematic
and add a new
entity decorator on top.
Making sure to
imported from type rm.
Next up was at a few columns
for ID email and password.
And now that we have the
basics of our entity set up.
Let's registered this user
entity in our application.
To achieve this let's
open up our users module
and first create an input array
inside of the model decorator.
In this imports re let's add type r
m four feature passing in an array
with our users
energy inside of it.
And just like that
we created our first database entity
and table within our postgres database.
Now.
That we have all this and place
we could start using a real
database in our application.