In this lesson.
We're going to implement
a new feature putting
users sign up and
sign into our application
using their Google accounts
instead of using
regular credentials
like email and password.
For most applications
and for those who want to
provide for the needs of their users.
Is very important to offer
one click authentication options
like Google asked
make it easier to
register and log into apps.
And this lesson
will be setting everything
up in our nest application.
Also make sure to
check out the two previous
tax base lessons as they are companions
to everything we will be doing here.
One lesson
is about instructions
on how to set up a new
Google project via
the gcp dashboard.
And the other lesson.
Is on how to test our
Google authentication blow.
After all
we will need a you are to do
so so make sure to check out
the lesson on creating a
Google off the front and demo.
Where you can set up a
very basic react application
in order for us
to test everything.
But note
that this could be
done with anything.
Any front and the
framework of your choice
a mobile application
etc.
So back to our task at hand.
Let's switch to r i
he
ain't start by updating
our dot e and the file.
Inside the dmv file.
Let's declare to new
environment variables
Google client ID
and Google client secret.
You can get these ideas
from your gcp dashboard
if you've set all
that up already.
If not make sure to go
through both of those text-based
lessons first before
continuing further along
in this lesson.
The next la is open a bar terminals and
first less install a new dependency that will
need to use to
verify Google tokens
the Google off library package.
Once the installation
process is complete.
Loss generate a new service
and put it inside of i
am authentication social
and call it Google
authentication service.
Let's also create its corresponding
controller in this same location.
Okay great.
Let's open a bar newly generated
Google authentication service
and declared the our
client private property.
Of type
o off to client
imported from the Google
off library we just install.
Now let's inject three dependencies
into our services constructor.
Config service.
Authentication service
in our user repository.
Also let's implement the on module in the
interface as we're going to want to do a
few things when the module
initializes in or applications life cycle.
Inside the on
module in it method.
Is initialized the our client.
By calling new
a both to client.
Passing in both our client ID
and plight secret.
Both which we can
get from r e n b file.
Grape.
Next.
What's the fine and
authenticate method.
Which will do all
the heavy lifting here.
This method takes one parameter
which is the access
token issued by Google.
Using the oh author client.
Must retrieve the user
specific information
as follows.
Now before we move further
let's really quickly
navigate to the user energy
class and make to
additions there as well.
First we'll need a new
column called Google ID
that will contain values
only if a user's account
has linked to the
corresponding Google account.
Also
let's make sure we update
the password column
and make it nullable as users
who use Google for signing in
won't have passwords
in the standard sense.
All right back to our Google
authentication service.
Us retrieve the user entity
based on a user's Google ID.
If it doesn't exist yet.
Will create a new
account on our system.
Otherwise
we'll sign the user in
and respond with the access
and refresh token pairs.
Lastly.
Let's wrap everything
up in a try catch block.
If there was a conflict.
Let's make sure to
throw a conflict exception.
Otherwise
we can throw
unauthorized exception.
You may have noticed that
we're using a unique error
code here since we're using
post crests as our database
for this exact
conflict logic here
might look different if you're
using a different database
in your future applications.
Are a great so
moving on let's
save our changes.
In create an actual
endpoint for everything by
opening up our Google
authentic cation controller.
Let's start by updating
the controller prefix here
to be authentication slash Google
so it's consistent with other routes.
Next.
Let's inject
Google authentication service
using the standard approach.
Now inside of our class.
Sickler a single authenticate
route that cause the
corresponding Google
authentication service method.
We don't have a Google
token detail class to find yet.
Let's go ahead.
Navigate to r d
to your directory
and create a new
Google dash token
dot dt or file in there.
Inside this file.
Let's add a simple
class with one property
represents the Google token.
With this and place
let's switch back to
our controller class and
make sure to add the
missing details class import.
And lastly
just to make this route public
let's make sure we
annotate the entire controller
with the auth
decorator passing in.
Off type none.
One last thing
before we continue.
Since our you i is hosted
on port port thousand.
And r a p eyes on
port three thousand.
We have to enable course or
cross origin resource sharing.
Easy fix though.
It's open up our main t s file
and add the following line.
Aap dot enable course yeah
and that's it.
With everything set up
now let's start our react
application if you set it up already
just so we can
test the overall flow.
If we open our browser
support for thousand
once our react app
is built and running
we should see our
Google sign in button.
Let's go ahead and click on
sign in and as your account.
And it should open up a pop up or a sep
but tab in the full window mode letting you
choose the account
you want to log in with.
And after a successful login
you should see the access an refresh
token logged out to your chrome consul
and there we have it.
In just a few steps we managed
to integrate our nest application
with Google authentication
one of the most popular one
click off providers out there
in today's world.