In the real world production applications
should never store passwords in clear text.
Instead.
Passwords should
always be hashed
salted.
Hashing is defined as putting a
password through a hashing algorithm.
Be it be crypt se j et cetera.
Return plain text into an unintelligible
series of numbers and letters.
In contrast to encryption.
Ashing is a one way mechanism.
Once hashing has been done
it should be impossible to
go from the output to the input.
Salting is the act of adding a series of
random characters to a password before
growing through
the hashing function.
Thus the input is made
up of the password.
Plus the saw salt.
Note that the salt should
be unique for each password.
As resulting helps
developers increase password
complexity without
affecting user experience.
Adding salt makes
it very difficult for
hackers to guess the original
password using a rainbow table attack.
In this extension
will be using the be crypt algorithm
the it is based on the blowfish cipher.
It is designed to be slow
and not to allow any shortcut
and slowing down any attack.
All right so let's get started and get a
dependency installed before you begin.
As head over to our ID and inside of
our terminal lessons thought the be crypt
package and it's
type definitions.
We have these packages
already installed so we'll skip ahead
but if you're following
along go ahead and pause
the video until everything
finishes installing.
Once it's done.
Before we dive into all the
good stuff let's first wrap up
all of our upcoming
work into a new module.
Let's generate a new nest module
and call it i am.
Ct for identity and
act zest management.
He had nest g module
i a m.
Inside of this module.
Us generate to services.
One that will act
as an interface.
Let's call it hashing service.
And another one
representing its implementation.
Be crypt service.
Will generate both services and side of the
i am slashed hashing directory as follows.
Let's open up the
newly generated hashing
service file first and
make a few adjustments.
Let's start by making this
class abstract as we wanted
to act as an interface or
hashing service abstraction.
Next let's define
to abstract methods
that will have to be provided
by the concrete implementations.
Hash.
Makes data as an input argument
and returns a high hashed string
while compare
also takes two arguments.
Data.
Being the data to be encrypted
and encrypted.
Being the data to
be compared against.
This method will return a promise
to be either resolved or rejected
with an air.
With this and place let's open up
the other service we just created
be crypt service
and make sure it implements
our new hashing service.
Our ID should prompt us to
auto implement this interface
lets go ahead and do it.
Next let's update
the hash method
and make use of the hash function from
the be crypt package we just installed.
First let's of flagged
this method as a sink and
then replace its context
with the fallen and code.
Now onto the compare method.
Similarly here
let's use the corresponding compare
method from the be crypt package as well.
And that's it.
Note that of the code here can
be found below the course video.
Lastly
let's open up the
i am module file
in let's change a
few things in there.
You may have noticed we're
getting some airs at the moment here.
This is because of the hashing
service is an abstract class
and it can't be
registered as a provider.
Is it cannot be instantiated.
Her fixed us up let's replace the
providers array with the following code.
With what we just did here
now whenever the
hashing service token
is resolved it will point
to the be crypt service.
Ashing service will serve
as an abstract interface.
While be
service is are concrete
implementation of that service.
What we've done here is
really useful because if we ever
decided to migrate to a
different hashing algorithm.
We could simply create a new service
that implements the hashing service
and update this provider
to point of the new service
instead of the be
gripped service class.