As we mentioned in
the previous lesson.
In this chapter.
Will implement in
Apia keys feature
that will let us send
requests on behalf of a user.
So
let's start by generating a new entity
class called a p i dash p dot entity.
And please it
within their directory
of users slash a p i dash keys
slash entities.
Just a reminder
that were passing
the no spec flag
that the cla doesn't generate a test
file as we won't need them for entities.
Let's do what we typically do.
An stopped by renaming the class to simply
Apia key removing the entity suffix year
since it's redundant
and we don't want the
word entity in our database.
Next let's start by
adding the entity decorator
on top making sure to
import it from type of ram.
And afterwards let's
add a few columns.
ID.
E.
U you ID.
Lastly.
Let's establish a many to one
relationship with the user entity
using the many to one decorator.
Now that we have the
basics of her energy set up.
A register this Apia key entity
in our application.
To achieve this.
Let's open up our users module
and let's add the a p i key entity to
the type r ram module for feature array.
Let's not forget to update
our user energy as well.
Adding the Apia keys field
there and specifying that
user is the owner side of
this one too many relationship.
Perfect.
With our energies updated.
Let's create a new
Apia keys service in the i
am slash authentication
directory using the.
I see alive.
Once as generated.
Let's open up the newly generated
file and defined for methods.
Create and hash.
Or creating and hashing new a
keys.
Validate
for validating a PR keys.
Extract ID from a
a key for retrieving the Apia
key ID from the encoded Apia key.
And lastly.
Generate Apia key for
generating a p key strengths.
Before we jump
into these methods.
Let's start things off by declaring the
missing generated a PR key payload interface
right above the a
Yankees service class
but ideally.
Move this into its own file
we're just trying to focus
on the task at hand here.
This interface will
consist of two properties.
Ape yankee which represents
a user friendly Apia key
and hashed key
a hashed version of the Apia
key that will store in the database.
With this interface in place.
Let's inject the hashing service
into the Apia keys service constructor.
All right.
Now onto the methods.
Will start with the
January Apia key.
Inside this method.
Let's first generate a
random unique Apia key string.
Using the random you
you ID function from the
native crypto package we
used in previous lessons.
And pretending it
with and Apia key identifier.
Just ID and our case.
Next.
Let's use buffer
and it's to string method.
Generate the corresponding
strength in base sixty four format
just to make sure it looks more
user friendly and consistent.
Without spaces etc
and then let's
return the result.
Next let's move onto the
create and hashmap acid.
Inside.
Let's start by generating in a p
key using the January
Apia q method we justified.
Next using the hashing service.
As generate a hashed
key and await the result.
Lastly.
Let's make sure to return the generated
a p i keep payload object meaning
a p a key and hashed key.
Note.
Instead of using the
be crypt algorithm here
you could consider using
something a bit more performance
as will need to validate
the hash per each request.
You you idea itself is
already pretty long oh so
be crypt might not
necessarily be require here.
Next onto the
validate the method.
And are valid a method.
Will just call their corresponding
hashing surface method
as follows making
sure to return the result.
Now lastly
the extract ID from
a be a key method.
This method takes the encoded a
PR key in based sixty four format
and returns the extracted ID
which we assigned as a prefix
of the random unique string
in our generate Apia key method.
Alright
with everything in place.
It's now generate
a new a p key guard
using the nastiest schematic
to wire everything together.
Was open up our
terminals and run.
Nest g guard.
I am slash authentication slash
guards such a p i dash keep.
Let's now navigate to
this newly generated file
an start off by retrieving
the request object
from the execution
context instance.
Next.
As the finding method
called extract key from header
that you may recognize
as it resembles the
corresponding extracts
token from had method.
We implemented
in our access token guard.
As you can see
in both access token driven
and a PR key driven strategies
we use the authorization header.
So to avoid
unnecessary validations.
If the request header
contains an access token
not a napier key
will add an
additional if condition
that will return the token
variable only if type ipe.
Equals Apia keep.
Is also open up the
access token guard
and make sure to make
the same update their.
One little difference instead of
looking for the Apia key prefix.
We now check against the
presence of the bear string.
Great.
Going back to r Apia key guard.
Let's use this method from within the can
activate method to retrieve the Apia key
and if it's undefined.
Let's throw the
unauthorized exception.
Before we move further.
That's inject the a
r keys service to our
guards constructor some
can use it to validate
incoming Apia keys.
Also.
Lets inject the
Apia keys repository
we can retrieve a p i key
entries from our database table.
With these
dependencies and place.
Let's switch back to our
can activate method again.
Using the extract ID
from a p i key method.
From our Apia keys
service lets extract the a
key identifier from
the encoded string.
Next up let's add
try catch blocks.
Inside the try block
let's retrieved the Apia he
entity from our Apia keys table.
Using the ID we extracted
from me encoded string.
Note that
we instruct the or am
here to auto populate the
related user entity as
part of the same query.
Remember that we are
using type r m in this course
but whatever rm your
application is using.
You'd want to make sure to populate
the user entity and this call as well.
Next.
Let's use the validate method of the a
p r keys service provider to validate the
given a PR key and compare it with
its hash that we store in the database.
And lastly.
Says we want to allow
the use of a PR keys
to authenticate on
behalf of specific users.
Let's make sure we also
assigned the related user entity
to the request object so it can be retrieved
later on in our controller methods.
This will make it easy
for us to access to
user in r code base
winter request comes in.
Perfect
for their guard all set up let's
open up the authentication
guard and inject the newly
created a PR guard there.
Next navigate to
the off type ii numb
and let's add
the a p i t in there.
Back to our
authentication guard.
Let's also update our mapping
the off type guard map object.
And that's it.
So to wrap everything up.
Let's open up our i am module
an change a few things in there.
First up
let's make sure we register a p i e
repository in the context of this module.
By adding a p i e entity
the for features imports
array of tibor a module.
Next.
Let's add the Apia key guard.
The providers around
so it becomes injectable
meaning that it can be injected
into the authentication guard.
Grape.
Are Apia key based
authentication is now also.
Let's save our changes and
navigate to the coffee's controller now.
Here
will apply the off decorator
to the controller class.
Instructing are authentication
guard that both bear
and a p i key driven strategies
are supported by coffees routes.
All right.
To
everything out we need to
create a testable Apia keno.
We don't plan to implement the
entire crowd workflow for Apia keys
as this is something we've
already done thoroughly.
In our fundamentals course
but ideally
it's probably something you'd want to
have and a real-world application so if you
want set it up for
fun and for practice.
So instead the.
As an easier way for
us the test everything
will use nests rebel
feature once again.
Let's open up our terminals and start
the rebel using the following command
and p m run start dash dash.
Dash dash entry file
and rebel.
Inside the rebel session.
Let's first stickler a
unique ID for our a p i keep.
You you ID equals the string of
random underscore unique underscore ID.
Next.
Let's away and retrieved
the Apia keys service
called the create and hash method to
generate the a p i keep payload saving
everything to a
payload variable.
And lastly lessons or a new a
PR key into our database table.
Using the Apia accused repository
and calling these saved method on it.
Making sure to pass down.
You ID.
A key with the value of
our payload dot hashed key
and user making sure to
specify the user in our case
ID one.
And voila.
Let's make sure to copy this
generated a p a key we got back.
Now let's head over to insomnia
and while we're on the
coffee's endpoint page.
Let's switch to the headers tab
and replace the current
authorization header value
to Apia key.
Making sure to add
a space and then let's
paste that generated
Apia a key here.
Now.
Let's click cent.
And look at that.
As we can see.
The request was successful.
R a p i returned a response back to us we
were authenticated to access this endpoint
on behalf of user one.
They're valid in
Apia key fantastic.
A switch back to our ID
and take a look
at our terminals.
As we can see here
our user
a user of ID one
that's associated with
the Apia key was logged
into the console thanks of
the console log we added
in our coffees controller
in a previous lessons.
With everything we've
accomplished in this lesson.
Now our coffees and point
supports both bearer token
and a
key driven authentication flows.
You can see there's a lot of
possibilities for application from here.
We now have the ability to provide this
Apia key the driven authentication flow
to other parts
of our application
if we ever needed it.