A refresh token
is a special token used to
obtain new access tokens.
This allows us to
have short lived access
tokens without forcing
users to manually log in
every time the original
access token expires.
Once the access token expires.
And applications can
use a refresh token.
Who refresh ag a
regenerate or retrieve
the new access token
behind the scenes.
Refresh tokens should be returned alongside
the access and or ID tokens as a part of
a user's initial authentication
and authorization flow.
After that
applications must then
securely store refresh tokens.
You can think of a refresh token
as if it were a users credentials set
as it does let them
re authenticate.
Enough theory.
Let's switch over to r i d e and begin
implementing this refresh token functionality.
First let's open
up our dot e n v file
to declare a new
environment variable
at specifies the lifetime
or time to live
for our refresh tokens.
Let's use eighty six town
than four hundred as the value.
Which represents twenty
four hours or one day
but in milliseconds.
Next
let's move to
the jwt config file
and add a new refresh
token t t l property
following the same naming
convention we did with our access token.
Were passing a fallback
default value here just in
case the environment
variable isn't set but i do really
you should have schema
validation future turned on instead.
The the fundamental
course for more information.
Great.
Let's make sure we save our changes
and navigate to our authentication service.
Make things simpler let's
refactor the token signing logic.
And let's extract extracted
to a separate method.
On the method
sign to token.
We're gonna need a bit
more here to get what we want.
Let's add a few
things to our method.
First let's start
by modifying the
generated method signature
and at three parameters.
User ID of type number
which is our user ID.
Expires in
which represents the
to an expiration time.
This'll be different depending on whether
regenerate and access or refresh token.
And lastly
payload.
Which is an additional set of properties
to be signed an embedded in the token
of type t.
Which will be our type
argument that we can pass down
via a generic.
With our method
signature and place
let's make use of these
do parameters and update
everything in our
method body to use them.
Great
lastly
let's update the method usage in our sign
in method above making sure we're passing
down the generic of
partial active user data
and then passing down
the three parameters to it.
As we can see.
We now have the generic
sign token method available
that we can use to
generate our refresh token.
Now
we need to use the promise dot all
to generate both tokens and parallel
which will save us some time
and give us better performance.
Oh let's first convert this chunk
to use the promise that all format.
And then
let's add the refresh token
generation logic here as well.
Perfect.
Lastly
we just have to add the
refresh token property
to the object returned
from this sign and method
and we should be all set.
Let's make sure to
save our changes
at ever do insomnia
and call the sign in and
point to test everything out.
As we can see.
Alongside our access token we received
the newly added refresh token great
but
how can we use it.
Well
there are two viable approaches.
In the first approach
we could modify the
existing sign in and point to
accept additional
properties in the request body
respectively Grant.
Which in decatur what strategy
we want to use token or credentials.
In the second approach
we could simply expose a new one point
that validates the incoming refresh token
in generates access and
refreshed oh compares for us.
For simplicity's sake
will choose the second approach
but just know that there are other
options available to achieve all of this.
Okay so so first inside the i
am authentication d t o folder.
Let's add a new file in name
it refresh dash token dot d t o.
Inside of this file.
Let's add a simple detail class
and call it refresh token dt oh.
Let's annotate the
refresh token property
with the is not empty decorator
from the key class
dash validator package.
With this in place
let's navigate to our
authentication controller
and add their corresponding
refresh tokens post endpoint.
Similar to our sign an endpoint
be annotated it with the
http decorator to instruct
a framework that in case
of a successful response.
The okay status
should be used as a.
Two hundred.
Let's copy what we have here.
Open of the authentication service and
paste it they're removing all of the https
specific annotations
in flagging this method
as a sink.
Inside our method
here let's first verify
the incoming refresh token.
Next let's use the sub
which represents the user
ID to retrieve the user
entity from the database.
Once we have the user instance
let's scroll up a little
to the sign in method
as we could reuse the
tokens generation logic
but
we want to avoid
copying coat over
but let's refactor this method
and extract these lines
to a dedicated method.
Let's call this new method
generate tokens.
Before we proceed
let's make sure to label
this method as public
as will need it
in future lessons.
With our new method in place
we can now use the
generate tokens method
in our newly defined
refreshed tokens method.
Lastly
let's wrap everything
up in a try catch block
and in case any error
occurs be it user does not exist
refresh token is
invalid or expired etc.
Will make sure we throw the
unauthorized exception error.
Perfect.
Let's save our changes as
and head back to insomnia.
Let's copy the refresh token
we received a few minutes ago
in hit the authentication slash
refresh dashed tokens and point
to retrieve a new
pair of tokens.
Passing in the refresh token.
As the request body.
And voila.
We have successfully regenerated
are tokens using the refresh token.
As we can see.
Users will now have the ability
to re authenticate themselves
be a refresh tokens.
All while keeping
our application
fairly secure.
Who do are access tokens
have in short detail or time to live.