Passport
is the most popular know js
authentication library out there.
It is well known by
the community and
successfully used in many
production applications.
Passport
has a rich ecosystem of strategies to
implement various authentication mechanisms.
While simple in concept.
The set of passport
strategies use used for
them as large and
presents a lot of variety.
Passport abstracts these varied
steps into a standard pattern.
In the nastiest passport module.
Wraps and standardize
is this pattern
into familiar nest constructs.
So far throughout this entire course
extension we have implemented
everything by ourselves
without using passport
just the show you that even though passport
is great to years and super popular.
You can build a fully fledged
flexible authentication system
without using it as well.
In this lesson
will show you how you
could integrate passport
with nest which might
be useful for situations
where you don't need
that absolute full control.
Like all the custom things
we've gone through this course.
Also.
Just to mix things
up a little bit more
instead of using
jwt for authentication
will be using
server-side sessions.
Which is another great
option for authentication that
may make sense and some
applications and circumstances.
A session
allows web apps to persist data
about the current user between requests.
The mechanism we used to
accomplish this is a cookie.
Which allows the server
to create small blocks of
contextual data placed in
the user's browser or device.
So what that means in the big
picture is that when a user logs in
regenerate a sec the ID
and send it back to the user.
Expecting that it will be sent back to
us in subsequent requests as a cookie.
On the a p i sighed
we can then compared
the received ID aka
session ID
with the ID we have
stored in memory.
The issue with this approach
is that it's fully stateful.
If you have a load
balancer in front of your a p i.
The user may authenticate through
the first instance or node and then access
resources through
another instance.
In this case
the server won't
recognize the user
to solve this problem
we typically use a database
for storing session ids
most often
read us.
All right so before we start
let's open up our terminals and
install a few dependencies passport.
Nest j s passport
and express session.
Let's also install their
corresponding type definitions
make sure we save them
as depth dependencies.
Once the installation
process is complete.
Let's open a bar e n v file
and add a new environment
variable for hour session secret.
We need a secret to encrypt
and decrypt hour session ids.
Next up.
Let's open up her
i am module file
and add to imports
for express session
and passport.
With those in place.
Let's scroll down to
our i am module class
and make and implement
the nest module interface.
This interface requires us to
provide a consumer method
that takes one input argument.
Middleware consumer.
Which lets us register
middleware functions.
Here.
Let's register a few passport
related middleware functions.
Note that the order in which
middleware is placed is very important
as they get ran
one after another.
With our middleware
functions registered
let's open up our terminals
and generate a new session
authentication service
using the nastiest July.
We could have instead
modified the existing
authentication service that currently
implements Jada beauty based authentication.
But since we don't want to confuse
you and mixed these two concepts.
Were deciding to
keep them separate.
Next let's generate a dedicated
session authentication controller.
Great.
With both files place
let's navigate two hour
session authentication service
and start by injecting to
providers into the constructed.
User repository
and are hashing service.
Now in the service
will implement just one method
sign in.
Which will actually look
just like are so sign a method
in our authentication service
we created a while back.
To let's go ahead
and copy that method over
and replace a few things.
Let's start by removing the two
factor authentication code here
just to make the authentication
float easier to comprehend.
And instead of generating
tokens upon successful login.
Let's just returned
the user energy.
The code here can be found
below the course video as always.
Next up let's move on to our
session authentication controller class.
First
let's decorated with the auth
decorator passing and auth type none
to make sure all routes declared
here in this controller our public.
Next
let's inject the session authentication
service using the standard approach.
And lastly
let's add a sign in method
that once again will
be similar to our sign in
method from our previous
authentication controller.
One different here
is that we're going to use the request
log in method provided by passport.
Passing the user energy
as an input argument.
Which will log this
specific user in.
You may have noticed that we
are using promise of i hear as well
as the original log in method
implements a callback style
and promise of i
helps convert callback
a p eyes into a promise.
Passports request logged method.
Requires us to
provide logic for.
Serializing the user
and d serializing.
So let's get that logic setup.
Open up our terminals and
generate a new class with the.
A seal i
called user serializer
and put it within
a new serializer
folder.
Or can place all of
our related larger.
Let's navigate to this
newly generated class
and make it extend
the passport serializer
class from the nastiest
lush passport package.
Inside this class let's
declare to methods.
Serialize user
which takes the user entity object that
we pass into the request log in method
and maps it to the
active user data payload
we've seen in previous lessons.
The
serialized user method here
simply passes the d
serialized payload up.
Know that we could possibly
use the user repository here
to retrieve the user entity
based on the active user data.
But since this method is
executed on every request
this would most certainly
have performance implications
so be mindful of doing
something like that in the the future.
Now let's save our changes.
Open up our terminals
in generate one remaining class
a session guard.
Once created what's
navigate to this class and add
the following lines to
our can activate method.
Where all we need to do
is grab the current request
in return request that is authenticated
method result from passport art.
Which returns a boolean.
Letting us know whether the
current user is authenticated are not.
Nice and simple right.
With everything
we've done so far
our session based authentication
is now fully functioning.
So to test everything out
let's switch to our session
authentication controller
and add a random route there
for demonstration Peru offices
and protected with
our new session guard.
Now let's make sure
to save our changes.
In before we test our endpoints
let's make sure we register
our user serializer as a provider.
Of navigate to r i
am module real quick.
Add the user serializer class to the
providers array and save our changes.
Great.
Now let's head over to insomnia
and start by calling the session dash
authentication slush sign in post endpoint.
Making sure to pass
in our credentials.
In the request body
just like we do with jwt
based authentication.
As we can see we received a two hundred
ok so everything worked and we were able to
sign in and have a
session created great.
Now if we click
on the cookies tab
will see our
session ID in there.
Now.
Let's hit our random and point
protected by our session guard
that should say hello
followed by our user email.
If everything works properly
and were authenticated.
And voila as we can see
we got a two hundred okay
and were able to see hello
user one at ness js dot com
which is our current email that
we signed into our system fantastic.
As we mentioned at the
beginning of this lesson
session ids are kept in memory.
So in real world systems.
We typically use an external
database to keep track of sessions.
Another important
problem to remember
is that every time
you reboot your e poi
meaning stop or started.
Pushed new changes
or anything like that.
All sessions will be lost and
everyone will be logged out.
For demonstration purposes.
Will use read us as is
pretty simple to set up
plus we already have
configured in her application
since we used red us for
refresh tokens in previous lessons
but
you could use any database of
your choice to soar session data.
Read us is fantastic.
As it's very lightweight
an extremely fast so it's
without a doubt an
excellent of option for this.
So first
let's install a few required dependencies
that we will need before going forward.
Connect dash
us
and the type definitions for.
Once the installation
process is complete.
Let's navigate to
r i am module file
scrawled of the top and
add the following import
importing star
as create read a store
from connect dash read us.
Next onto the configure method.
Here
let's create a
reddish your class
passing down the session package
reference as an input parameter.
And next
what's up the the configuration we passed
two hour session middleware adding one
additional property
called store.
And let's make sure
to import read is here
from Iowa
us
and that's it.
Few steps we just leveled up our session
authentication system to use read us.
Everything should
work just the same
but now if we stop and
restart your application.
Will see that we are
still in fact logged in
and able to hit that guarded
and point we created.
For fun.
Look into your read estate
a base annual even be able
to see the key values
for your sessions and side.
So we've gone through
a lot in this lesson
showcasing just how
easy it is to use passport.
Password does give away some of our control
since we don't have absolute manual control
over every little thing in the
authentication process of our applications
but it does make a lot
of things easier for us.
Note that using passport
with Jada beauties
is very similar to
what we've done here.
We won't be showcasing
that in this course
but if you're interested
in that specifically
we covered in great detail
in the official
j js documentations.
You can find a link to that
below the course video.
Thanks again for watching.