As we mentioned in
the previous lesson
in any application there are always certain
and points that should remain public.
Take for example
this sign in and point
that lets users log
into the system.
Unless it's public
no one would be able to
access it in actually log in.
Right now in our application.
Every route is being protected
by our as access token
guards since we registered
at globally via ap guard.
But how can we let her application know
which routes we want to remain public.
Which he of this.
Let's create a new decorator
that lets us flag specific
and points as unprotected.
This will also come in handy
in future challenges we will face
in upcoming lessons.
Let's start things off
by creating an enum
that will indicate what authentication
type we want to use for specific routes.
In our i am slash
authentication folder.
Let's create a new directory
named he nubs
and inside of it.
Re a new file
old
off dash type.
Dot enum
dot t s.
Inside this file.
Let's create a simple ina
that consists of two values.
Bear.
Which is going to
beat the default strategy
and none
which indicates we want to skip
authentication for a given resource.
Next up we're going to
create a decorator named off.
This do decorator will
let us choose the strategy
for the annotated endpoint
on or an entire controller.
Though alongside the
newly created enums folder
let's create a new
directory called decorators.
And inside the folder.
Create a new off dot
decorator dot ts file.
In this file.
Let's first declared
the meta data key.
Next.
Let's create our
custom decorator.
If you're not familiar
with the set meditate a
her here
we recommend
looking at the lesson
using meta data to built generic guards
or interceptors from our fundamental
force.
With all of this and place
let's head over to our
access token guard
and start by removing the console
log we added in the previous lesson
as we no longer need it.
Next let's open up our terminals
and generate a new guard
using the nest the alive.
Let's place it within the i am
authentication and guards folder
and let's call this
authentication.
In this guard.
We're going to need
to dependencies.
First being the reflector provider which
gives us access to the underlying meta data.
And the second dependency
being our access token guard.
This may look strange since we're composing
a guard from multiple other guards
and we are even injecting the access
token guard in the constructor here
but injecting
guards in this way.
Similar to how he typically inject
services is feasible as long as
register our guards as providers
in our modules providers array.
Next in here let's dig Claire
to properties in our class.
One being the static
default aspx type property.
Indicating which
strategy is the default one
in our case will make
that off type bear.
And another one
this time non-static which represents
the mappings between off types
in their actual
corresponding guards.
With all that in place now let's move
onto the can activate method of our guard.
Let's call the reflectors
get all and override method
and passing the author type
key constant as the first argument.
For the second argument.
Will be passing in an array
that consists of two targets
that we want this meta
data to be retrieved from.
Either a class.
Or a handler aka a
method reference.
By doing all of this.
Were able to place our guard on
either a class or the method level.
Next using our off
type guard map.
Let's map of type values to the
corresponding guard instances.
Also
let's make sure to
declare the error variable
that represents the
exception to be thrown
by the authentication guard
in case all guards
returned false.
And lastly
less iterate through
our the guards array and
call their respective
can activate methods.
If any of the allowed
authentication types pass
we return true.
Otherwise our guard will throw the most
recent error thrown by the trigger guard
or unauthorized exception
which is the default air.
Let's save our changes.
Open up the i am module
and replace the access token
guard with our newly
created authentication guard.
Was also make sure to register at the
an access token guard as a provider now
but it becomes injectable
for the authentication guard.
Perfect.
Let's save our changes had ever do insomnia
and let's test the sign an endpoint.
As we can see.
It is now returning a four o one which
means it's currently protected by our guard
does not what we want actually.
Let's switch back to our ID.
Open up our
authentication controller
and applied the off decorated we
created at the beginning of this lesson
and apply it to the entire
authentication controller class.
Passing in the
off type none as
an input argument.
If we save our changes.
It back over to insomnia and test
everything again we'll see wala it works.
Are sign in and sign up routes
are now publicly available
were no longer
getting a four o one
and users will be able to sign
up and sign into our system now.
Not only that
but with the help of our
authentic a reader in the future
we can now make public or make unprotected
any other future routes we might need.