A claim
is a name value pair that
represents what the subject
can do not what the subject is.
When implementing
claims based authorization.
Instead of defining a set of roles
that can be assigned to users.
We define multiple permissions
and then have the ability to Grant
those permissions to individual users.
In our application so far.
We assumed that only
users with the admiral
can create update
and delete coffees.
Claims based authorization comes in
handy when we need more granular control
and for example
one specific users to be able
to create and update coffees
but only one specific supervisor user
has the capable city of deleting coffers.
Thought switch to r i d e
an start by creating a new
coffees that permission that t
file in the copies directory.
Inside this file
let's create an enum representing
all coffee related permissions
can find the code
below the course video.
Note once again at typically
you'd store these permissions
in a dedicated database table.
Okay so let's save our changes
and navigate to the i
am authorization director.
Here.
Let's create another file
called permission dot type.
In in this file.
Let's declare the
permission constant
and make it equal
to an empty object.
Inside this object.
Let's use the spread
operator on our coffees
permission enum making
all the permissions available
in the permission constance.
Let's also export the
permission type here so we can
use it as an input argument
type of our decorator.
Now.
Let's implement the permissions decorator
that indicates which permissions are
required in order to access
an annotated endpoint.
As we've already created a
few decorators in this course.
Will be following the same syntax
decree are permissions decorator.
You can find the code here
although the course video.
Perfect.
Now.
Let's create our
permissions guard.
And just like our roles guard.
It's almost identical so we won't need
to look at everything line by line again
but note that the only
main difference here
are that were grabbing
the permissions key.
And checking the user's permissions
against what was passed into the decorator.
One other important though thing
that's different and permissions check here
compared to our roles guard.
Is that instead of
using the some method.
We want to use every.
Which make sure that the user
has all required permissions assigned
not just one of 'em.
Also
since users can have multiple
permissions instead of using triple eagles
were using the dot
includes method here
and that's it.
With our permissions
garden place.
Let's now open up the i
am module and temporarily
replaced the roles guard
with our permissions guard
just to keep things simple
for the sake of this lesson.
All right.
Now the only remaining
step is for us to add the
missing permissions
column to our users entity.
Let's open it up and at it right
below the existing roles column.
Note.
As we've already mentioned before in a real
world application you would likely have a
dedicated permissions
table where you'd store
apps specific permissions.
Also
instead of storing users
permissions in a jaison column.
There would be a many
to many relationship
between the users a
and the permissions table.
Just as we mentioned
in the last lesson
if you'd like to practice go ahead and
create the entity controllers relations etc
to establish all
of this if you'd like.
Another common approach for permissions
is to tie permissions to roles themselves.
That's a slightly
different technique
and requires a
different configuration
but might be a better
for for certain systems.
In this different approach
you could keep using the role-based access
control implementation with the roles guard
and each role would have to
specify etc permissions tied to it.
Back to our code.
As you can see in the comment
above the permissions column.
Having this column in
combination with a role.
Does not make sense yeah.
We use both in this course
just to showcase two different
approaches to authorization
but in your application
you should decide
which approach you'll take.
Okay so next up.
Let's open up our
active user data interface
and add the corresponding
permission field there as well.
And last but not least.
Need to open up our
authentication service again
and make sure we
include the permissions field
and he signed a sink token.
Note
that once again
this is far from ideal.
Embedding a large
array of strings into our
token will lead to a long
non lightweight token.
In a real world application.
Where you store
permissions in the database.
We should only include an
array of ids here and said.
Moreover
if you expect a lot of
permissions in your system
perhaps https you should
embedded in the token at all.
In most cases.
It wouldn't have these stored
in a database and we would
retrieve these permissions
on each action or request.
All right with this
commonplace let's save our
changes open up the
coffee's controller file
and instead of using the roles
decorator on top of our create method.
Let's use permissions
now instead.
Passing permission
dot create coffee
as an input argument.
Let's save our changes.
Had ever to insomnia
and start things off by first
retrieving a new access token.
Once we get the response
let's up the our authorization header
again with the newly received access token
and hit the post
slash coffees on-point
just like in the last lesson.
Great.
We received a four
three forbidden error
just as we should expect
since our user does
not have any permissions
assigned to it yet.
To fixed us up.
Let's switch back to r ID e
open up our terminals
and using the rebel
again let's add the create
underscore coffee
permission to our user.
Note if you're getting any errors like
property permissions was not found in user.
You may need to
restart your rebel session
meaning
close the window
and run it again.
Let's get the user repository
update user one
an ad permissions
rate underscore coffee to it.
Right.
Now back to insomnia.
Let's retrieve a new
token again making sure
these updated permissions
are embedded in it.
Let's grab the token.
An update that authorization
header one last time
and had the coffee's
post and point once again.
We'll see that vala it works.
Are permission system is all
set up and working properly.
So as we've
mentioned in this lesson.
There's a lot of different techniques and
approaches to claim based authorization
and role-based access control.
Here in this lesson
we have both as we built on top of the
same project we used in the previous lesson
but
in a real world application.
Will likely just need one
or a slightly different combination
like we mentioned briefly a moment ago
where permissions are associated
with roles themselves
and not users directly.