Two factor authentication
or to f a.
Is the process of requiring a user to verify
their identity in to unique ways before
they are granted
access to a system.
To f a
extends this paradigm
by adding an additional step
to the authentication process.
Typically requiring
the user to enter
a one time token that
is dynamically generated
and delivered through a method
that only the user can access.
Via.
Google authenticator sms
and many other options.
To f a protects against phishing
social engineering and
password brute force attacks in
is a vital part of most secure
authentication systems.
Before we start.
Let's install a few required dependencies
that will need before going forward.
O t p lib
is a javascript one time
password or odp library
for one time pass
regeneration and verification.
It's compatible with
the Google authenticator
application that will
use in this lesson.
The qr code package is a qr code
two d barcode generator.
Will be continually
ahead as we already have
these installed but if
you're following along
just pause the video and come
back when everything's finished.
With everything installed
let's generate an ot
p authentication service
using the nes jsc ally.
Where will store most
of our odp business logic.
Before we start
implementing our service.
Let's open up our dot e m d file
and declare a new environment
variable they're called
t f a underscore app
underscore name.
In this variable
will store the to factor
auth application name
it will just call hours
off dash playground
but feel free to name
it whatever you'd like.
Now onto our service.
Let's start things off by injecting to
dependencies and our constructor.
Will use config service to retrieve that
to f a app name environment parable
and use a repository to enable two-factor
authentication upon successful generation
of a qr code.
All right so first
let's declare a
generate secret method.
Each user
must have a unique secret
key so inside this method
let's generate one
using the o t p lib library.
Let's make sure we import the authenticator
object from the ot p lib package
and call the generate
secret method on it.
Next up.
Let's first retrieve the
application name using
the config service that
get or throw method.
And then generate a you are i
using the authenticator
he you are a method.
And lastly.
Let's return both the you are i
and secret from this method.
Also.
Wanted a method that verifies user provided
code or token from the authentication
application in our case
Google authenticator.
So let's define the
verify code method.
Which also uses
authenticator from oh t
lib
and this time calling
the verified method on it.
Before you move further.
What's navigate to our
user entity and add two
columns here that will
need for our to factor needs.
First we need a column
that determines whether two
factor authentication has
been enabled for a given user
let's make sure to
set the default to false.
For the second column.
As great a column
named tf a secret
which will use to store a user's
two factor authentication secret.
With all that set up back to r
o t p authentication service.
Let's add the last method
we need their which
enables two factor
authentication forgiven user.
Know that we left a
comment here that ideally
we would want to encrypt the
secret instead of storing it in plain text.
But also know that we wouldn't
be able to use hashing here
as the original secret is required
to verify the users provided coat.
All right
but this service in place
and ready to be used.
To navigate to the
authentication controller
and add a new one point there
so we can access everything.
This endpoint
will return a user
specific qr code to be
scanned by the users
authenticator application.
To achieve this.
When easy access the native express js
response object the other rez decorator.
Also note that this method is
annotated with the hoth decorator
tour earning on bear
authentication for this endpoint
as other routes registered in
this controller our public by the fall.
Inside this method.
As first generate the
secret for the active user.
Using the generate secret method
we created just a moment ago.
Next.
Let's unable to f a.
Using the active user email
and a secret we just generated
making sure to oh wait the results.
And lastly.
A said the response
type two p n g
as will be returning a qr code image a return
the generated qr code back to the user.
Note that we imported the to filestream
helper function from the qr code library
which rights to qr
code image to a stream.
Let's save our changes.
Had ever do insomnia
and log in again just to
make sure we're not
using an expired token.
Now.
Let's try to hit our newly
created authentication
slashed to f a slash
generate and point
to see if everything works.
An excellent.
We can see we got that qr
code image back in the response.
That we can now scan or qr code
with our Google
authenticator application
on our mobile device.
All right so with our
qr code generated
we need to update the sign and flown
out to require a use or to pass the t o tp.
Or time based one time password
in this case our Google authenticator
code alongside their email and password.
Will to navigate
to the sign in detail class
and at a new field
they're named tf a code.
Of type string.
Will flag as optional
as as required only
for users that have to f a
turned on.
Now let's open up our
authentication service
and inject the oh.
Authentication service as will
need it for validating tokens.
Let's scroll down
to the sign in method
and a just before regenerate
access and refresh tokens
let's add a new condition.
Checking if tfl is enabled.
With a given user.
And if so
let's verify the code
and thrown an exception
if it's invalid.
Great.
Let's make sure we
save our changes.
Had ever do insomnia and
try to log in one more time.
Since our user
has two f a enabled
since we generated a qr code by
hitting the to f a slash January endpoint.
We received an error
invalid to f a code just
as we should expect.
So let's update our request body
and past the appropriate
tf a code that you can
retrieve from your Google
authenticator application.
On your mobile device.
Notice will of course be
different than what we're
entering here at the very
moment of this record it.
If we had sent
you'll see that we
successfully logged in.
So in this lesson we've
done everything we need
to set up to f a within
our future applications.
Bringing our log in
security to the next level.