A policy defines a requirement
or a collection of requirements.
That the user must satisfy
in order to access a resource.
In fact.
Even if you use claim based
or role-based authorization.
You're actually using policy based
authorization but as hard-coded policies.
Think of the roles
decorator recreated.
Which required a user
to have a specific role
essentially creating a hardcoded
policy implemented within our roles guard.
Just as a disclaimer that in this lesson
we're going to be diving into some much more
advanced scenarios of
authorization that aren't
typically required
for most applications.
Usually
roles based or claims based
is sufficient for most use cases
but we thought it might be helpful to
showcase policy based authorization.
Just in case you might need it for
yourself in your future applications.
All right so let's
switch to our ID
and see how we could leverage
policies and our application
if we felt we needed them.
Inside the authorization folder let's
create the following directories tree
policies slash interfaces.
In the interfaces folder
with create a new file and
name it policy dot interface dot t s.
Inside of this file let's
declare a policy interface.
This'll be a very simple interface
which will consist of one property
name
that will use to make
debugging simpler.
Next let's create a another file
alongside the policy interface and name it
policy dash handler
not interface dart t us.
Inside of this file
must declare a policy
handler interface.
This interface requires at the
handle method must be implemented.
This handle method
will take two arguments.
Policy
which is the corresponding policy instance
for which this handler was implemented for.
Note the generic type t
as different policy handlers will
have their own dedicated policies.
And our second argument
be active user data object
indicating what's
the context user
for which were
executing this policy on.
Perfect.
With these interfaces and place let's never
wanted the policy handler storage class.
This class
will serve us as a
static map collection
that associates policies
with their corresponding
policy handlers.
Each policy
should have exactly
one policy handler.
The policy handler
will be in charge of
processing a specific pa rc.
Don't worry.
All this will make much
more sense in a moment.
Let's start by creating a policy
dash handlers dot storage file
in our policies folder.
An inside of this file.
Let's declare a simple class that contains
one private collection under the hood.
Also.
Let's make sure to annotated
with the injectable decorator.
The first type argument
we specify for the map class
indicates the type of
our keys in this collection.
Since keys equals classes
representing our policies
and we need to use
type of policy here.
The second type
argument we see here.
Represents values
for these keys.
Year we've used policy
handler of type any.
As will be using policy
handler instances as values.
Note that in the case of keys we operate
on types not concrete instances as we want
to enable developers
to manually instantiate
an convey figure
policies for example.
If different and points in our
application have different requirements.
All right so enough theory.
Next.
Will need to methods
that let us operate on
the internal collection
of this storage class.
Yet.
Or retrieving the policy handler
class based on the given policy class.
And
the method add.
Or associating policies
with policy handlers.
Nope we've used the
cls suffix here to indicate
were operating on
classes here not instances.
With this storage
class and place
we can start creating
our first policy.
For demonstration purposes
will implement a
very custom policy.
Framework contributor policy that checks
of the user's email address is registered
under the nastiest
dot com domain.
So one side our policies folder
let's create a new file and name it framework
dash contributor dot policy dot to yes.
Inside of this file
let's create a simple class
called framework contributor policy
and make it implement
the policy interface.
Let's also not forget to
provide the name of this policy.
Note
typically would recommend
creating another file next to this one.
In calling it
bremer contributor policy
dash handler that t ts
but since the framework contributor policy
is very straightforward short and simple.
In order to make things
easier to comprehend
and understand.
We decided to create
the handler class
straightened side of this file
right after the policy definition.
The let's go ahead and create the
framework contributor policy handler now.
Once again
let's make sure it's
annotated with the injectable
decorator and that implements
our policy handler interface.
Next up let's
declare a constructor
and inject the policy
handler storage provider.
Inside this constructor.
Using the policy handler storage
add method we
created a moment ago.
Let's associate this handler with the
corresponding framework contributor policy
as follows.
Since all of our policy handlers
are designed to be a synchronous.
Let's flag this method
as a sink.
And from here
we can start implementing
our actual policy.
Inside of the handle method.
Let's add the following logic you
can find below the course video.
In the code shown here.
We are simply checking
whether the the user's
email address ends
with at ness js dot com
and if not
we throw an exception
and that's it.
Remember
we are just creating a very simple policy
for demonstration purposes but hopefully
you can see the
possibilities here
and why this type of
authorization could be useful.
In certain applications
and circumstances.
Before we continue further.
Let's open up our i am
module file and make
sure to register both
policy handler storage.
And framework contributor
policy handler classes as providers.
This is why we added those
injectable decorators after all.
Right.
Now there are two more
steps we need to do.
That we already covered
in previous lessons.
First.
Instead of our decorators folder
let's create a new
policies decorator for
attaching policies to
end points or controllers.
Like always all of the code for this
can be found below the course video.
Once we're done.
Let's create a a
new policies guard
that runs context specific
policies for a given operation.
We'll start by pasting
our usual boilerplate
reading the meta data
ignoring the guard if
policies aren't present etc
we've done this a few
times already in this course.
And with his coat and place.
Let's start implementing the
policy specific lodge Jack now.
Now listen Jack the policy
handler storage regretted.
As will need it for retrieving
policy handlers themselves.
If policies are defined
then let's iterate through them.
Map to their corresponding policy handler
instances and call the handler method.
Passing the policy
instance as a first parameter.
And the active user data
as the second one.
Note
to retrieve the
corresponding handler.
We have to pass the policy
the constructor reference.
As you may remember
our policy handler storage associates handlers
with policy classes and not instances.
Since our policy
handlers handle method
are a sink.
Let's use the promise that
all here to all wait the results.
In in case any error was thrown.
Let's use catch and map the heirs
to the forbidden exception error.
Perfect.
With all of that in place.
Let's navigate to
the i am module file
an swap the permissions guard
with our new policies guard.
Next.
Let's open up our
coffees controller file.
And instead of using the
permissions decorator.
Let's commented out
and let's use the
policies annotation.
Applying the framework
contributor policy.
Awesome.
Know
you could apply multiple
policies to a single and point
as follows if needed.
Alright.
So let's save our changes.
Had overdue insomnia
and test everything to see
these policies and action.
Lets it send
an check to see if we can access
the post slash coffees endpoint.
Know that if you're getting
a four o one air make
sure to sign in again and
update your access token.
And yes as we could
see we do have access.
Since our users email address
is user one at nest jazz dot com.
Now.
Let's switch back to r i d e.
Open up our framework
contributor policy handler class
to instead of checking for
the presence of at sjs dot com.
Updated to expect
at trial on dot io.
Let's save our changes.
Had overdue insomnia and try to
hit that same and point once again.
And as we can see.
We are now an authorized
to access this endpoint due to
the policy authorization of
restrictions we have sat on it.
Recovered quite
a bit in this lesson
and hopefully you could see the
value in policy based authorization
but also how it really may not
be necessary for every application
and especially
not every endpoint.
Like most tools
there's a use
case for everything
and with what we've
covered in this lesson
you'll be able to cover.
Even the most complex
authorization scenarios in
your future nest applications.