Hey everyone and welcome to
the official nastiest js courses.
In this extension we're
going to be covering ness js
authentication and
authorization from top to bottom.
Getting you up to speed
and creating
enterprise great a p eyes
with the help of nest chess
in no time.
So let's introduce the
instructors for this course.
My knee mr Mark part
of the nest js core team
and together with Camille
the creator of ness js
were excited to have
you learning nest with us.
To get the most out of this course
try to code alongside us in remember
you can pause the
videos at any time.
Almost everything we're
going to be looking at.
Learning
and building in this
course will be incremental
by the end
you'll have a somewhat
real world a p i and
be ready to fully take
advantage of nasty js.
Even using this application.
As a great jumping off point
for your future applications.
Please note that this
extension is a continuation
knowledge wise of the
nastiest fundamentals course.
Before you start watching this course
we recommend taking a step back
and checking out the
official fundamentals
course if you're not
already comfortable with
yes that is.
In this extension will assume that you're
familiar with everything we've covered in
the fundamentals
call source however
we will be starting this course
with a new application from
scratch to make sure we
don't have any redundant files.
This will make it easier
to holistically understand
what's needed to implement
authentication in our nest js projects.