Authentication and authorization
while often used interchangeably
represent essentially
different functions.
Authentication is the
process of identifying users
invalidating who
they claim to be.
One of the most standard an
obvious factors to authenticate identity
as a password.
If the user matches the password
credentials him means the identity is valid
and the system grants
access to that user.
This entire face is usually
done before authorization.
Let's put things in terms
of our coffee application
that we've been building
in all of the nastiest courses.
As a more real world
example of authentication.
Let's say a user wants to view
a list of their favorite coffees
but to do so
they would need to sign in first
that they can be properly identified by
the system before seeing their favorites.
Authorization on the other hand
is the process of giving a user
permission to access a
specific resource or function.
Or example in administrative
user may be allowed to create
edit and delete coffees
whereas a non
administrative user
is only authorized
to view coffees.
Authorization
as orthogonal
meaning that it is
independent of authentication
however
authorization does require
an authentication mechanism
in order to function properly.
On the current slide
you can see a nice simple
comparison between
authentication and authorization.
Don't worry if it doesn't
make much sense yet.
In this course extension will be implementing
both of these mechanisms step by step.
To let's get started and
set up everything we need
in terms of authentication
and authorization.
All completely from scratch
without using any third party off libs.
All industrious.