‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In the last lesson we saw how to handle a mongoose schema validation error.
‫Whenever we are processing an Http request in our nestjs backend.
‫And that request contains some data that when we try to add it or update it on the database, it ends
‫up triggering a mongoose error that we then handle with our fallback exception filter.
‫Now we would like to take our validation a step further for that specific type of errors, validation
‫errors from our input data.
‫We would like to, instead of letting the execution logic of the backend reach the point where the data
‫is trying to get inserted into the database, let's instead validate the data immediately when it arrives
‫to our backend.
‫More specifically, we would like to validate, for example, this course object that we are receiving
‫here in the body of the Http request.
‫Going back here to our Restlet interface, this is the Json payload that we want to validate immediately
‫when this arrives at the backend.
‫So we want to detect that there is a problem in the sequential number field right at the beginning of
‫processing this Http request and not close to the end when we might have already triggered some logic
‫that might have accidentally produced some side effect on the database.
‫We want to detect validation errors right at the beginning of the request and we want to produce a more
‫useful response for our client.
‫So we want to make sure that we validate all the errors of the payload and not simply report the first
‫one that triggered the schema validation error.
‫We want to send back a complete error payload specifying all the fields that are in error.
‫Any mandatory fields that are missing and specifying what is the exact problem with each of the fields.
‫This way, in our front end we are going to be able to display a more useful error message to the user,
‫informing him of all the fields that he needs to edit in order to implement this type of validation
‫logic.
‫We are going to be using the class validator package.
‫So as you can see, this is validation made easy using TypeScript decorators.
‫Let's have a look at what it looks like.
‫So as we can see here in the examples, we are going to be taking our domain model object interfaces
‫such as, for example, courses, lessons, et cetera.
‫And we are going to turn them into classes.
‫Then as classes we will be able to apply decorators to its properties.
‫We have here a series of decorators that allows us to specify that, for example, this number here
‫must be an integer and it must be between 0 and 10.
‫We can even validate string patterns using regular expressions such as, for example, is email.
‫We can validate that this is a valid date.
‫We can make fields mandatory, we can validate the length of a field.
‫ET cetera.
‫So we have here a very fine grained control over the validation of each of the properties of a given
‫domain model.
‫At this moment in the course, you already have class validator installed in your workspace.
‫So as an example, let's apply this to the course type definition.
‫Going back here to our project, we are going to go here to the shared folder in the root directory
‫of the project and we are going to click here on course.
‫So as you can see, this is now currently an interface, so we can't apply here decorators to it.
‫So let's then first change it into a class.
‫Now that we have changed it to a class, let's go ahead and add here some decorators to specify the
‫validation messages for each of these fields.
‫For example, this field here is supposed to be an integer.
‫So let's go ahead and add here.
‫The is int decorator from class validator.
‫Now this decorator takes in here a series of configuration parameters.
‫One of them, for example, is the message.
‫So we can specify here a message for when this validation is not met.
‫We are going to add here.
‫For example, the second no must be numeric.
‫Let's give here a few more examples.
‫For example, the property must be a string.
‫So let's add here the string decorator and let's make this, for example, an optional property.
‫Let's set in here the always flag to false.
‫This way we can validate course instances that don't have a filled in.
‫We can apply similar decorators to the other properties of a course.
‫Let's add here a string to icon URL, also to course list description to description.
‫Also the long description field should be a string.
‫The category as well.
‫Let's add here the is int decorator to the lesson count property and let's also validate that the promo
‫field is a boolean.
‫Using is boolean to complete our example.
‫Let's make sure that.
‫This field here is a string as well.
‫Now, because this ID field is also a MongoDB field.
‫Let's add in the is mongo ID decorator as well.
‫Now we are going to come back to this definition of the course class and adapt here, the validation
‫decorators.
‫Right now we want to show you how to use this decorators in order to validate an incoming Json payload.
‫So in order to do that, we are going to need to introduce a new nestjs concept, which is the notion
‫of pipe.