‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this lesson, we are going to introduce a new Nestjs concept.
‫We are going to introduce the notion of pipe.
‫So a pipe is a transformation construct that takes an input and produces an output like the name indicates.
‫Nestjs.
‫Pipes work a bit in a similar way as Unix pipes in the sense that we can chain them together in order
‫to produce a final output.
‫Let's give a simple example of a use case for a nestjs pipe.
‫So going back here to our Restlet API, let's take here for example, the sequential number field.
‫So the sequential number field is supposed to be numeric, but let's say that accidentally we fill in
‫here a string instead of a number.
‫We would like to make sure that our code always receives a number instead of a string.
‫So for that we would like to apply a pipe only to this property of the Http body and transform any string
‫value that we have here into a number.
‫First, let's grab this value in our backend and confirm that indeed it's type is a string.
‫Let's take for example, the update crud operation for the course entity.
‫So we are going to do here a put call.
‫We are going to access here slash API slash courses and we are going to add here the ID of one of the
‫courses.
‫So this is the mongo ID identifier of a particular course object.
‫And let's say that we would like to update here the sequential number property.
‫Let's now switch back to our program and see that indeed we receive this as a string.
‫We are going to go here to the update course operation.
‫And let's, as an example, add here a new parameter which we are going to call sequential number.
‫Let's say that this is a number and let's fill this in by using the body decorator.
‫We're going to pass in here the name Segno.
‫So this is going to come from a property in the Http body of the incoming request called Segno.
‫And we have annotated it here as a type as being a number.
‫This is the TypeScript type for a number, but this is not the number type of the JavaScript runtime.
‫So let's check at runtime.
‫What is the actual type of Segno We are going to add here a little bit of logging where we are printing
‫the sequential number value, but we are also printing the actual type of this variable using the type
‫of operator.
‫Let's now trigger the update operation and let's see what we get on the log.
‫So we are going to click here on Send.
‫As we can see, we got here a 200.
‫Okay response.
‫We got back here, the new version of the updated course as it exists after the update on the database
‫and going back here to our terminal, we are going to see that indeed the sequential number value is
‫ten, but the runtime type is actually a string and not a number.
‫So what we want to do now is apply a transformation operation only to this field to turn it from a string
‫into a number.
‫Notice that we also got here, a small notification here, a deprecation warning from Mongoose that
‫this operation find one and update is internally using an operation available at the level of the MongoDB
‫driver that has been recently deprecated.
‫So if we want to fix this warning, we need to go to our Main.ts file and let's add here some mongoose
‫configuration.
‫We are going to configure Mongoose to not use the use, find and modify operation at the level of the
‫driver.
‫This is the operation that got deprecated.
‫So Mongoose will use a new alternative that is available at the level of the MongoDB driver.
‫Let's then import here star as mongoose from Mongoose.
‫And with this we will have fixed the issue that we saw in the console at runtime.
‫Now that we have introduced the notion of pipe and we know what it's used for, let's then in the next
‫lesson, implement a custom two integer pipe that takes a string and converts it into a number.