‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to write as an example our two integer pipes.
‫So this is going to be an example of a nestjs custom pipe.
‫Let's open here the source folder and let's create here a new folder called Pipes.
‫Inside it.
‫We are going to be creating a new file that we are going to call to integer dot pipes.
‫And inside this file we are going to be defining a new class that we are simply going to call to integer
‫pipe.
‫Now, in order for this class to be a pipe, it needs to implement the pipe transform interface.
‫So make sure that you import the pipe, transform interface from nestjs common and not from angular
‫core.
‫Now we need to specify here as a parametric type, what is the input type that we are trying to transform?
‫In this case, we are trying to transform a string and we also need to implement here the transform
‫method.
‫So we are going to be providing here a number as the output of our transformation.
‫So the pipe works in the following way.
‫We are going to receive here as the input value, the input that gets passed to the pipe, in this case,
‫a string that we want to transform into an integer.
‫And here as the output we need to provide the result of the pipe transformation.
‫So let's go ahead and try to convert our value into a number we are going to be applying here the function
‫parse int and we are going to pass it the value.
‫So now we are going to test if this is a valid numeric value or not.
‫Let's use for that.
‫The is not a number function and pass it this value to check if it's actually numeric.
‫So if it's not numeric pass INT is going to return the value, not a number and assign it here to this
‫val constant.
‫So if this value is not a number, then we are going to throw here an exception.
‫Let's throw for example the bad request exception.
‫Let's create here a new instance of that exception and let's add here a message conversion to number
‫failed and let's pass in here the value that we did not manage to convert into a number.
‫So as you can see, pipes can be used not only for transforming inputs into outputs, but because that
‫operation can fail, they can also be used for validation.
‫Let's then return as the output of our transformation, the new numeric value.
‫And with this we have a two integer pipe ready to use.
‫So let's go ahead and plug it into our backend.
‫Let's apply the two integer pipe just to the update course operation and more specifically here only
‫to the sequential number field.
‫So we are going to add here the constructor function of two integer pipe.
‫Let's now try this new version of our backend.
‫We are going to switch here to the Restlet API interface.
‫We are going to send a new test request.
‫It went through successfully.
‫Now let's go back here to our terminal and notice that the warning that we had here before is gone.
‫And we have here the sequential number value is ten and the type at runtime is now a number.
‫So the two integer pipe converted the string that we had on our Json payload into a number as expected.
‫Now, because this operation is very common, converting a string into a number nestjs already comes
‫with a built in pipe for that.
‫So if instead here we apply the parse int pipe from nestjs common, we are going to get the same result.
‫Now what is important to retain about pipes is that they can be both used for transformation and validation
‫because the transformation operation might go wrong.
‫So we are going to see next how to use a pipe, a built in pipe that is already available in Nestjs
‫in order to validate the data in a course object using this decorators here from class validator.