‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to learn how to use class validator in order to validate an incoming
‫Http payload body that contains, for example, a course entity.
‫So as you can see, the course entity contains these properties which have been decorated here with
‫decorators such as is int, is string, etcetera.
‫So these are the decorators that are going to be used to validate an instance of a course.
‫We would like that a course object whenever it arrives here, for example at update course or even create
‫course.
‫We would like that this data here to have been already validated at this point before applying any of
‫our controller logic.
‫So if there is a validation problem with that data, we are not even going to apply any of the controller
‫logic.
‫Instead, we are going to immediately send back to the front end an error message that is going to help
‫the user understand what went wrong.
‫So in order to validate this course input here, what we are going to do is we are going to apply a
‫built in nestjs type similar to the two integer type that we built here manually, which is called the
‫validation pipe.
‫And because we want to apply this to every controller in our application, we are going to declare it
‫as a global pipe.
‫So we are going to use here app dot use global pipes and here we are going to configure a new instance
‫of the built in validation pipe.
‫So with this global pipe in place, any inputs in our controllers that are annotated with any of these
‫decorators from the class validator package are going to be used to validate the Http request payload.
‫However, in order for this to work, we need to make these types not partial instances of a course,
‫but we need to make them actual instances of a course.
‫Otherwise class validator is not going to work.
‫So for example, here in our update course, the same thing applies.
‫We need to remove here the use of partial and instead we need to consider this as a complete instance
‫of a course.
‫Of course at runtime.
‫That is not going to be the case here.
‫In the case of an update, we are only going to receive the properties that we need to modify on the
‫database.
‫We can also go ahead and remove the sequential number parameter because it's not being used here in
‫the body of our update course method.
‫We simply use it to demonstrate the use of the parse int pipe.
‫Now we would expect that this changes object should be validated according to this decorators.
‫So let's try this out.
‫Let's switch here to our Restlet client and let's use here a payload that contains a couple of errors.
‫For example, we are going to be using here the sequential number field, which has a non-numeric value.
‫And we are also going to use here the promo field with a non boolean value.
‫We are also using here the description field which contains a valid string value.
‫So let's submit this request and see what happens.
‫So as you can see, the response that we got back was a 400 bad request.
‫It was created by the Http exception filter, and we have here a series of error messages.
‫So let's open one.
‫We can see that it's targeting the field sequence number and we have here the constraint that this should
‫be a mongo ID.
‫Let's have a look at the second message.
‫It's targeting property sequential number.
‫Here we are targeting the URL, the icon URL and so forth.
‫So all of the decorators have been used in order to validate our input payload and that resulted in
‫our validation pipe to throw an error, which is a subclass of Http exception.
‫So that causes our Http exception filter to get triggered and build this error response for us.
‫Now, this payload here, it's still not very useful for our frontend client, so we are going to see
‫how to build a better response in a moment.
‫Right now let's focus on the following.
‫As we can see, all the properties are getting validated and this is because we have not made the properties
‫optional.
‫So instead of making every single property optional here in the definition of our schema, let's instead
‫configure our validation pipe to ignore any missing properties.
‫So let's pass in here a configuration object and we are going to set the skip missing properties property
‫to true.
‫Let's now try this out.
‫So going back here to our Restlet client, let's submit again the request.
‫It's still in error, but this time around we only get two errors.
‫One targeting the sequential number field and the other targeting the promotional field.
‫So this means that these two fields were correctly marked as in error, but the description field went
‫through without any problem and the other missing properties in our request did not trigger an error.
‫As we can see, our validation pipe is working correctly.
‫But the error response that we get here is not exactly what.
‫We want.
‫So again, we are going to customize the error response for the specific case of validation errors.
‫So just like before, we are going to customize the error response for validation errors and we are
‫going to do this in three steps.
‫We are going to have the validation pipe, throw a custom exception.
‫We are going to define that exception ourselves as a subclass of Http exception, and we are going to
‫create a specific validation exception filter to properly format this type of messages.