‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this lesson, we are going to learn how to configure the response generated by the validation pipe.
‫So the validation pipe is going to throw an error if some of the input parameters of the request are
‫considered not valid by applying the class validator decorators to our input model, in this case the
‫course class.
‫So if, for example, the icon property is not a string, then we are going to be throwing a new error
‫that this time around we want to catch and format properly before sending the response back to the front
‫end.
‫For that, the first thing that we are going to need is a new custom validation exception.
‫Here in our filters folder, we are going to create a new file that we are going to call validation
‫dot exception, dot ts.
‫So inside it we are going to define our new exception.
‫Let's start by defining simply a validation exception class and let's have it extend the existing bad
‫request exception from Nestjs.
‫So this bad request exception is an Http exception.
‫Let's now add a constructor to our custom exception.
‫We are going to start by calling the super constructor of Bad Request Exception, and we're going to
‫add here a mandatory parameter which we are going to call validation errors.
‫So one instance of a course class or any other model class in our application might have one or more
‫validation errors and let's report them back to the front end as an array of strings.
‫So one string per validation error.
‫All we have to do now is to find a way to throw this exception.
‫Whenever a validation error occurs, we can do so by going here to our main file and here in the configuration
‫of the validation pipe, we are going to specify here a property called Exception Factory.
‫Now this property is going to receive a function that is going to get triggered whenever a validation
‫error occurs.
‫So the function is going to have here an input argument which is going to be an array of validation
‫errors.
‫What we want to do now is to take the validation errors that were created whenever we were validating
‫an instance of a course, for example, and we want to define a validation exception that contains these
‫errors with a well formatted error message.
‫And we want to return this as the output of the exception factory function.
‫So the validation pipe is going to see that we have produced here a new validation exception and then
‫it's going to throw it.
‫Now we are going to need to catch this exception later on with the filter.
‫Right now, let's build the exception.
‫We are going to define here a new property called Messages that is going to be derived here from the
‫errors.
‫Let's map each error into a string.
‫Then let's take the error and let's build here a custom string using the template literal syntax.
‫So let's mark first here in our string.
‫What is the property to which the error belongs?
‫So let's call here error dot property and let's say that this property has the wrong value and let's
‫place in here the wrong value so that we know exactly what we need to change in our front end.
‫Let's add here a comma and here we are going to be adding the complete error message that we got from
‫applying each of the decorators.
‫We can obtain this information by accessing error dot constraints.
‫So for one, given property we might have several validation issues.
‫For example, a value might not be a string and it might not follow a certain format such as, for example,
‫being an email address.
‫So we are going to take here our multiple error constraints and we are going to join them all in a single
‫string.
‫Let's then apply here object dot values.
‫Let's get the values out of the constraints property and let's join all the constraint messages, for
‫example, with a comma.
‫Now that we have created here a properly formatted validation exception and we had the validation pipe
‫through it, we now just need to catch it and properly format our error response.
‫So for that, as usual, we are going to be creating here a filter.
‫Let's create here a new file that we are going to call validation dot filter, dot ts.
‫So inside it we are going to be defining our filter.
‫Let's go ahead and define here a class with the validation filter name.
‫And as usual, let's implement here the exception filter interface.
‫This interface has one method, which is the catch method.
‫So here we are going to be receiving a validation exception that we have just defined and we are going
‫to be using here arguments.
‫Host In order to produce our Http response.
‫Let's start by grabbing here the Http context and with the context, we are also going to grab the.
‫Response itself.
‫Let's now build the response that we want to return.
‫So let's return response dot status and we want to use here status 400 bad request.
‫We want to send back a Json payload.
‫Let's add here the payload body.
‫We're going to add here the status code.
‫Let's say it's 400 bad request and let's also add the property created by so that we can clearly see
‫where this exception is coming from.
‫This is coming from the validation filter.
‫Let's now add here a new property called validation errors, and this is going to contain the exception
‫validation errors array containing all the validation errors that were found.
‫Now let's annotate this class with the catch decorator and we're going to say that this exception filter
‫should be used for validation exceptions only.
‫Let's now take the validation filter and let's configure it here in our main method.
‫As we have mentioned before, in the filter configuration order here on use, global filters is important.
‫It should be from the most generic to the most specific.
‫So our validation filter is handling validation exceptions, which are subclasses of Http exceptions.
‫So it's a more specific filter.
‫Let's then add it here at the end of our array.
‫So with this we are going to make sure that whenever a validation exception gets thrown, that it's
‫the validation filter that is going to get triggered and not the exception filter.
‫Let's now, before trying this out, complete here, the implementation here of the exception factory
‫function.
‫So we have defined here the messages property, but we did not create our exception.
‫Let's create here a new validation exception and let's pass it in the constructor.
‫The messages containing the multiple validation errors.
‫Let's now try out our error handling solution here using the Restlet client.
‫Let's submit this payload.
‫So let's remember that there are two errors here.
‫One in the sequential number field and one in the promotion field.
‫Let's click send.
‫So again, we got a 400 bad request, but this time around we got here a response created by the validation
‫filter.
‫And as we can see here, we got two validation errors we have here that the sequential number has a
‫wrong value and the value happens to be error.
‫As we have seen here.
‫We have here the validation message must be numeric and something similar here for the promo field.
‫That must be a boolean value.
‫So as you can see, everything is working as expected and we are having our input course validated according
‫to the content of this class validator decorators.
‫Let's now see what would happen if we would switch here the order of the filters.
‫So instead of applying here, the validation filter at the end, let's say that we would apply it here
‫right after the fallback exception filter.
‫So if we now try out this new version of our backend, we are going to submit the same request.
‫We can see that we still got a custom error reply, but this time around the http exception filter was
‫triggered and not the validation specific validation filter.
‫So as you can see, the order of the filters is important.
‫We really need to configure them from the most generic to the most specific.
‫In the case of our application, the validation filter is more specific than the exception filter,
‫so it should come after it.
‫Here on this configuration array.
‫And with this we have completed our error handling section.
‫Now, before moving on to more advanced concepts such as authentication, authorization guards.
‫ET cetera.
‫Let's take a couple of practice lessons to apply the concepts that we have learned so far.
‫We are going to be building a new screen in our application.
‫It's going to be the View course screen where we are going to do a couple of extra requests to our backend,
‫and along the way we are going to learn a couple of extra features of Nestjs.
‫We are also going to learn how to create a one to many relation in Mongoose.
‫So this is coming right up in the next few lessons.