Hey everyone
and welcome to the
official ness js courses.
In this extension will
be going through many
advanced concepts and
nestorius from top to bottom
getting you up to speed and
creating enterprise great applications
with the help of
nest yes and no time.
Let's introduce the
instructors for this course.
My name is Mark
part of the nastiest escorting
answer whether with Camille
the creator of nestorius
were excited to have
you learning nest with us.
To get the most out of this
course try to code alongside
us and remember you can
positive videos at any time.
Please note that this extension
is a continuation knowledge wise
of the nastiest
fundamentals course.
Before you start watching
this course we recommend
taking a step back and
checking out the official
ornamentals course
if you're not already
comfortable with nasty ass that is.
In this extension.
Will assume that you're
familiar with everything
we've covered in that
fundamentals course
let's go ahead and get started.