Along with traditional
object oriented hierarchies
another popular way of building up
classes from reusable components
is to build them by combining
simpler partial classes.
This is known as
the mix and patter.
May already be familiar with the concept of
mixins or traits from languages like scala
but the mixon pattern
has also gained some pop
clarity in the javascript
community as well.
Mixins provide a form of code reuse
that is based on composing behavior.
Flexibility gained
from using make sense
becomes apparent once
you start composing room.
The class.
Hint include as many
mixins as you want
as opposed to inheritance
which can only
inherit from one class.
Now that we understand
the basics of mix sense
let's dive into some code to see
some practicals use cases for them
that we might need in
our future applications.
Using the next
seal i let's generate a new mixing
class and call it with you you ID.
Placing it within a
common slash mixins fallen.
Know it will end the file with dot
mixon as well just for clarity's sake.
Let's open up this
newly generated file
and paste the following code which
can be found below the course video.
As we can see here
the with you you ID mixon.
We created generate
a random you ID and a.
It to the you you ID property.
We could have also
declared methods
and even a constructor
here if we wanted to
more on that in a moment.
The function here accepts a parameter
called base of the generic type tea bags.
In strain to be compatible
with type from nastiest common.
Type your represents
something that can be constructed
meaning a class.
Within the body of the function.
We create in return a
new class that derives from
the base class that has
passed into the function.
Note that the class keyword is not
followed by a name although it could be
but this name would only be
useful locally within the classes body.
Just so the class could refer to itself if
let's say for example we wanted to access
some static
properties of the class.
All right so with all the
place let's run
some experiments.
As navigate to the
coffee class ass
enlist declare a
constructive there.
Below the class.
Let's declare a new coffee
with you you ID sea ice variable
and make it equal
to with your you ID.
Passing and coffee.
Using this new class.
That's instantiate a new coffee
with view ID sea ice instance
in assign it to eight
new coffee variable.
Now if we access coffee
and hit dot
will see to
available properties.
The name property
we created within
our coffee class itself
and you ID
which came from our mixon.
Which we can see is now
easily available here as well.
Just for demonstration purposes
as navigate to the with
you i defunct and again
and add a new
method they're named
regenerate you you ID.
The code for which can be found
below the course video as always.
Let's save our changes.
At back to the coffee file
hit dot again
we can see that are ID he now
includes that method as well fantastic.
Hopefully you're starting to see the
power and potential so far with make sense.
Now that we understand
the mixins concept we can
look into it a bit more
ness j a specific use case.
Now for demonstration purposes
as generate a new pipe using the
nastiest seal i ain't caught entity exists.
Let's open up this
newly generated pipe
and renamed the class to
entity exists pipe sea eyes.
Now.
Let's wrap this
class with a function
using the original entity
exists pipe as a name.
And let's make sure to
remove the export keyword.
From the entity exist
pipe sea ice class
and move that export
to the outer function.
Below the class declaration.
Let's add a return statement
returning the inner class.
And last but not least.
As at the return type to our function so
the era we're seeing right now goes away.
Setting it to type.
Of pipe transform.
So far so good.
Next up
let's add an input argument to our
function named entity sea ice of type
type.
Using this parameter
let's inject the corresponding repository
provider into our entity exists pipe
using the following syntax.
Know that since we are not
using and r m in this lesson.
Will just use this
inline random tight
but generally in
your application.
This would most likely represent
a repository provided by and r m.
Whether it's type r m
mongoose micro or m
prisma or something else.
We're just keeping things simple to
focus on learning the main concept here.
Lastly.
Let's flag our transform method as a sink
and add the following instruction and side.
Remember that this is all pseudo code
and our case where just assuming that and
exists method is exposed by
and or m specific repository here.
Hopefully
you get the idea of what
we're trying to do either way.
Now with everything in place.
To navigate to our
coffees controller.
If we look at the
update method there
we could see that it
takes two parameters.
ID of the coffee to be updated
and the payload.
Let's by this newly created
entity exist pipe to the ID puram
and since it's a mixon now.
You can pass the coffee energy
class as an input parameter.
And voila
we've managed to utilize
mixins to help us bro errors in
a specific case where an
entity does or does not exist.
This was all merely
for example sake
but you can imagine how using
mixins might be very beneficial in certain
circumstances you'll run into
in your future nest applications.
Before we finish
let's make sure we
comment that line out
as it was all pseudo code since we
don't have an rm set up in our application.