A schematic is a template based code
generator that is a set of instructions for
transforming a
software project by either
generating or modifying coat.
The angular
kit schematics were introduced by
the angler team and twenty eighteen.
However
even though the schematics
were developed by the angler
team and despite the word
angular being in the name.
Any one could still
use them in any sense
to generate any type of code.
As they are platform
independent.
The you could technically generate
anything whether it's ness jas
react
vue etc.
He could utilize the schematics to enforce
architectural rules and conventions making
our projects consistent
and injure operatives.
Or we could create schematics to
help us generate commonly used coat
shared services modules
interfaces health
checks docker files etc.
For a more real world example.
With the help of schematics we could reduce
the amount of time we might need to set
up all the boilerplate for creating a
new microservice within our organization
by creating a
microservice schematic.
A generates all the common
cold loggers tools etc.
We might commonly used in
our organizations microservices.
As you can hopefully see
the use cases and applications
for creating our own custom
schematics can be endless.
In fact.
We've already used schematics multiple
times as a part of this course extension
as that's exactly what the nastiest
seal i use us under the hood.
All the generators we
executed in previous lessons.
Weather we've been generating
modules controllers or pipes
were just simple predefined
schematics coming
from the nes j slash
schematics package.
In the next lesson will implement
a custom schematic ourselves
which internally will execute the
existing ness Jess module schematic
and afterwards
generate a module definition
file that uses the configurable
module builder we
presented in a previous lesson.
As an added bonus.
Will set up the schematic to automatically
update the module class to extend the
configurable class exported
from the module definition.
Of all that sounds like a
lot right now don't worry.
We'll be going through everything
step by step in the next lesson.