Get started with creating
our own custom schematics
let's create a blank
schematics project
using the angular delicate
schematic see alive.
We're going to be using and px here but know
that alternatively you could install the
angular Jeff kit schematic
steel i packaged globally
and refer to it as schematics
instead of using and px if you prefer.
As for the name of our project
which was schematics but
if you want to use something
else that's totally fine.
Just make sure to put the
output a project in the schematics
or tools directory so it doesn't get
mixed up with your actual code base.
Rate.
A blank schematic we used.
Rates either a new project or adds a
blank schematic to an existing project.
He can actually
be used for by both.
Before we proceed.
What's open of rts
config build jaison file
and add the schematics folder to
the exclude configuration property.
This the make sure it doesn't get
built alongside our applications coat.
With our boilerplate generated.
Us navigate to this newly created schematics
folder and before we continue let's
install the schematics
slashed angular package
as will need it later
on in this lesson.
Once the installation
is complete.
Inside the source directory we can
see a new collection that Jason file.
The collection da Jason file
is the main definition file for the entire
schematics library in contains definitions
of all the schematics
available in that library.
Well as we create more schematics
this file will have all of them listed out.
We can see that our project
currently contains one schematic
with the name schematics
which might be quite confusing.
Let's rename it to
configurable dash module.
Also as we can
see it points to the
dot slash schematics slashed
index file a more specifically to the
pound schematics
function within that file.
Must change the directory name
to be configurable dash module.
Endless was changed the name of
the function to be generate as well
as it makes a little more sense in
context of what we will be building.
And lastly within this file
let's make sure we also update
the description to be
generates a configurable module.
Excellent.
Next let's open up the index file located
in the source slashed schematics folder
and update the name of
the function to be January.
As that's what we change
it to and our schema file.
So far
we can see that this
is a simple factory it
takes and options
argument and returns a rule
which takes in a tree
and returns it back unchanged.
The options argument here is an object that
can be seen as the input of the factory
and based on those properties lets us
determined the behavior of that factor.
And schematics.
Virtual file system is
represented as a treat.
A tree data structure contains a
base or a set of files that already exists.
As well as a staging area.
Does a list of changes
to be applied to that base.
When making modifications we don't actually
change the base itself but add those
modifications to
the staging area.
A rule object
the finds a function
that takes a tree.
Applies transformations.
More on transformations
in a moment
and it returns ain't new tree.
The main file for a schematic
which is that index t s file
the finds a set of rules that
implement the schematics logic.
Transformation is
represented by an action.
For which there
are four action types.
Create.
Rename
overripe and elite.
Each schematic runs in a context
represented by a schematic context object.
All right so now that we understand the
major building blocks of schematics let's
learn how things work by
calling an external schematic.
The nes.
Module schematic
and see what happens.
In the code shown here
we are using the external
schematic function to
refer to an outside schematic
in composing its rules
onto our customs schematic.
We also pass the options
object in but for now
were temporarily marketing
the name of the module to be
placeholder instead of it
being passed and via user input.
Also make sure to notice the
chain function call were using here
which lets us combine multiple
rules if we need that ability.
Currently
we only have one rule
for calling chain is not
require but eventually
we're going to add other custom operations
applied here so we'll add those later on.
Lastly.
Let's prefix the tree parameter name with
underscore just instruct typescript that
this argument is intentionally
unused for the time being.
Otherwise the typescript
compiler would throw an error at us
when building the schematic.
Rizzo now let's save our
changes and before we test
everything out let's rename
the inner schematics folder name
be configurable dash module.
Reflect our configuration file.
Now let's open up our terminals and and
a separate terminal window navigate to the
schematics directory
with cd schematics.
Then let's run
and p m run build.
Dash dash dash dash watch to
build our schematics in watch mode.
Once it's complete
let's which to the original terminal
window in execute the schematic with the
following command you can find
below the course video was always.
Remember that
instead of using and px
we could have installed the
angular delicate schematic
seal like globally or
locally within our project.
All right so
as we can see in our console are
schematic executed in debug mode.
Debug mode results in
the same behavior as if
we ran into schematic
with the dry run flag.
Meaning that no changes
get permitted to the file system.
Instead
we are shown the create
update delete statuses of
files that will be affected
with our schematic.
To turn debug mode off we could just pass
the dash dash debug equals false flag but
since our schematic
is not ready yet.
Let's wait to try this later on.
Otherwise things look just as we could have
expected a new module named placeholder.
Would have been generated
and the app module files
would be updated as well.
The external nest
module schematic is doing
everything we could
have expected it to do do
rate.
So we already know how to
execute external schematics but now.
How can we accept parameters
to control our schematic.
Well first
let's navigate to the
collection Jason file in
at a new property to our
schematic called schema.
Make equal to configurable dash
module slashed schema that jaison.
Next let's create that scheme a file in
the configurable dash module directory.
Inside this file
what's paste the
following schema.
Like always
you can find the code
here below the course video.
Alright let's break things
down here at step by step.
The dollar schema key points to
the jaison schema defining this format.
It is used by i didn't used
to do auto-completion
tools for validation and
it is entirely optional.
ID is a unique ID for this
scheme and the collection.
Type is a descriptor for the
type provided by the properties
object in our case.
Let's focus on the
most important part here.
Properties object.
This object defines the available
options for our schematic.
Each option associates
a key with a type
description and
of original alias.
The dollar default parameters tells us
that it will assume that the first argument
given to this command is the
value for the name property.
The type defines the shape
of the value we expect.
In the description
is displayed when the user
requests usage help for a schematic.
You could check out the angler documentation
for additional customization for
schematic of options
link below the video.
Here we specified that the
required property his name.
Which determines the name
of the module to be generated.
Will pass this option down to the underlying
external nastiest modul schematic.
The show everything
working here at full circle.
Not that you could of course at as
many other properties as you need here
and creating schematics were just keeping
things simple for learning purposes.
But save our changes open up our
terminals and run the schematic again.
So as we can see the
schematic seal i now prompts us
for the name that we want
for the module will create.
However
since we haven't updated
the actual schematic.
You can see that it still tries to
generate the police holder module
instead of a module
with the name we specify.
To fix this.
Let's open up the index js file
again and start by declaring a new
configured module
schematic options interface.
Next let's up the degenerate function
signature to instead of using the type
any for options
to use our newly
created interface.
And lastly instead of passing
the hard-coded placeholder string.
Let's pass down the
options dot name value.
But save our changes
again open up our
terminals and run that
schematic will more time
entering the name of recipes.
And voila as we can see a generated
the recipes module now perfect.
All right for the next step
let's update our generator to also generate
the module definition alongside the
module t s file
that gets create.
Were achieved this.
Inside of are configurable
dash modules schematic folder
let's create another directory
and caught files.
We have to use the files
folder name because it will
be excluded from the
typescript compilation by default
check the t s config Jason in
the root of the project for more.
This folder
has to be excluded because we do
not want to compile these template files.
You'll see why
and just a moment.
Let's add one more nested
folder inside of the files folder
with the name
underscore underscore
name at dash
eyes
underscore underscore.
The w underscores is a
delimiter which separates the
name variable from the
rest of the normal string.
Dasher ice here
is a helper function
which will receive the
value of the name variable
in converted to a
kebab case stream.
And lastly
the at symbol here
is a way of applying variables
to help her function so in our case
were passing name
and to dash rats.
Inside that folder
let's create a file.
Named w underscore name at dash
eyes
w underscore.
That module dash definition that t s
and paste the following code inside.
I see
the code here is our
regular template for configure
will modules we covered
in a previous lesson.
Our goal is to auto generate
that file alongside the module file.
Now onto our schematic function.
Said the following code to make
sure includes this new folder and file.
And let's break everything
down here line by line again.
Dot slash files is the location
of the files we want to include.
Options.
Is the options pass
into our schematic.
And strings is a
collection of utility functions
such as dash eyes which
we used just a moment ago
provided by the
delicate schematics.
The template method
generates our template based on
those options and string
utilities passed down to her.
Next up we are going
to call the move method
to move those files to a desired location
which and our case is the so source folder.
Once we have the
template source.
We can add it to the chain
using the merge with function.
Merge with merges and input
tree with these source passed in.
Remember all this is happening
within the trees staged environment
to try to keep that in mind and think
of what has happened there already
in what your desired outcome is
whenever you're building schematics.
Let's save our changes.
Open up our terminals
and run schematic again.
And voila.
As we can see
we have a new module dash name that
module dash definition file auto generated
rate.
The last step we
need is to configure our
schematic to automatically
import that definition
into our module class and
also make this class extend.
The configurable module class.
This part is going to be
the most tricky one yet
as will have to operate
on the typescript as tea
or abstract syntax
tree directly.
Luckily we can leverage
some of the existing as
to utilities provided by
the angler schematics
which had helped make
things somewhat easier.
Now that we will be using
quite a bit of advanced
schematic utilities and methods
and tools here from now on.
It's difficult to explain
every aspect but hopefully
once it's all piece together
you have a good
understanding of what's what
and how things are
all tied together here.
So let's start by
adding a new function
called update module file
that takes two parameters
tree
and the options object and then let's
return the modified tree object back.
Inside this function.
Let's start by
defining to constance.
Name
which is a dash
your eyes the name
and module file path which is
the path to the mall agile file.
Next using the tree
object let's retrieve the
module foul content
with the read text method.
Using module filepath
and module foul content
as construct a new
typescript source file.
Let's also make sure
we import the typescript
compiler Apia itself
using import star as ts.
Just to make sure we're
using the same version
of typescript the
schematic utility support.
Back to our function
with all that in place we
can begin updating our tree.
First
let's call the tree dot
begin update method.
Passing and module
filepath as an argument.
Next up will use the
insert import utility function
exported from the schematics
slash angler slash utility.
Lush as t
dashed you tells package.
Passing and for arguments.
Typescript source file.
Or module filepath.
The item to import which is
configurable module class in our case nice.
And the path to the file we
want to import the item from.
As insert import returns
a generic change object
we have to check if it's an
instance of import change.
And if so
using the update recorder
and it's insert right method.
We can insert a new line at the
insert import change that pos position.
With the insert in poor
changed up to add content.
Know that to at is just a
simple generated string
we want to insert in our case.
Lastly after the if condition let's commit
the update using the commit update method
of the tree object
passing an update
recorder as an argument.
Just a test everything out
what's also add a console logging.
In before we finish
just make sure we actually
use dysfunction so scroll
down to generate an ad
update module file to the chain.
Great.
Make sure we save our changes open up
our terminals and run the schematic again.
And voila as we can
see in the console.
Our new import was
added successfully
fantastic.
Last but not least.
We have to make sure
they're module class actually
extends the configurable
module class we just important.
Over this.
Let's first retrieve the class declaration
note using the find nodes utility function
from anglers utilities.
Here
we're passing the typescript
source file as the first argument
and the syntax kind or the type of a know
that we're looking for as the second one.
Also as this function returns an array of
notes and and our case where a hundred per
cent sure there's exactly
one class in that file.
We can simply
retrieved the first element.
With a re zero.
Will make sure to handle
things accordingly here
when building your own
schematics in the future.
Now it's update our file.
Let's use the update
recorder to insert right again
and for the first argument
we need to pass in the position
indicating where we
need to put that new string.
Since we know that our classes empty
meaning it doesn't have any methods.
We can just take the and
property of the class note minus two
to get the desired position
to right before the brackets.
Know that this might not always be the
case for whatever you might be building and
future schematics
so just keep in mind.
You might need a little different logic
here this was implemented on let's say a
existing modules that a
user might already have
a code base.
Where the second
argument let's passed a
stringer want to insert
their which is extends
configurable module class.
And that's it.
Let's remove the console log
save our changes open up our
terminals again and run the schematic.
This time
let's pass in.
Dash dash debug eagles false to actually
apply the schematic to our project.
And voila
if we look.
We can see we have our recipes folder
created with both the module definition file
and our recipes module x attending
are generated configurable module class
fantastic.
Although things might have gotten a bit
overwhelming near the end of this lesson as
we started to really deep dive into some
advanced schematic use cases in utilities.
Hopefully you can see the power
and abilities you could have when working
on schematics for your own organization.
Whether it's generating libraries
microservices etc with batteries included.
Bill with of the important but boilerplate
code that your organization needs
or maybe you need a schematic
to handle something else important
the sky's the limit.
More inspiration
check out how the nest seal icicle medics
are built themselves to get some ideas on
how to handle other
tricky scenarios.