Every nestorius js application
has at least one module
a route module.
The route module
is the starting point nest users
to build the application graph.
Which is the internal data structure
that nest users to resolve module
and provider relationships
and dependencies.
In this directed graph
in which the edges
heavy direction.
Every module is a effectively
represented as a single node
importing another
module or node.
Instructs the nest framework to create an
edge between these two points in the graph.
Although this graph
is statically scoped
and doesn't get recreated
over time meaning that only a
single instance spends the
entire applications life cycle
it is possible that it may
contain modules or nodes.
The register non
statically scope providers
specifically
request scope providers.
Requests scoped providers get instantiated
dynamically upon receiving a signal.
In terms of for
example rest a p eyes.
This signal would
be an http request.
However
for things like cron jobs this signal
will be the invocation of the job itself.
You can see that when it comes to how
requests go providers are invoked it really
depends on the context
of an individual application.
In reaction to that signal.
Know she has constructs a so
called dependency injection subtree
that's associated
with a given signal.
For instance
where an incoming http request
it instantiates a new controller
that declares a specific route.
This instance
is created exclusively
for that particular request
and will be removed when the
request processing has completed.
And this lesson will showcase
how you can manually
construct and manager one
dependency injection subtrees
using the power of
the module ref class.
So
let's switch to r ID
and using the nes jsc ally let's
generate a new resource called tax.
With this resource of place.
As navigate to the auto
generated tax service class
and make it request
scoped passing and scoped
out request object to
the injectable decorator.
As we already learned
in the fundamental scores.
Scopes actually bubble
up the injection chain
this means that if the
tags controller depends
on the tax service which
is now request scope.
It implicitly becomes
request scope as well.
All right next up was
opened the tags module file
and inject the module ref provider
using the standard approach.
Let's also make the tags
module class implement
the an application
bootstrap life cycle hook.
Our ID
should prompt us to implement
the interface lets go ahead and do it.
Inside of this an application
bootstrap method.
As dynamically resolve the
request scope tag service
provider using the module
rough in it's resolve method
and let's console
log that serve as out.
Know that this resolve method may come in
handy when testing requests go providers in
the future so always
try to keep it a mind.
Let's save our changes.
Open up our terminals
and as we can see here
are tag service was instantiate
properly just as we should expect.
Great.
Back to our task at hand.
Let's talk about what
exactly happened here.
So what the module ref dot
resolve method does under the hood
is that it internally constructs a
dedicated dependency injection sub tree.
Where our tax service is
the root note of that tree.
This sub tree has its own unique contexts
identifier that represents that true.
Who better understand that.
Let's create two copies
of the tag service provider
calling resolve twice and
comparing their references.
And as we can see in our
terminals they are in fact not equal.
To as we've mentioned
above the resolve method
returns a unique
instance of the provider
from its own diy
container subtree.
These instances are not equal
as they belong
to different trees.
To generate a single instance
across multiple resolve calls
in ensure are they share the same
generated DEA container subtree.
We can pass a context
identifier to the resolve method.
First.
Let's use the context idea factory
class to generate a context identifier.
This class provides
a create method.
Returns inappropriate
unique identifier.
And with this context
idea and place.
Let's pass it in as the second for
diameter of the resolved invocations.
And if we save our changes
and take a look at our
terminals again we'll
see that are instances
are now equal hence true.
Great.
All right
so we already know how
to generate context ids
ids that represent our subtrees and
the actual DEA subtrees using either a
specific contexts ID or
the auto generate one.
We also know that
request scope providers can
inject a request object
acre a signal payload
is associated
with the host the i sub tree.
So for demonstration purposes.
As navigate to the tax service
class an eject the request there.
It's also make sure to
console log the request out.
Next let's switch back
to the tags module file
and to make things simpler
let's make sure we create only
one instance of the tax service.
And now for demonstration purposes let's
register a request payload for our sub tree
using the register request by
contacts ID method as follows.
But save our changes.
Open up our terminals and voila.
There's our request object
acre a signal payload that
successfully associated
with the host the i sub tree.
Lastly
just a few more important
notes about the context ids.
In fact a context ID is just a
regular unique javascript object.
Nest jazz associates sub to these
with their corresponding ID objects
and if the context ID
gets garbage collected
so does the entire dui sub tree.
That meets the eye
subtrees are ephemeral
meaning that they are removed as
soon as or context ideas garbage collected.
Just keep in mind that if you keep track of
the contexts ID for example by storing it
in the static array or
any other collection.
The subtree
associated with that context
object will never get removed.
It so now that we have an understanding
of the basic mechanics of DEA subtrees.
Let's dive into a bit more
practical example in the next lesson.