Now that we understand how
dependency injection aka DEA subtrees work
let's build something a bit more complex
so we can get a better understanding
how and when we could use the i some trees
to benefit our real world applications.
This lesson.
Gonna use the nastiest
event a metre package
which provides a simple
observer implementation
that allows us to
subscribe endless and for
various events that
occur in our applications.
Events serve as a great way to decouple
various aspects of our application.
That a single event can
have multiple listeners
that do not depend
on each other.
To get started.
A support of our
terminals and installed the
nest year slash event
dash a mirror dependency.
Once the installation
process is complete.
As open up our app module
a registered the
event a metre module.
Next up using the
nastiest the ally
must generate a new
payments module.
Let's also generate the payments
webhook controller inside of that module.
Know that we're passing
the flat flag here just to
instruct the nestle i to not
create another nested payments
dash webhook director.
With all this and place let's open
up the newly generated controller
and add a simple get route just
for the demonstration purposes.
With this endpoint of place
that subject the event emitter to
class using the standard approach.
We need this class in
order to dispatch events.
Before we can proceed.
We need to declare the payment failed
event class that will use in this lesson.
So inside of the
payments folder.
Let's create a new
directory called events.
And in this directory
let's create a new file
named payment dash
failed the event that t s.
Inside of this file.
Let's define the fallen class you
can find below the course video.
This event will represent a
failed possibly rejected payment.
It exposes the static key property
that will use to identify the event.
And takes to input arguments.
Payment ID
which is a unique ID that
represents that failed payment.
And meta object that
will dive into later on.
Now.
Let's declare event hand
slurs or event listeners that
will subscribe to the payment
failed event occurrence
and will process
according accordingly.
It's open up our terminals and generate
a new service called notifications service.
Normally we generated
in a separate module
but since we want to
keep things simple here
we'll just use the
payments module for now.
Also
let's generate another
subscription service class in
the same module using
the nest the ally once again.
Both services
will listen to the
payment failed event
and will perform relevant
corresponding actions.
Let's start with the
notification service
open it up and declare a new
send payment notification method.
Register this method
as an event subscriber.
Let's use the an event decorator
passing the payment failed event
duck key as an input parameter.
Great.
Let's follow the same steps
for the subscription service.
At a new
cancel subscription method an
annotated with the same decorator.
Now there's one limitation
you should be aware of here.
Events subscribers cannot be request
scope by definition since thus can't really
tracked down what
service controller
triggered the events as that would be
against the loose coupling capabilities
the events provide us with.
Excellent.
The last but not least
let's switch back to our
payment webhooks control solar
and dispatch a random
payment failed event
with the webhook endpoint handler
just to the contest everything out.
Right let's save our changes.
Open up our terminals and
in a separate terminal window.
Was triggered the slash payments
webhook endpoint using curl.
Now let's switch or the
other terminal window and
as we can see both event
subscribers were trigger
excellent.
Alright
so we already know how to emit
and asynchronously process events.
We are also aware of the
event subscribers limitations.
As they can't be requests scope.
So now what if we actually
want to use a dynamic
requests go provider from
within the event handler.
How can we access the
original color request object
without polluting our
event class even further
and explicitly passing it
through the constructor.
What if we have a request scoped lager
that would like to leverage inside of our
events subscribers or many
other real world examples as.
Luckily
we can overcome this limitation with use
of module rough and our knowledge of DEA
subtrees that we covered
in the previous lesson.
Let's open up our payments webhook controller
and first modify the webhook method
signature to take the
request as an argument.
Next up using the
context ID factory
a generate a new context ID
as we did in the previous lesson.
Next.
Inject the module refusing
the standard approach.
And must make sure we also register that
request object for the given d i sub true.
And lastly
let's update the context i
do that we pass as an input
parameter to our event
constructor to be context ID
instead of no.
Perfect.
Let's save our changes
and before we continue
let's create a new requests go provider
that will represent our event context.
Inside the payments directory.
Let's create a new
contexts folder and it's out of
this folder let's create
the events contexts file.
Inside of this file
was paste the fallen content that
you could find below the course video.
So basically this class will
serve as our event context
that provides us with
the caller request object.
It's also not forget to register this class
as a provider in our payments module.
With his provider register.
Us navigate to our notification service
and first inject the module rough rider
using the standard approach.
Inside of our send
payment notification method.
Let's retrieve the event context
object using the event dot Meadow
up context ID
and let's lock
down as you are up.
Let's repeat the same steps in
our subscription service as well.
Once finished let's
save all of our changes.
Open up our terminals
and triggered the webhook
and point once again.
And as we can see
both subscribers
can now access
the request object
and could share the
same DEA subtree
rate.
Though in this lesson we only use
the request provider as an example
but you could actually resolve any
requests go provider you wish or neat.
Furthermore.
The using the same context
ID and both subscribers
if you Rick quest a let's say
request scope lager instance
as we mentioned earlier.
It will only be created once
and share between
all event handlers.
Hopefully you can see the multitude of use
cases and possibilities available to you
now with his new DEA
subtree superpower.