Requests go providers can
sometimes lead to increased latency
since we're having at least
one request to go provider
injected into let's say a
controller instance or deeper
inject into one
of its providers.
Makes the controller
request scoped as well.
That means it must be
recreated or instantiated
for each individual request an
garbage collected afterwards.
For instance for thirty thousand requests
in parallel there will be thirty thousand
ephemeral instances
of the controller
and it's requests go providers.
Having a common
provider that most providers
depend on for example
a database connection.
Automatically converts all those
providers to requests go providers as well.
As compose a challenge and
multi-tenant applications for for example
especially for those the have a central
request scope data source provider
that grabs headers tokens
from their quest object
and based on those values
retrieves the corresponding
database connection schema
specific to that tenant.
For instance
let's say you have an application
alternately used by ten different customers.
Each customer could have
its own dedicated dataset arts
and you want to
make sure customer a
will never be able to reach
customer bees database.
One way to achieve this could
be to declare a request scope data
provider
a based on the request object
determines who the current customers
and retrieves it's
corresponding database
but
as we said a major downside
to this approach is that
since most likely a large
chunk of your applications
opponents
rely on the data source provider
it will implicitly become
request scoped as well
and therefore you will undoubtedly
see an impact in your apps performance.
But
what if we had
a better solution.
Let's say that we only
have ten customers can we
have ten individual DEA
subtrees per customer.
Instead of recreating
each tree per request.
Well if your providers don't rely
on any property that's truly unique
for each consecutive request
for example request view
ids but instead there are
some specific attributes
that led us aggregate them.
The we have no reason to recreate the
DEA subtree on every incoming request.
This is exactly where durable
providers come in handy.
In the next two lessons will show you how
to leverage durable provider futures when
implementing to
common use cases.
Internationalization
and multi-tenancy.