Multi-tenancy
is an architecture in which a single
instance of a software application
serves multiple tenants
or customers.
Each tenant.
As its own set of data
as a major security concern is data
partitioning across accounts or tenants.
For example
users from tenant a should not be
able to access data from tenant be
advice for ursa.
The most common use case for multi-tenant
systems are sas based applications
which was different
levels of data isolation.
Depending on the
domain of the application.
Let's start by going through the most common
techniques for blending multi-tenancy.
In the silo strategy.
Where have a separate
database instance per tenant.
This approach provides
a strict data separation at
the expense of both
higher infrastructure costs.
Any more complicated tenants set up because
you will have to provision and manage a
new database instance for each
tenant the onboard your sas offering.
The nature of a single-tenant
silo means you're never
sharing resources but as
we mentioned of course.
This comes with
price and concerns.
In the pool model.
All tenants share one
database instance.
In this approach.
Data for all the
customers said side by side
but each table or view
contains a partitioning g
usually the tenant
identifier aka a tenant ID
which we used to
filter the data by.
The pool model uses
resources more efficiently
save the most an
operational costs
a reduces your
infrastructure overhead.
On the other hand
there's no separation
of tenant data
and there's a risk that
data may lead to other
customers if we forget
to apply the query filter
whether it's an additional where
clause or a local per transaction variable.
And lastly the bridge strategy.
In this approach we
share the same database
instance but use a different
schema for each tenant.
Scheme us are technically
the same for all tenants
the same tables and
constraint definitions for all
but they remain
isolated from each other.
This strategy makes
sense if you have a few high
value tenants using
your busy mr business sas
otherwise you might
be best using the pulling
strategy augmented with
rls or row level security.
Regardless of which
approach you choose
for your application but will
showcase in the next lesson
should be helpful to
understand how durable providers
can benefit
your future multi-tenant
ness js applications.