Another we have a good understanding
of what multi-tenancy is and the different
techniques we can use to
apply them in our systems.
Let's kick things off
by switching to our ID.
Opening up our terminals and generating
a new module named data source
using the not see alot.
But also generate a
data source service that
we will configure it to
be requested scoped.
This provider will
represent a database or data
source connection any
real world application.
And lastly before
we continue onwards
must generate a new users
resource that we will use
for demonstration purposes
throughout this lesson.
With all that in place.
As navigate to the newly generated
data source service class and first
exposure to flagged
as requests scoped.
Next.
Let's inject the
request payload into our
class constructor using
the inject decorated.
Know that for now we'll just use
unknown as the type as this context payload
will differ depending on whether the service
class is registered as durable are not.
Necklace navigate to
the data source module file
it make sure that the date
source service provider
is exported from this module.
But this module and place.
Just navigate to the user's
service regenerated a minute ago
and eject the data source service provider
they're using the standard approach.
Let's also make sure
to console log this
wiki debug it later
on in our terminals.
To make the data source service
available in the context of users module
as make sure we add the
corresponding important.
Perfect.
Their application
running in the background
let's open of our terminals
and use curl to trigger
get http request to the
slash users endpoint.
Next
let's switch to the
other terminal window
and as we can see their
the data source service
was logged to our consul
containing the
actual request object
as a request context
dependency great.
So far we made our data
service request scoped.
And we also injected the request
object through the constructed
but none of this was new year
we learned about the requests go
providers in the fundamentals course.
Through durable providers
come into play here.
Well as we mentioned
in the previous lesson.
Durable providers are similar to requests
go providers as they're both dynamic.
The differences
requests go providers by
diff fault are instantiated
per each request.
While with durable
providers we can control
under which conditions
they become durable.
In fact durable providers
are just a subtype of requests go
providers with one essential difference.
While requests go providers
are tied to the request life cycle.
Terrible providers lifecycle can
be controlled and managed by us.
All right so back to
our task at hand what's
navigate to the data
source provider again
and let's flagged as durable
passing the durable Colin true
sure injectable decorator.
Also before we continue further.
Something to always keep in mind
custom providers can be durable as well.
Art back to our task.
Let's know that
similar to request scoped.
Durability bubbles up through
the injection chains well.
That means if user
service depends on data
source service which
has flagged as durable.
User service implicitly
becomes durable to
on less durable is
explicitly set to false for
user service provider
which right now it is not.
All right with our first
herbal provider and place
what's though configured
the strategy for managing their
riders in our system.
Where this let's create
a new core folder.
In inside of this folder.
Create a new file called
aggregate by tenant strategy
that ts.
Inside this file
was kicked things
off by declaring a new
aggregate by tenant
context ID strategy class
and make a implement the
context ID strategy interface.
Are i do he should prompt us
to auto implement the interface
lets go ahead and do it.
Next.
A stickler a new private
property called tenants.
This collection will hold tenant
ids and their associated context ids.
Don't we learned about context ID
in the diving into DEA subtrees lesson
this context at he represents our
manually created de-ice of true.
As we're using
express in this course.
Has also update the type of the request
parameter to be request from express package.
Depending on what
we want to accomplish
there are different strategies for
associating request with specific tenants.
For example the tenant ID could
be encoded in the jwt payload.
Or
you could have a
proxy in front of our a p i.
Would attach the
corresponding x tenant ID header.
Even simpler if the
communication is internal meeting
between private services
running in an internal cluster.
In that case.
You could just manually
attached that header
to every request been
calling another service.
In this lesson
will be aggregating request by x
ID
had her values
but know that the
implementation won't differ much
depending on which
approach you end up taking.
All right so back to our task.
A start by retrieving that x
tenant ID value from the header
and if it's undefined
has just returned the
original context ID object.
Next let's declare a new
local tenant subtree ID variable
that will represent our contexto de
object for the given tenant DEA subtree
and chug of our collection
already has such a key.
If so
let's retrieve their value and assign
it to the tenant sub tree ID variable.
Otherwise let's construct
a new context ID object
and added to the collection.
And last but not least.
Was returned the
context resolver object.
Depending on whether
the tree is durable or not
we return either the tenants
specific context ID object
or the original parent one.
Also we specified the payload object
that holds the tenant i do property.
This payload will be registered
as per the i sub treat request object.
Finally.
Was up open up our app module file
and apply this newly defined strategy.
Note that we could have applied this elsewhere
as well we just picked up module as it
seems to be the most
suitable as were applying
everything globally in our
application and our case
but you may want or need to do
things differently in your system.
With this and place.
Let's open up our terminals
and use curl again and
execute the http request
to the slash users endpoint.
This time passing in the
x dash tenant dash ID header.
Of one just for
our demo purpose.
Now
a switch or the
other terminal window
and as we can see
even though he triggered
this endpoint multiple
time times the user
service instance was created
only once.
More importantly.
Once per tenant
fantastic.
Also we can see that the request context
is now equal to the payload we specified
in are accustomed
context ID strategy.
Now just to verify and double check
that everything works as it should.
Let's call us and point again
changing the x ten and ID
header to be a different value.
And voila.
As we can see
what we did lets us construct
separate DEA trees per tenant.
For example
we could have our
application set up to have
separate type r ram or
mongers connection per tenant.
Or any other
multi-tenant situations
may need for your different
tenants in your system.
The sky's the limit from here.
Now before we
wrap up this lesson
there's one future would
like to demonstrate as well.
Let's open up our strategy file
and after inserting a new context
i do you to our tenants collection.
That at a time out
and invalidate meaning
let's remove that key
of after three seconds.
But save our changes open up
our terminals and use curl again.
Wait at least three
seconds and called the same
and point again passing
the same tenant ID.
Now let's wish to our other terminal window
and as we can see after three seconds our
d i saw trigger
invalidated and recreated
when we hit our
application again a worked.
Great.
So we covered quite
a lot in this lesson.
But in summary although
we just marked out certain
things like data source
connections etc in our case.
Hopefully you can see
with everything we've set up we could
have separate instances now per ten.
Each doing different
things if needed.
Whether it's separate
connections scheme us pretended.
Or dedicated repository
data access class does
that automatically assigned
tenant ID with were clauses etc.
Now that you know how to implement the
basics of multi tenants in your applications.
The sky's the limit for your future
nest apps and their use cases.