Internationalization typically
abbreviated as i eighteen in
is the process of
designing an application
that it can be adapted to
various languages and regions.
Adding support for more
languages currencies etc
shouldn't require project
implementation tweaks
and depending on the
implementation whether
reload translations
statically or dynamically
we should be able to
modify translations on the fly
but that means
is textual elements
such just status messages
error messages etc
should not be hard-coded
but instead
pulled from a specific
translation file or source
relevant to a user's region.
Is allows for an incredibly
flexible system where a user
could ask for something in a
certain language currency etc oh
and get it returned back
to them in that format.
Now when it comes to
internationalization there
are a lot of libraries we
could use in our apps
i eighteen an
eye eighteen next.
Sjs dash eighteen n etc.
And whether you choose one of those or just
decide to implement something on your own
really depends on what
complex features your app
requires and of course
how much time you have.
In this lesson
will implement a very basic mechanism
by ourselves just to avoid pulling another
library and making
our application prone
to potential breaking changes
that could be introduced.
By third party
packages in the future.
However
to make our lives at least a little bit
easier and focus on the task at hand.
Will be installing
to utility packages.
The first being a
except language parser
which parses the except
language hunter from and http
request and produces an
array of a language objects
sorted by quality
and string format
which is a small javascript
library for formatting strings
that accepts named properties.
All right.
Let's head over to r ID
open up our terminals
and install both is packages.
Once everything's installed.
Us generate a new i eighteen and
module using the necessary osceola.
Also as generate a
corresponding service.
Let's open up this newly generated module
and start by making sure we export that new
i eighteen and service said it's
available to our other providers.
Next up in the source directory
let's create and assets folder
and inside of this folder
another directory
called locales.
In this folder
will create two files.
E n dot Jason for our default
language which will be English
and pl that jaison for
another language Polish.
And side both files let's
paste the following content.
In the e n Jason
file hello hello
and in the pl Jason
file hollow sash.
As we can see
we have to translations
so far and each
translation file contains
one key which is hello.
This is just for demonstration
purposes of course but if you're new to
internationalization in these files you
would have all of your key values for
everything you need
translated in your system.
As we mentioned earlier
this can be specific success
error messages prompts
general ai responses
anything and everything that
would be important for
you to have translated.
Let's also make sure we
update our ts config js on file.
Setting resolve jaison
module to true which lets us
import Jason modules from
within typescript the modules.
Now onto our
eighteen and service.
There by adding three imports.
Note that alongside the to
language specific imports
you might see English
and Polish and our case.
We also have one
additional to type only import
the indicates that will tree
our e and jaison schema as the
main schema for all the other
languages and translations
and will be making it our
default locale for our application.
Also note that in our case here were
statically importing all the languages
the more languages we would have
the more important
we'd have to add here
however
if we wanted to load all
languages dynamically
the could just iterate through
files located in the locales folder.
Check out the corresponding
code in the description of this
video for how that can be
achieved if you're interested.
Inside the eighteen
and service class
let's declare three properties.
Static default language
which is pretty self descriptive
will make it equal to e
n or English in our case.
Static supported languages
which is an array the
represents all the supported
languages by our application.
And a local private
locales object
which holds all the
actual translations.
With all this the place
was now declared the
translate method next
and let's break it down.
This transit method
takes a single input argument which is a
key under which each transaction provide the
appropriate string
and returns a string.
Or translations
only have one key
so far which is hollow.
This will work just the same if we
had ten thousand keys there as well.
Inside of this method
we retrieve the corresponding
texts for any given keep.
But how can we get the current
users locale on this method.
This is where
requests go providers
and especially durable
providers come in handy.
So let's first
slag this class as
request scoped passing
scoped out request to
the injectable decorator
and also
let's set it to durable true.
With this and place
we can
inject our durable DEA subtree payload
using the inject request instructions.
Here we can expect
that the payload will be
an object with a single
property locale code
which represents
the users locale.
And with this dependency
injected into her classes constructor
we can now use it in the
translate method to retrieve a user
locale
removing the to do
comment we had here
and replacing it
with a fallen coat.
Last but not least we
must implement our custom
context ID strategy to
actually register per locale
DEA sub trees.
For this let's create a new
file in the core directory
alongside the strategy we
created in the previous lesson
and call it.
Aggregate by locale strategy.
Inside this file.
That space where we
implemented in the previous
lesson replacing the
tenant word with locale.
Now aside from the boilerplate
code that's almost identical
there are a few other things
we will need to change your.
First let's replace every occurrence
of locale ID with locale code.
Is to make things
more itself descriptive.
And also.
Let's make sure our
payload matches the interface
be expected to be inside
the i eighteen and service.
Next
instead of using the
x locale ID header
that's retrieved the locale information
from the except language header
using the pick function.
From the except language parser package
we installed in the beginning of this less.
Also
in case locale code is know we
can fall back to our default language.
You can also remove
the condition below since
locale code will never
be no or undefined.
With this in place was
make sure we replaced the
context i do strategy we
applied in the previous lesson
with the new one we
built in this chapter.
Over this.
With navigate to
the app module file
and change the aggregate
by tenant contexts ID
strategy to aggregate by
locale context ID strategy.
Great
and now before we
test everything out.
We have to actually do use the
eighteen and service someone.
Let's open up
our app service file
and start by first
injecting the eighteen and
service inside of it using
the standard approach.
Note that this will make our app service
and app controller implicitly durable as
well so always
keep that in mind.
Inside the get hello method
let's use the i eighteen and
service translate method.
When typing things inside
of the translate method.
We could see that we have
things strongly typed here.
Since hello is the only
key we have provided so far
let's go ahead and use it here.
Naturally.
Reduce different keys
in different situations
where we needed a
different strengths sent back.
Okay so let's save our
changes open of our
terminals and use curl
to test our important.
First.
Without passing any headers.
And we received hello just as
we could have expected great.
Especially since we have set up a
default language and or application
and he returns the English
translations for us automatically.
Now let's specify the
except language header
setting peel or
Polish for the value.
And voila there we have it
says she got
returned back to us.
If we change her head or to e n
or English will receive hello again.
As we can see
not only could users now
pass in their desired language
of we forgot to do so we even have our
default all set up a working properly great.
So before we
wrap up this lesson.
We'd like to demonstrate how you could also
enhance your eighteen and module to let
you pass arguments
to translations.
This essentially add support
for parameter his strengths.
Also will dive into how you could
have grouped aka a nested translations.
Both of these will come in handy in
your future internationalized applications.
Let's start by first opening our
he ended
on file
and modifying the hollow
translation to be hello.
First name surrounded
by curly braces.
These braces indicate that we're going
to be inserting a variable or parameter
to string here.
Similarly
as to the same thing
and r p thou Jason file.
With our translation files updated let's
navigate to our eighteen and service and add
a new spread parameter to
the translate method signature
calling it barks.
Will pass these args or arguments to the
format function exported from the string
format package that we installed
at the beginning of this lesson.
Let's save our changes
and navigate to
our app service now
and for the second argument
of our translate method.
Let's pass an object setting
first name to an arbitrary name
let's say Camille.
Once again
let's save our changes open up our terminals
and let's test our and point once again.
And while i.
Allow Camille.
If we test Polish we'll see we'll get back
safe Camille and if we set the language
header to English
will see once again
hello Camille.
Perfect everything's
working great.
Although our example is simplified here the
same logic and set up could be applied in
any other situation where you need to
have dynamic parameters string values set.
Whether it's a specific Erica that
you're returning or anything else.
Or our last demonstration let's
implement translation grouping.
For this lets navigate
to r e n Jason file
now the following entry.
Similarly was to the same
thing in a PR Jason file.
Next up.
Is navigate to are eighteen
and service and as we can
see we're already getting
some type of errors now.
The reason for these errors as
that now our translations are not flat.
Some keys might be equal to
objects not just strings as before.
Thankfully typescript is
helping us prevent errors here.
We should have
expected ourselves.
But a fix all of this up.
Let's replace the current
implementation of our techs variable
with the following code that can be
found below the course video was always.
Now with this and place
i eighteen and service consumers
will be able to pass the translation key
using the dot
notation for example.
Errors dot user
not found in artists.
Lastly.
We have to update the type of the key
argument as well as it right now does not
support passing strings
with this dot notation.
For this.
Will declare to help
or types of of our class.
Note that like always you can find this
code to copy paste below the course video.
We will be diving into these types as there
is someone outside of the scope of this
lesson but just so
that you are aware.
Combined.
These types let
us construct a type
that consists of a union
of all the keys of an object
including nested at
next.
Don't worry we'll see everything
in action here in a moment.
Using these types down what's up the
our translate method signature as follows.
Let's save our changes
navigate to our app
service and remove the
hollow argument and see
what keys we can pass it.
And there we have it
now or keys are strongly typed
and fully contextually aware.
We could see hello and errors dot
user not found shown here fantastic.
Now for testing purposes let's just
temporarily use errors dot user not found here
just the we can make
sure that it works.
But save our changes
open up or terminals and use curl
to test that and point one last time.
And there we have it
user Camille does not
exist great it worked.
So in this lesson not only did we learn
about an extremely important part of most
enterprise applications
which is internationalization.
We also learned about the
power of durable providers.
That unlike requests
scope providers.
We have things stay in
memory for quite some time.
As opposed to be in created ain't
garbage collected on every single request.
We hope you enjoyed learning
more advanced concepts
and sgs and stay tuned for
more courses coming soon.
Thanks for helping
support in sjs.