Before we kick things off let's start off
by generating an empty nest js application
just the we have something we
can work with in the following lessons.
Let's head over
to our terminals.
In enter into the
nest new command.
Calling our project
advanced dash concepts
or whatever you wish.
Once everything
finishes installing.
Let's cd or change directory into our
newly created application by entering cd
advanced dash concepts.
With our initial
starter in place
let's generate a
single resource.
With nest g resource
that we will call coffees.
Miss the we have something to
operate on throughout the course.
Will use the auto generated module
service and controller in future lessons.
Great.
With all the some place
we can now start our
application in development
mode owed with n p m run
start Colin depth.
As always our application will now
be available on port three thousand
and there we have it
were all set to continue
moving forward.