During your journey
while learning ness jazz
you may have encountered various different
errors while working with the framework.
In this lesson
will walk you through
the most common issues
engineers typically run
into when working with nest.
Telling you how you can solve and
avoid them in your future applications.
A sort of by looking at the
cannot resolve dependency air
which is probably the most
common error message
you'll see when working
with the framework.
The most common
culprit of this air is not
having a provider in the
models providers array.
However
this is not always the
case in there are many other
scenarios where you
may stumble across this air.
First.
Let's showcase the most evident
scenario where our coffees controller
that we generated in
the previous lesson.
Depends on a coffees
service that is not registered
in the modules
providers of right.
Though let's
head over to r i d e
and open up the coffee's
module file in remove
the coffee service from
the providers a wreck.
Let's make sure to
save our changes.
Then open up our terminals again
and as we can see
the info miss cannot resolve
dependency air showed up of course.
If you run across this air while
developing your application.
Take a look at the module mentioned in
the air message and look at his providers.
Or each provider in
the providers array
make sure the module has
access to all the dependencies.
Often times
providers are duplicated
in a future module oh
and a route module which means a nest
will try to instantiate the provider twice.
Along with just manually verifying
our dependencies are correct.
We can set the
nest underscored debug
environment variable to a string
that resolves is true the
and get extra
logging information
on nest is resolving all the
dependencies for our application.
Though let's
terminate our process.
And add nest underscored
debug equals true
before the n p m run
start calling def command.
Just to turn this feature on
and run everything again.
The string and yellow
found in our terminal is
the host class of the
dependency being injected.
The string and blue
is the name of the
injected dependency
or it's injection token.
In the string and purple
is the module in which the
dependency is being searched for.
Using this method
you can usually trace back the
dependency resolution to see was happening
and why you're getting dependency
injection issues and errors.
As we can see here.
For our coffees controller
nest is trying to resolve the
coffee's service dependency
and it's sequentially
searching for that dependency
in the host module.
Which is the coffee's ma module.
After looking there
it also searches within
the imported modules.
Since our coffers module does not
import other models at this moment.
It won't be able to find the
coffee service there as well.
Interestingly enough.
We do see an internal
core module show up here
but we didn't even import that
in her application anywhere.
Well
the internal core module is actually
an internal framework module that gets
automatically imported
into every module.
Providing us access to
classes such as reflector.
Module ref
and many others that
you may have seen before.
A lot of which we covered
in the fundamentals course.
Though
as nest tried to search for
coffee service and all those places
and it was not provided
any of these modules.
Nest aired out with a can't
resolve dependencies exception.
All right so far
this was the most
obvious scenario where you
may have seen such
an air plenty of times
next up
let's dive into something
a bit more complex.
Before we continue onward.
Let's make sure we revert the
change we did in the coffins module file
and add the coffee service
provider back in the Iraq.
Let's change gear slightly to showcase
another similar and common situation
developers frequently
stumble upon.
What started off by declaring a new
interface and the coffee service file
and call it coffees data source.
Leasing right above our
coffee the service class.
We'll use the index signature to describe
the types of values that are possible here.
In this case
we assume that the data source will be
in array that consists of zero and elements
and those elements
are of type coffee.
As you can see in
the comment above
we could alternately use the type
declaration here if we wanted to.
Now
let's try to inject this coffees
data source into our coffee service.
Let's save our changes.
Open up our terminals and look at
the air message we received this time.
As we can see
instead of seeing a message that says
something about our coffees data source here.
We only see object
which makes this air even
more confusing and ambiguous.
But why isn't nest
helping us out here.
Well the reason is
actually because typescript
doesn't leave any meta
data about interfaces.
Every interface is represented
as object in the
produced js file.
Though we can't really provide users with
helpful information about what's missing
the coffee service
provider here.
But that's why we can't
and shouldn't use interfaces
as provider tokens.
As a best practice instead.
As declare a new symbol
above the interface declaration
and name it coffees underscore
data underscore source
and use this instead.
Now.
Let's use the inject annotation to inject
that data source into our coffee service.
Let's save our changes and
navigate to the coffee's module file.
In here
let's declare a new
coffees data source provider
using the custom
provider syntax.
If we save our changes again
and check back in our terminal
will see that
everything works though
no errors.
Oh now for fun.
Let's do a little experiment
and move coffees data
source declaration to
the coffee's modul instead
removing it from
the coffee service.
Has also update our import
pats as they will be different now.
Let's save our changes
and open up our terminals again.
As we can see here.
Are getting an error now
but what happened.
Well
the reason why we're seeing
an air now is that we just
introduced a circular
important in or application.
Circular dependencies can arise
when to providers depend on each other.
Or
typescript files
depend on each other
whether that's exported
variables constance functions etc.
In our case here we have
the coffee's module importing
the coffee service so it can
be registered as a provider
but at the same time.
The coffee's data source is
exported from the module file.
Being imported into the service
will can be injected
there as well
hence the circular important.
In our exact case the reasoning this is
all happening is pretty sure wait forward.
Especially since be noticed
the issue the moment we did it.
However
and more sophisticated
applications
fracking circular dependencies can be very
tedious and generally difficult to uncover
where they're
actually coming from.
Lucky for us.
This is where the tool
maj comes in handy.
Maj is a developer tool for generating a
visual graph of your module dependencies
binding circular
dependencies and it even helps
give us other useful
information about everything.
That's open up
another terminal window
and execute the
following commands.
And point match to are built
nest code in disc slash main dot j s.
Passing in the circular flag.
We can see here that maj found
one circular dependency for us
and tactic.
We can even generate
a dependency graph.
Using the following command.
Passing the dash
dash image flag.
In the name of the image
we want to save it as.
Note.
If you want to generate a graph with
the graph this tool you can find more
information about that in the
description below this video.
Let's open up the
graph we just created
and see what we have in there.
In the mid shown here
we can see that the blue
notes have dependencies.
Reno it's have no dependencies.
And read notes have
circular dependencies.
As we can see
maj really helps us visualize what
depends on what in our applications.
Image tool
along with the
visualization tool really help
us pinpoint and locate
circular dependencies
as well as other issues in our
application quickly and effectively.
Letting us make some changes
and give us the ability to
test everything once again
to see if we fixed whatever
problem were facing.
And the case of our
circular issue here.
As a best practice.
We should
only ever export one
thing from every file while
but sometimes we have go against this practice
let's say we had a constants t s file.
Where we were holding a
bunch of constant variables.
Ideally
we'd want to make sure he has lent is throwing
a linting are at us whenever we forget
this to prevent situations like
this from a rising in the future.
If we move the concert
export into its own file
containing that new interface we
made an make sure to update or imports.
Will see that our application
now runs without any errors
and if we run maj again
we'll see there are no longer any
circular dependency errors as well.
Following this best practice in the future
will prevent these situations from arising.
In your know best applications.