We can identify two different
types of dependencies in ness Jess
explicit
and implicit dependencies.
Let's start off by analyzing
implicit dependencies.
If we look at the following
coffees controller class
will see we have a one implicit
dependency which is the carton service.
We refer to it as an
implicit dependency.
Because the framework is in charge
of reading the constructors meta data
in the retrieval of the coffee
service class reference itself.
In fact
this syntax is an
implicit version
of the explicit syntax that
uses the inject decorator like so.
Both variants are
technically equivalent.
In would result in the
same injected dependency.
But how does all this
work behind the scenes.
When the typescript compiler transpires
typescript files into javascript files.
It leave some additional
meditative behind
that allows us to use reflection
to analyze everything at runtime.
If we open up the transpire
coffees controller jas file
located in our disc directory
and scroll down a bit will
see the following code.
Thanks to the design and
puram types meta
data we can see here
it is not required for us
to use the inject decorator
and explicitly pass a token we
want to look up this dependency.
However
we have to explicitly
use the inject annotation
for dependencies that we can't
simply referenced by their classes.
Take for example
the symbol and interface reference
we used in the the last lesson.
To demonstrate
everything further
as open up our coffees
controller file again
and add a new dependency here.
Let's try to inject a coffees
data source provider
just like we registered
in the previous less.
If you have reverted
those changes already
you can find the code
below the course video.
Now let's open up our terminals
and run on
n p m run bills.
Once it finishes.
Let's navigate to the coffee's controller
js file once again and take a look.
As we can see.
Instead of having the coffee's data
source reference or some type of coffees
data source related meta data.
We simply have
the object reference.
The reason once again
is a interfaces don't
exist in javascript.
The air wiped out during the transpiration
process by the typescript compiler.
And so.
This is why for other types of providers
be at value providers or factory providers.
We have to use inject
decorators explicitly.
This decorator
makes sure to tell the nest framework
exactly which dependency should be injected.
So as we can see.
What we specifically used
for providers be classes
interfaces etc
and how we inject them.
Is all very important.
Make sure to always keep these things
in mind in your future nest applications.