By default modules
are eagerly loaded
which means that as soon
as the application loads
so do all the
applications modules.
Whether or not there
immediately necessary.
While this is fine for most applications it
may become a bottleneck for applications
or workers running in a
serverless environment.
Or having little to
no startup latency.
Or cold start
is absolutely crucial.
Lazy loading can help decrease bootstrap
time by loading only the modules required by
a specific serverless
function invocation.
In addition
you could also load other
models a synchronously
wants the serverless
function is warm
to speed up the bootstrap time for
any subsequent calls even further.
This is no one
as deferred
modules registration.
Most commonly you will
see lazy loaded modules
in situations where
your worker cronjob
lambda
or serverless function or webhooks
must trigger different services
or different logic.
Based on any given
input arguments
be at route path date.
Worry parameters etc.
On the other hand
lazy loading modules may not make
too much sense for monolithic applications
where the startup
time is rather irrelevant.
So
let's get started by
switching to r i d e
and see how we can lazy
load modules in ness jazz.
First.
Let's start off by generating
a new rewards module.
Note raising the skip
import flag here to instruct
the cla to not add the newly
generated rewards module
to our route
at modules imports array
as we wondered lazy load it.
Next up let's generate a single
reward service within this module.
With this in place what's
navigate to our coffee service file
and before we start let's inject
the new lazy module loader provider
using the standard approach.
But this dependency and place
what's that we want to the create method
and first
let's update the method
signature to be a sink.
Next.
Let's use the load method of the
lazy module loader provider to lazy load
the rewards module.
The lazy module loader
load method returns of
the module reference
of rewards module here.
Which lets us navigate
the internal list of providers
and obtain a reference
to any provider
using its injection to
good as a lookup keep.
Next up.
Let's retrieved the rewards
service class reference as follows.
And lastly
let's use that reference to
retrieve the corresponding provider.
Just so we could
test everything out.
As open of the rewards
service and at a random
method in there that
console logs some texts.
Right let's save our changes
and back to the coffee service
and call that method from within their.
Great.
Now onto our terminals.
Just make sure we have the application
up and running in the background
with n p m run start
Colin def command.
And
let's open up a separate
terminal window and use
curl to call our post
slash coffees and endpoint
just a test everything out.
Great as we can see no errors.
So
let's switch back to the other
terminal window with our app running.
And as we can see here.
There's our hello from the lazy
loaded rewards service message
which is logged to our console
just as we should have expected.
Now what happens
if we call this endpoint
a second time.
Will the rewards module
be loaded once again.
Well
lazy loaded modules
are cached upon the first
lazy module loader
load method invocation.
This means that each
consecutive attempt to load it
will be very fast and will
return a cached instance
instead of loading the
module all over again.
Just to prove that it works.
Etc or to our crate method
and use the console that time and
console that time and methods there
who can measure how
long it takes to retrieve
the rewards service instance.
Let's save our changes
head back to our
terminals switch to that
second terminal window
and run that curl
multiple times.
Next.
Let's switch back to our applications
terminal and see will got log to our console.
And as we can see
each consecutive attempt
to load rewards modul
was much faster as the load methods
simply returned a cached instance
instead of loading the module
again and again.
Of course our example here is it one
you would likely due in the real world.
We kept things simple in this lesson
and just use our existing application.
Just for demonstration
purposes of course
but achieving
everything we did here
or whatever scenario
you need in the future
whether it's for microservices
Ron jobs
serverless functions etc
just know that everything
could be achieved
exactly the same way.