Often times when building integration and
generic libraries we require access to the
applications inversion of
control or i o c container
in order to introspect all of the
register providers and controllers.
For example
if we look at some
of the official nest js
packages such as ness
j a slash graft you well.
We will see that this pack which
traverses and applications module graph
and providers
by analyzing their meta
data to determine which
providers contain graft
your specific meta data.
For instance the package checks of a
classes annotated with the resolve decorator
and searches for methods decorated
with the resolve field decorator as well.
Similarly
if we look at another
nastiest package the nest
schedule or library.
Will notice of this package
iterates through all providers as well.
Checking to see if any of them
register schedule or methods.
Intervals or cron jobs.
So
let's learn how we could
do similar things ourselves.
To help facilitate creating
extensible modules and libraries.
Nest jazz exposes a module
known as the discovery module
that will showcase
in this lesson.
Let's recreate our own
small scheduler like
library to help us put
everything together.
But start things off by
generating a scheduler module
using the nest jsc ally
it will use as a central point to
help us understand everything.
In sight of this module.
Let's generate a single provider
in name of interval scheduler.
Will use this service to traverse
the modules graph in ultimately.
Auto register any
discovered intervals.
Let's open up that file and start by
annotating it with the injectable decorator.
Next.
Let's make this class implement the
an application bootstrap life cycle hook.
Our ID he should prompt us to implement
the interface so let's go ahead and do it.
Moving on from here for a moment
but to navigate to our
schedule or module file.
In register the
interval scheduler
as a provider.
Let's also make sure to
import the discovery module
from nastiest that we
mentioned just a moment ago.
Great.
Actor are interval scheduler.
As inject a new service called discovery
service using the standard approach.
Next.
Let's move onto the an
application bootstrap method
and use the discovery
service to retrieve a list
of all providers registered
in our application.
Note that if we wanted to
retrieve a list of all controllers.
We could instead use
the get controllers method.
If we hover over the
providers variable here.
We'll see that it's type is an
array of instance rapper objects.
Instance rapper
is an internal nastiest
wrapper class that
represents all controllers
providers enhancers
in any thing that gets registered in
nests inversion of control container.
This class exposes several
methods but in the majority of cases.
Who won't need a lot of 'em.
Most are simply
needed and used by other
internal nest packages and modules.
Though for
demonstration purposes
as soon as the for each method on
providers to iterate through this array
and then console log
each providers token now.
Let's save our changes
open up our terminals
and see will get
logged to our console.
As we can see.
Here is an entire list of
everything in our application
from modules configurations.
Services
and even our intervals
schedule or itself.
Act or interval scheduler.
So far we've learned how to
retrieve a list of all provider rappers
but
how can we filter out
some of those providers
for example by checking
if they're annotated
with a specific decorator.
Similar to how nest does
itself in certain packages.
Though before we
continue let's start out by
creating a new decorator
that we will search for
to learn more about how
all this functionality works.
Inside our scheduler directory.
As create a new folder called
decorators and side of this folder
let's create a new file and name
of interval host decorator dot t s.
Inside this file.
A stickler a do inch
yeovil host key constant
and make it equal
to the string of
interval host key
which will use as
are met a day to keep.
Below that constant.
Let's utilize the set meditate
a function exported from
NASA has common and declare
a new interval host decorator
as shown here.
A save our changes.
Open up our terminals
and generate a new
module called cron
using the and sgs the alive.
Then that module
has also generate
a cron service.
In this newly generated
service lets annotate the class
with the interval hosts
decorator that we just created.
Great.
Now let's save our changes.
Which back to our interval
scheduler class again
and let's start by injecting
the reflector class as
the second dependency
using the standard approach.
But this dependency injected.
Let's move onto the an
application bootstrap method
and inside the providers
that for each callback.
As retrieve the providers instance
from the instance rapper object.
Let's make sure that the
instance is a not know or undefined
and grabbed the instances prototype using
the object i'd get prototype of function.
Next up let's make sure we
add a condition checking of
both instance or prototype
variables are not defined
and if that's the case let's return
to prevent running for their coat.
Doing this as your useful to exclude
value and factory providers as well.
Lastly.
Let's use the reflector instance in
retrieve the instances meta data like so.
So if we get a value here.
Meaning that there's an
interval decorator found
let's log the providers
token down to our console.
At save our changes.
Open up our terminals and as we can
see the only provider that got logged out.
His are annotated
crown service great
a worked like a charm.
Alright
so as we already know how to
access providers host class meta data.
How could we analyzed
the providers methods.
Let's imagine that we'd want our interval
scheduler to discover all methods annotated
with the interval
decorator on its own.
And register them
as intervals
automatically for us.
Since we don't have
that decorator yet
let's go ahead and create that
first before we continue further.
Let's create another new
decorator named interval.
Just like we did before
and this time with a constant
interval key.
And when we
declare our decorator.
Let's make sure it has
a parameter named m s
which is of type number.
Let's never go back to
our crown service and
declare a new method
they're named every second.
Annotating it with our
new interval decorator.
Passing in one thousand
as an argument.
Let's save our changes
and head back to
the interval scheduler.
And let's inject yet
another dependency.
Belt meta data scanner.
Next
let's use this new meta data
Skinner right below are if condition.
Calling the get all
method names method.
Passing the providers prototype
function as an argument.
Next let's iterate through the method keys
array and retrieve the interval meta data
using the reflector
like we have previously.
And let's make sure to pass in the
meth reference as the second argument.
Which we can grab thea
instance method key.
Like before.
Let's also make sure
that it's not undefined.
This helps exclude methods that are
not annotated with the interval decorator.
And last but not least
now that we've established that we're
using the interval decorator on this method
and we found a function.
As register the actual interval
using the native
set interval function.
Let's save our changes.
Open up our terminals and
take a look at our console.
And as we could have expected.
We can see the
this will be logged
every second message
is being displayed in
our console every second.
Everything worked
perfectly great.
One tiny improvement
before we finish though.
We always want to
make sure we clean up all
resources when we
terminate or applications.
Let's make sure we implement the
an application shut down life cycle hook
and close all registered
intervals there.
So let's start by first implementing
the an application shut down interface.
And then declare the an
application shut down method.
Let's leave it empty for
now as we don't keep
track of registered
intervals in our class just yet
but will implement
that right now.
As that a new class
property called intervals
making it of type
know js dot timer array.
And inside of our for
each callback function let's
make sure we add the
interval we create to data array.
Lastly.
Let's head back to our an
application shut down method
and make sure we clear all the intervals
looping through everything in the array
and calling the clear interval
method on each iteration.
So we've covered
a lot in this lesson.
And although we
created just a simple utility
decorator for easily turning
methods into intervals.
Hopefully you can see the
power of what we've accomplished
and how you could add
much more intensive or
useful functionality in
your future applications.
Utilizing the same
strategies we put to use here.