Worker threads help us offload cpu
intensive tasks away from the event loop
so that they can be
executed paralleling.
In a non-blocking manner.
Although
they do not help us much with io or input
output intensive work since the know js
built-in a synchronous
io operations
are much more
efficient themselves.
Each worker thread how as its own isolated
v eight environment context event loop of
que etc.
However
they can share memory.
They could do so by
transferring array buffer instances
or sharing shared a re buffer
instances with one another.
Also
a worker and parent can communicate with
each other through a messaging channel.
Note that in no Jess it's important to
differentiate between cpu intensive long
running event loop
blocking operations
and io
or input output operations.
Such as http requests
inquiring the database etc.
Or us to better understand when
worker threads might come in handy
but switch over to our ids and
generate a new fibonacci module.
Inside this module
let's also generate a
new fibonacci controller
that we used to
test out a few ideas.
Let's open up this newly
generated a controller
file a declare a new get
route there as follows.
This endpoint will accept
one query parameter
and
which is the nth
fibonacci number.
Inside this method was
implement the fibonacci formula.
Note that there are no i o operations
here so this is a perfect example of a cpu
intensive time consuming
and or blocking operation.
Let's save our changes
open the our terminals
and run our application and
development mode with
n p m run start calling deaf.
Once our app as bootstrapped
let's open up a separate
terminal window and
use curl to call our
get fibonacci endpoint.
Passing question Mark n.
With are cleared
perimeter equaling forty one.
Where forty one represents
the forty first fibonacci number.
Below the video you'll
find the curl code to
can copy pasted and
tried out for yourself.
As we can see
it took approximately
five seconds
which may not seem like a
long time but since calculating
the fibonacci number is a
synchronous blocking operation.
During these five seconds
even if someone
tried reaching our a p i
r application would
not be able to respond.
That means if there were any other http
request during this five sec timeframe.
All of these would have to wait until this
specific fibonacci calculation is done.
As you may have already guessed.
This is far from ideal.
So case in point
situations like this are exactly when
worker threads might come in handy.
Instead of blocking
the main thread.
We could delegate that operation to a
separate worker therefore r a p i would remain
fully responsive and
operate like normal.
Let's start by
creating a worker file
and naming it fibonacci
dot worker dot t s.
Inside of this file let's
paste art fibonacci function.
Next
we need to register
an event listener.
Listening to incoming
messages from the parent port
our workers parent.
To do so let's utilize
the parent port object
imported from the worker
underscore threads module
and register the on
message listener.
As an input argument
for the callback function.
Let's use an ID destructuring
the incoming message object.
Where n represents the nth
fibonacci number to be calculated.
And ID
is the unique
request call identifier.
And last but not least.
Inside this callback
function let's calculate the
fibonacci number and
respond to the parent port.
Using the post message
method.
Passing the unique
call ID and the result.
Let's save our changes and
next to the fibonacci worker file
let's create a another file intimate
fibonacci worker dot hosts file.
Inside this file let's declare
the injectable fibonacci
worker host class that
implements to lifecycle hooks.
An application bootstrap
and an application shut down
as well as provide a run
method where will set up the
logic that helps us communicate
with the underlying worker.
Let's also declared to
private properties in this class.
Worker.
Which represents the
underlying worker instance
and message dollar sign
which is where will store our
messages in and rx js observable stream.
More on that in a moment.
To start things off
inside of our an application
bootstrap method.
Let's initialized
the worker inst this.
Let's create the message dollar sign
event stream using the from event helper
function from the
rx Jess package.
Constructing a
stream based off the
this dot worker
on message.
With our bootstrap
face all set up let's move
on to the an application
shut down method
a make sure we
clean everything up.
Here we just want to
terminate the spawned
workers let's call the
terminate method on it.
Now let's move on to the fun
part and set up the logic itself.
Inside of our run method
let's first generate a unique ID.
We will use this ID to
differentiate requests
as each message will
have its own unique ID.
So that we can associated
with a given specific request.
Next let's send a message to the
worker using the post message method
passing in an object that
consists of two properties and
and ID.
Know that we could have
used array buffer and shared a
buffer to implement memory transfer as
we mentioned at the start of this lesson.
Or share between threads to make
the execution even more efficient.
Lastly
let's return the value from
our messages observable
making sure to filter it
based on the unique ID
and grabbing the result value.
If you're not too
familiar with our extra as
it's unfortunately out of the scope of this
course to dive into all of the specifics
but just know that
here were essentially
piping the stream.
Filtering by unique ID.
The mapping and
plucking that result value
just as we mentioned.
If you're interested in learning
more about our ex jazz itself.
Check out the official docs
station at our exchange dot death.
Great.
Let's save our changes and
navigate to the fibonacci module
to register our fibonacci
worker host as a provider there.
With our provider registered
let's wish to the
fibonacci controller
and inject our fibonacci work or host
they're using the standard approach.
And finally.
Us replace our current fibonacci method
implementation with the following code
a caused the run method of
our fibonacci workers hosts.
Excellent.
At once again save our changes.
Open a bar terminals and call
that fibonacci and point once again.
It works perfect.
Now for fun let's change the
and parameter to let's say sixty
just so it takes a very long
time to calculate that number
and call that and point again.
In the meantime
let's open up another
terminal window and see if our
Apia is responsive by hitting
another random endpoint.
And as we can see
our Apia is still
responsive now great.
Next.
Let's try to hit the fibonacci endpoint
bullets change the end perimeter to something
that shouldn't take too
long for example five.
And as we can see.
The application is hanging
on us but why what happened.
Well the reason or application is hanging
here is because our worker is still busy
with the previous
request of we executed.
Where we asked them to calculate
the sixtieth the
fibonacci number.
But how can we overcome
this kind of an issue.
Well to address
this limo citation
we could implement
a pool of workers so
basically instead of
having one worker instance
we'd maintain a pool
aka a collection of workers.
Then instead of delegating
work to a busy worker
we'd just retrieve one
that is available and free.
In this lesson instead
of implementing static
and dynamic worker
pools by hand ourselves.
Will be utilizing
the Pacino library.
Which will make things much easier for
us and with a lot less boilerplate code.
Pacino
is a widely used node worker pool
package that supports flexible pool sizes
provides fast communication
between threads
and covers both
fixed task and
variable task scenarios.
So let's get it installed.
Once the installation
is complete.
Before we continue let's
open up our ts config file
and said the as modul
interrupt property to true
as it is required
by this library.
Next
let's move onto the fibonacci controller
and replaced the classes constructor
with the following code.
Initializing the
Pacino worker pool
and passing in the
filepath to our worker.
Also let's make sure to
not forget to update the
fibonacci method to use the
fibonacci worker now as well.
And
last but not least
let's open up our
fibonacci dot worker vile
and replace our on message event
listener with a simple export.
And that's it.
If we save our changes
open up our terminals
and use curl to again
calculate that sixtieth
fibonacci number
and we switched to
another terminal window
and call the fibonacci and point again with
a different value of and let's say five.
As we could see
were able to start up
multiple workers now
without causing the
application to hang.
All while keeping our application
fully row responsive so if you want.
Try to hit a random point again
and see if that works.
With everything we've
learned and done in this
lesson we can now handle
any intensive tasks we need
in our nest js
applications future.