In today's world it's common
for applications to make
remote calls to services
running in different processes
or even on different machines.
And he distributed environment.
Also remote resources
and services can fail due
to a variety of reasons
the network connections.
Amounts.
Or the resources being
temporarily unavailable.
What could make men
there's worse as if you
have many callers to
and unresponsive supplier
it's possible your system could
run out of the critical resources
leading to a cascading failure.
Across multiple systems.
Also known as a snowball effect.
These types of false commonly resolve
themselves after a short period of time
and any robust cloud application
should be prepared
to handle them
by using a strategy
such as the retry pattern
or many other strategies.
However
there also could be situations where
faults are due to unanticipated events in
situations like that might
take much longer to fix.
In these tough situations
it might be meaningless
for an application
to continually
retry an operation
that is unlikely to succeed.
Though instead.
The application should
quickly except that the
operation has failed
in handle this failure
accordingly.
The circuit breaker pattern can prevent
an application from repeatedly trying to
execute an operation
that is likely to fail.
In this lesson.
Will implement the
circuit breaker pattern.
Using an interceptor bound to an endpoint
that tries to invoke a remote service.
Will start off by generating
the circuit breaker interceptor
using the nes jsc ally.
You can notice that were passing the no
flat flag here so that the seal i creates a
new directory named circuit breaker
inside of the interceptors folder.
Will use this directory to group
circuit breaker feature related files.
Next to this interceptors file
let's create a new
circuit breaker t s file.
Inside this file
a sort of by adding some constants that will
determine our circuit breakers behavior.
Where success threshold represents
the number of successful operations.
Which once we have risen above.
We should close the circuit.
Failure threshold which
represents the number of failures.
Which once we've risen above
opens the circuit
to start repeating the last air
instead of executing the route handler.
And opened a
half open wait time.
Does the number of
milliseconds after which are circuit
breaker changes to the
half open state from open.
Will enter in one minute
in milliseconds here.
Next below these
constants let's declare an
enum that represents
our circuit breaker state.
As we can see
we have three
different states here
closed
which is the default state meeting at the
circuit breaker is closed aka not enabled.
Open.
Which represents when the number of
failures reaches the specified threshold
enabling our search breaker.
Lastly half open.
Indicating when the circuit
breaker is in the middle
of transitioning from an
open to a closed state.
Finally let's declare the actual circuit
breaker class with a few useful properties.
State which represents the
current state of the circuit breaker.
Failure count which is a
count of the number of failures.
Success count
similarly the number of
successful operations.
Last air
which stores the last thrown air
and next attempt
which represents when
our circuit breaker should
transition from closed
to half open state.
This is done by
combining the current time.
Via data now
and adding the wait time
that we've established.
Next up was declared three methods
inside that will handle some of our logic.
Exec which wraps
the execution logic
thinking the call handler
as an input argument.
In applying the tap operator.
Which depending on whether an
era was through one will call either the.
Handle success or
handle air methods.
And handle success
and handle air.
So let's start by implementing
the handle air method.
Inside this method.
Is make sure we first
increment the number of failures.
Next up
let's add the
following condition.
What we are trying to
deduce here is that if
the number of failures
reaches our threshold.
Or
if the current state of the
circuit breakers half open
the we need to.
Update the state to open.
Save the last
error that occurred
and we need to update
the next attempt property
which as we mentioned
is the current time.
Last hour wait time.
Right.
Now onto the handle
success method.
First let's reset the number
failures back to zero.
Next.
Let's check of the current
state is half open and if
so we need to increment
the success count property.
And lastly.
Needed to test whether we reached
the success threshold and if so
need to change the state to
closed in reset the success counter.
Perfect.
Last but not least
let's add the following
conditions to the exact method.
If the state is open
meeting that the circuit
breakers turned on.
The we checked to see if we
have reached the next attempt date
and if not.
Let's re throw the
last air that occurred.
Otherwise everything's all set
the we get update
the state to half open
and that's it.
As we can see
we had quite a few conditions
that situations we had to account for
but after all
the circuit breaker is doing
quite a few things for us
in helping us dramatically improve our
redress dragic so it's definitely worth it.
Let's make sure to
save our changes.
Let's head over to our circuit
breaker interceptor clothes.
Inside this class
let's create circuit breaker
by handler collection.
Using a week map collection.
Generally
will have an individual circuit
breaker instance per route handler
this is why we ideally want to have a
collection like this where we can store or
which circuit breaker
belongs to which route handler.
Inside the intercept method.
That's retrieve the currently
processed route handler
using the execution context by
calling the get handler method.
Next
depending on whether the
circuit breaker exists already or not
we either retrieve it from
our internal collection.
Or instantiate in update the
circuit breaker by handler map.
And finally let's replace the last
line of this method with the following.
Delegating the execution
of the circuit breaker itself.
And that's it.
Now for demonstration purposes.
Let's to navigate to
our coffees controller
and annotated with the
use interceptors decorator.
Passing in our
circuit breaker
interceptor inside.
Next
let's simulate that are find
all always returns an error.
Replacing the current method
implementation with the following.
Perfect.
But save our changes
make sure our app is
running in a separate terminal
window let's call our
endpoint fifty times using curl.
As we can see
for all these calls we
received the far away
request timeout error.
However
if we switch back to our
applications terminal window
who can see that our
endpoint was only executed.
The retire times
cause that was the threshold we
declared in our circuit breaker file
it worked.
Well as we can see.
Circuit breaker
we built did it's job
and kept returning the last error message
which was for away request time out
instead of constantly trying to hit the
service that's unavailable at the moment.
In our case since we have forced this
issue ourselves for demonstration purposes
we are not seeing the service recover
and the called becoming successful
which eventually we
would hope it would
but you can see with what we've
built here in a real world scenario
if this endpoint was reaching
out to an external service.
Once that service
fully recovered
everything would return back to normal and
eventually we'd get a successful response
back from that service.
Hopefully everything we've
covered here helps to mystify
and show the value of this
circuit breaker pattern to you
as it's an excellent strategy
for improving system's ability
to handle faults
errors and other
downtime problems.