Manually creating highly configurable
dynamic modules that expose async methods be
register async for route
async is quite complicated
especially for newcomers.
You may have seen methods
like these when working with
official ness packages such
as type or ram or graft ul.
In these packages
you have certainly done
things like typo around
module dot for route
or for or route a sink
when working with them.
If you have ever tried to create your own
dynamic module that accomplishes similar
things you may have realized
it's not very straightforward
and of also quite
a bit of boilerplate.
This is why nest exposes a somewhat new
class called the configurable module builder.
Which helps us facility
and simplify this entire
process and lets us
construct a module blueprint.
All in just a few lines of code.
While creating basic configurable
modules is pretty straightforward process
leveraging all the
built in features
of the configurable
module builder
might not be that obvious.
In this lesson
will showcase all the features of their
configurable model builder provides
and how it makes things significantly easier
compared to doing everything man you're.
So for demonstration purposes.
Let's start this off by generating
a new module with the nastiest
ally
and call it http client module.
Next alongside the newly
generated module file let's
create a new http client
module definition file.
Inside this file
let's construct a new
configurable module class.
Using the configurable
module builder.
Exported from the
nastiest common package.
As we can see
to create a new class we
simply have to instantiate a
new builder instance and
called the build method on it.
Next let's make sure we also specify
and options interface for this module.
Here we've specified
that our module takes an
object consisting of
one optional parameter
which is the base you rl
that we will use
for our http client
as and options object.
With all of this and place
but switched to r
http client module
and make sure our class extends the
configurable module class as follows.
Now if we navigate
to the app module
and type dot
after we try to empower
our http client module.
Our ID he
will show us to new
predefined methods
register
and register a sink.
We type register
and go inside the parentheses.
Will see that it even
shows us our options object.
Alternatively
we could also use the asynchronous
variant and we will still have all the
intelligence and place
for our options object.
Will stop here for a moment.
While building applications
with ness jazz you may have seen
methods like for route
register her
and for feature around
some of the nastiest packages.
You might have been wondering what
the difference our for all these methods.
Well
there is no hard
rule about this.
All the nest years packages try
to follow a few simple guidelines.
When creating a
module with register
we are expecting the
module to be able to configure
a dynamic module with
a specific configuration.
Or use only by
the calling module.
You can do this for as
many models as you want.
With for route.
We are expecting to be able to configure
a dynamic module once in reuse that
configuration in
multi will places.
Though possibly unknowingly
as is abstracted away.
This is why you have only
one graft your module for route
one type r m
module for route etc.
With for feature.
We are expecting to use the configuration
of a dynamic modules for route
but need to modify some
configuration specific to
the calling modules
needs let's say for example
which repository this
model should have access
to or the context that
a lager should use.
All of these methods usually
have a sink counterparts as well.
Register async for route async
and for feature a sink.
They typically achieve the
same thing as their counterpart
but they use nest
dependency injection
for the configuration in order to
handle things a synchronously.
Back to our task at hand
to test everything out
what's navigate to the
module definition file again
and export the
module options token
from the result of our canoe
configuration module builder.
As a best practice
we also recommend
renaming that constant to avoid
miss importing the wrong
module options token.
This may come in handy if
you have multiple modules
using the configuration
module build a class.
Now or case
are going to rename it
to be http module options.
And with distant place
let's open up our http
client module and inject the
options object they're
using the standard approach.
Also console log the
options object just so that it
shows up in are cancelled
to see what it actually is.
Let's make sure to
save our changes.
Open up our terminals and
see will got log to our console.
And as we can see
we have the base you are rl and nastiest
dot com that we passed in so far so good.
Let's switch back to
our module definition file
and see what other
possible what his behalf.
The configurable module
class by default provides the
methods register and it's
counterpart register a sink.
Use a different method name we can
use the set class method name method
as follows.
Now if we navigate
to the app module file
will see that register
is no longer present.
Instead we have
the for route method.
Back to our module definition
was coming out at line as
we want to keep using register.
Another useful method we might
want to use is set factory method name.
Since the register async
method or for route a sink or any
other name you have chosen
depending on your configuration.
Lets consumers pass a provider definition
that resolves to the modules configuration.
A library consumer could
potentially supply a class
to be used to construct
the configuration object.
This class by default
must provide the create method.
That returns a module
configuration object.
However
if our library is supposed to follow
a different naming convention.
We can change their behavior
and instruct configurable
module builder to expect a
different method for example
resolved as were showing here.
Now if someone used the a
configuration variant
it decided to provide a
configuration factor class.
This class would have to
provide the resolve method you.
Again
let's come at this out as in our example
we can just use the default value we just
wanted to showcase
the possibilities here.
The moving onto another interesting
use case for the configuration builder
is when our module needs to
take extra options that determined
how it is supposed to behave.
Imagine an option
such as the is global flag.
Or just global.
Which at the same time and
extra option like this should
not be included in the
module options token provider
as those options are
irrelevant to services and
provide riders registered
within that modul.
Take for example http client which itself
does not need to know whether it's host
module is registered as
a global module or not.
But these options are important
to those using our module.
Ideally we would want to
include them as additional options.
To achieve all this
we can use the
set extras method.
The first argument passed
into the set extra method is an
object containing default
values for the extra properties.
The second
argument is a function
that takes an auto generated module
definition with providers exports etc
in the extra object which
represents extra properties.
Either specified by the
consumer or defaults.
The return value this dysfunction
is a modified module definition.
In this specific example.
Were taking the extras
that is global property
and a sending it to the global
property of the module definition
which and our case determines
whether a module is global or not.
Now if we save our changes
navigate back to the app
module file will see that we
can pass in this additional
is global flag now we wanted.
And even though he pass in his
property here we look at our council
will notice that it does
not show up there.
This is because as
we've mentioned above.
Extras can be used to modify the
auto-generated module definition
they are not registered as part
of the options object or provider.
One thing that we
did not touch on yet
as that currently
this property is global
we added is always required
so how can we make
sure it is optional instead.
Back to our
models definition file
a specify the type argument of
the set extra method as follows.
And wala.
He has global property
as now optional.
Now for demonstration purposes
let's open up the
app module file again.
Remove the is global
prop we just added.
Copy the http client modul
import and paste it multiple times.
Let's save our changes
open up our terminals
and take a look at the logs.
As we can see even though
we imported http client module
multiple times only one
module was actually created.
For why is the.
While a nest every module is
represented as a note in a directed graph.
Meaning that notes
have specified directions.
Every node has its unique hash has
generated based on the modules definition.
If there is an existing
note with a specific cash
the nes points to that note
instead of creating a new one.
This all means that when we
have three http client module
imports and each module
shares the same configuration.
Only one node will be created.
However
when we change base your else to be
unique as follows an save our changes.
Will see that now we
have three models created
instead of one.
Let's revert this change and use the
same jarrell for Oliver imports for now.
Let's save those reverted changes and
switch back to the module definition file.
Let's pass the configuration object to
the configurable module builder constructor
setting the always
transient property to be true.
You see some
different functionality.
Let's save our changes
open up our terminals
and as we can see
there are three http
client modules now even
though they all have
the same configuration
because the module
is transient now instead.
This can be useful in situations
where you want to ensure
that every creation of the
module is in fact unique.
Back to our configuration
module builder options object.
There are two two other interesting and
useful properties you might want to use.
Options injection token
which lets us specify under which token
the options object should be registered
note that this is auto
generated by default.
Module name.
Which lets us specified
the modules name.
Which can be useful for
simpler debugging etc.
Also note that the build
method returns an object and
so far we've only used
to properties of that object.
Configurable module class.
In module options token.
There are two other properties
that may come in handy
if we wanted to override
the auto generated register
in register async methods.
Which are options type.
And async options type.
Now
let's switch to r
http client module
and see how we can use them.
As we can see.
Now we can make these options types
available for use since sometimes we may have
different configurable
options between register
and a sink register methods.
So in this lesson we've covered a lot and
done a deep dive into all the functionality
available with the
configuration module builder.
Hopefully you can see the power
and time-saving
capability that this build it
provides and creating
dynamic nest modules.
With his little
boilerplate as possible.
All while still having
complete control
over the dynamic module
process for your end users.