Everyone and welcome
to the official nest
courses.
In this extension
will be going through some microservices
concepts in scs from top to bottom.
Getting you up to speed
and creating enterprise great
applications with the
help of nastiest in no time.
So
let's introduced the
instructors with as course.
My name is Mark part of
the and sgs core team and
together with Camille
the creator of ness Jess
were excited to have
you learning nest with us.
To get the most out of this
course try to coat alongside
us and remember that you
can pause the videos at any time.
Please note that this extension
is a continuation knowledge wise
of the nastiest
fundamentals course.
Before you start
watching this course
we recommend taking a step back and checking
out the official fundamentals course
if you're not already
comfortable witness
asked
is.
In this extension
Wilson that you're
familiar with everything
that we've covered in
that fundamentals course.
So
let's go ahead and get started.