Before we kick things off.
Let's start by generating an empty nest as
application just so we have something we
can work with in
the following lessons.
Let's head over to our terminals
and entering the
nest new command.
Calling our project
virtual dash facility
or whatever you wish.
Once everything
finishes installing
let's cd or change directory into our
newly created application in our case by
entering cd virtual
dashed facility.
With our initial starter
and place we can
now start or application
in development mode
with n p m run
start colon depth.
As always
our application will now be
available on port three thousand
and there we have it
were all set and ready to
continue moving forward.