Micro services are a software
development technique.
A variant of the service oriented
architecture or esa way architectural style
that structures and application
as a collection of loosely coupled.
Fine grained services.
With microservices.
We could organize
our backend as a set of
services that are highly
maintainable testable
independently deployable
in organized around
business capabilities.
Often times they are
owned by a small team
since microservices encapsulate
specific smaller domains.
The benefits of
microservices are numerous
let's look at some of the most
important and valuable benefits.
Independent deployments.
We can deploy each
service independently.
Which means we can
deploy more often and faster.
We can also scale each service
independently which means
we can scale only the
services that need to be scaled.
Modularity.
This makes the application
easier to understand
develop and test.
Different teams can
work on different services
without having to know
the details of other services.
Technology diversity.
We could use different
technologies for different
services for example we can
use know js for one service
and java for another service.
On the other hand
microservices
also have some drawbacks.
Complexity.
With microservices we need
to deal with distributed systems
which are more complex
than the monolithic applications.
Also
enter service communication
has a higher latency
then in-process calls in
monolithic applications.
Data consistency.
Maintaining data consistency
across services is challenging.
Some operations may require
transactions that span multiple services
which is not that
simple to implement.
Testing.
Testing microservices is more complex
than testing monolithic applications.
The test each
service in isolation.
We need to mock
all the other services.
Also
we need to test the
integration between services
and to end and
integration tests.
And deployment complexity.
We need to deploy
multiple services here
which is of course more complex than
deploying a single monolithic application.
And of course there are several others
that we didn't get to dive into here.
So as we can see.
Microservice architecture
has its fair share of pros
and cons as thus everything
and software development.
It's not a silver bullet
and it's not suitable
for every application
as a introduces additional
complexity and overhead.
New problems
and new challenges
that we need to deal with
such as network latency.
Fault tolerance
data consistency etc.
As software developers
will need to always carefully consider
the pros and cons before we decide to use
microservices for any given
system we're working on.