When working in a
monolithic architecture
with a single application that
contains all of our business logic.
These monolithic applications
are usually divided into modules
but all these modules
are deployed together
as a single unit.
These applications are usually
deployed onto a single server
and all the modules share
the same memory ansi huh.
The modules communicate
with each other
using in-process calls
be it.
Function calls method calls etc.
That's why we can easily
share data between modules
and we can also use transactions
that span multiple modules.
Also
we can easily debug
monolithic applications
as we have a single process
and we can easily
trace the execution flow.
On the other hand
and a microservices architecture that
we learned about in a previous lesson.
We have a set of small
services that are deployed
independently.
Each service is a separate
application that contains
all of the business logic
for a specific domain.
The services can communicate
with each other using the network
via http
tcp etc
or message brokers
such as rabbit em que
kafka
and so on and so forth.
Just keep in mind that each
architecture has its pros and cons.
Monolithic applications are
usually easier to develop Andy bug.
In there are also
easier to deploy.
On the other hand microservices tend
to be easier to scale and maintain in are
usually more
resilient to failures.