In this lesson will create our first
microservice and call it workflows dash service.
Our existing virtual
facility service that
were created near the
beginning of this course.
Will use this new microservice
to manage workflows.
Meaning create
monitor etc.
To make things simpler
will use the nastiest cla to convert
our project into a mono repo.
Will also use the cla to generate the
new microservice within this motto repo.
Just in case you're not
familiar with the term
a mono repo is a single repository
that contains multiple projects.
In our case.
Will have to projects
eat virtual facility project our
existing nest yes application
and the workflows
service project.
Our new microservice.
Having them both
in a single repository
will make it easy ear to share interfaces
models in other common code between them.
So let's get started by
opening up our terminal
and running the
following command.
Nest g app workflows
dash service.
This command will generate
a new nest yes application
called workflows service and
place it in the apps directory.
Who will also update
the nest sila Jace on file
and add a new workflows
day ash service entry
to the projects section.
If we look at the
directory structure
we can see that instead of
having a src or source folder.
We now have to applications
virtual dash facility and
workflows dash service.
Both located
in the apps directory.
To keep things simple
will use http as the communication
protocol between the two applications.
We'll dive into other
protocols and built in
message broker
integrations in future lessons.
Before we proceed.
Let's make sure we update
the port on which the workflows
service application will
run to avoid conflicts.
Let's open up the
workflows service main t
file
and update the port to
three thousand and one.
This way.
Both applications will
run on different ports
and will be able to
run them side by side.
Of all right so let's get her hands dirty
and start by creating a new resource in the
workflow service application
calling it workflows service.
Will use the nastiest zeolite
to generate this resource for us
so let's head over to our terminals
and run the following command.
Nest g resource workflows.
The seal i will then
prompted to select which
application where we want
to gen rate this resource and.
Will select the workflows
service application.
Then the sale i will
generate the resource for us
and update the workflows
service application module.
Next up inside of the
virtual facility application
let's create a new
buildings modul that will
use this workflow service
to manage workflows.
So let's run the
following command.
Nest g resource buildings.
With this resource and place.
Let's open up the newly
generated building service
file and add a new method
here called create workflow.
This method
will call the workflows
service to create
a new workflow.
Ideally we would declare this
logic in a separate workflows service
but for the sake of simplicity
will keep everything any
single service for now.
No.
For those using older
versions of no jas.
Lower than virgin seventeen
you may need to install the no dash
fetch package to use the fetch function or
alternatively use
nastiest slash axios
for the same functionality.
Now.
Let's add a call to this new method
right after we create a new building.
So in the file let's head
to the create method
and add the following
code inside their.
As always the code can be
found below the course video.
Excellent.
Let's head of or to our terminal
and now start both applications.
Let's enter in
and p m run start com def
dash dash virtual dash facility.
And in a separate
terminal window
and pm run start calling def
dash dash workflows
dash service.
With both applications
running let's use curl to
create a new building
and test everything out.
If we look at the terminal where the
virtual facility application is running
we can see that
there are no errors
this means we successfully called
the workflow service application
from the virtual facility application and
have our first microservices up and running
great job.
Of course everything we have here so
far is all very basic but we have a great
starting point for us
to learn more about
microservices and how
to use them witness Jess.
In the next many lessons
will dive even deeper
into the microservices
architecture and learn
how to use ness js
to build even the most complex
microservice applications.