With the database
per service pattern
each service has its own
dedicated database that
cannot be directly access
by any other services.
This pattern is usually used
when we want to achieve a high
level of isolation between services.
It's also very useful
for one is different
database technologies
for different services.
So there are a few different ways to keep
a services persistence they'd a private.
Private tables per service.
This means that each service.
Owns a set of tables that must
only be accessed by that service.
Other services cannot
access these tables director.
If other services need to
query data in these tables.
They must do it through
the owning service.
Scheme up her service.
Each service has a database
schema that's private to that service.
And database server per service.
Each service has its own
dedicated database server.
This approach requires
much more resources but
it also provides a
higher level of isolation.
While having a separate
database server per service
generally makes a lot of
sense for larger organizations.
Where teams are working
on different services.
It's not always the best
choice for smaller organizations.
Of the drawbacks
of this approach are
increased complexity and cost.
Managing distributed
transactions is significantly
more complex than
local transit actions.
Some queries may require
data from multiple services.
Which means we need
to implement joins across
services which can
lead to increased latency
increased complexity
etc.
On the other hand.
Having a shared database server for all
services is also considered a bad practice.
As a introduces tight
coupling between services.
If one service changes
the database schema.
All other services need
to be updated as well.
Also if one service has a
bug that corrupts the database.
All other services will
be affected by this as well.
Coordinating schema changes
migrations etc between services
can also be very challenging
but not to say impossible.
Therefore in this course will be using
the database per service approach.
Although it may make things overly
complex for our small application.
A may not be the best choice for our
own product or organizations use case.
This remember to always make sure
to carefully consider the pros and cons
before deciding on an
architect you for your system.
As it's not a one size
for it's all solution.