In this lesson
will configure docker
compose to run our virtual
facility and workflows
service applications.
As was provision a dedicated
postgres sql database
or each application.
If you're not familiar
with docker compose.
It's a tool for defining and running
multi container docker applications.
With docker compose we can use a yaml
file to configure our application services
then.
With a single command
we can create and start all the
services from our configuration.
Let's start by creating a
new docker dash compose
yeah html file in the
root of our project.
This file will contain
the configuration
for our docker compose setup.
Again you can find the content
for this file below the course video.
Also.
We will need a dockerfile
that will be used to
build the docker image
for our applications.
Let's create a new dockerfile
in the root of our project
and add the following code.
With this violent place
as head over to our terminal
and run the following commands.
Docker compose
up.
Test that everything
is working as expected.
Let's use curl to create
a new building again.
As we can see
the request was
not yet successful.
This is because we
need to update the virtual
facility application to use
the workflow service host.
Instead of using local host.
Since now or applications are
running inside of docker containers.
To fix this
let's open up the buildings service ts
file an update the create workflow method.
Use the workflows dash
service host instead of local host.
Let's try that curl
command again.
And as we can see
the request was
now successful great.
However our services don't connect
to their corresponding databases yet.
As this is something we've already
covered in the fundamentals course
will skip over the details and
just move right into the code.
First
when you to install some
required dependencies.
Will be using type r m for
this courses or m needs but of
course you may need to use
something completely different
in your app or
organization but don't worry.
Everything we're doing
in this course would all still
the same.
So let's go ahead and install
the nastiest slashed her or him.
A bar him
and pg a proposed gross.
Once the installation
process is complete.
Will create two entities.
Building
in the virtual
facility application.
And workflow in the
workflows application.
As these entities will live
in separate applications.
We won't be able to declare a one
too many relationship between them.
Instead we'll use a building
ID field in the workflow entity
to store the idea of the building
to which the workflow belongs.
Next
let's make sure we update the virtual
facility application module to import the type
r ram module and configure it to connect
to the virtual dash facility database.
We'll also need to update the
workflows service application
module to connect to the
workflows service database.
With this and place.
Let's open up the
building service file
and use the type or
ram repository here
replacing all of the
mocked methods.
Next up
let's update the buildings module t s file
to import type or a module dot for feature.
Passing in the building
entity to the array.
That the service could
inject the buildings repository.
And likewise
let's update the workflows
service he has file
replacing all the mock
methods here as well.
And let's not forget
the workflows module
and let's make sure we import
the type or a module for feature
passing in the workflow
entity here as well.
Great.
Once again we're moving fast here
since we've covered all of these basic
m concepts and the
fundamentals course.
You could find the code to copy
paste below the course video as always.
Moving on to newer topics
to reuse data transfer object
classes between applications.
When need to generate a new
workflows library using the nastiest July.
One head over to our terminal
and run the following command.
Nest g lib
workflows.
Let's start by removing
the unnecessary auto
generated files from
the workflows library.
Next up.
Will create a new
detail directory
and create the create dash
workflow dot d t o duck ts file.
Representing the data transfer
object for creating a new workflow.
Before we proceed
let's install the class
transformer and class val
alligator packages that will
use for validation purposes.
Finally.
Has declared the create
workflow detail class
and add the necessary
validation decorators.
Next to this file let's create the
update dash workflow dot d t n t s file
represented the data transfer
object for updating a workflow.
Lastly
let's update the index t s file
to export both of these classes.
Great.
Now with the someplace.
Let's open up our workflows service
file an update the correct method their
to use our newly created
great work float
data transfer object.
We can also remove the auto-generated
detail classes here which were previously
generated by the nest
g resource schematic.
Another thing to note.
Let's not forget to update
the workflows controller file
to use these new data
transfer object classes as well.
Rate so let's save our changes
and to achieve
maximum type safety.
Let's update the
buildings service t
file
to use the workflows library
data transfer object class
also.
Excellent.
Since now our service returns
Jason instead of plain text.
Let's make sure to
change that rez dot
text method to rest up Jason.
And lastly for
debugging purposes.
Let's logged a response
body to the console.
With this in place.
Let's save our changes
head over to our terminal
i run the following
curl command.
As we can see
the request was successful and we can
see the response body in the console great.
This means that we successfully
created a new building.
Let's switch to the other
terminal window and
check to see if the
workflow was created as well.
Perfect.
As we can see
there's a new
workflow with the name
my workflow
and the building
ID is set to one
just as we passed and
and are curl command
rate.
We now have to microservices
that communicate with each other
all while using
separate databases.
Were starting to make
some real progress already
awesome.