Health checks are an essential part
of any production-ready application.
They allow us to monitor the health of our
application as well as its dependencies.
Database external services etc
and quickly detect any
issues that may arise.
Most cloud providers and container orchestrators
also use health checks to determine
if our applique patient is healthy
and ready to receive traffic.
In this lesson
will learn how to add health
checks to our nest js services.
Before we proceed.
Let's install the nastiest
terminus package that
will use to add health
checks to our services.
Once the installation
process is complete
let's generate a new health
module and health controller
using the necessary osceola in
the virtual dash facility application.
So
let's run the
following commands.
Nest g module health
and nest g controller help.
Next
let's import the terminus
module into the health module.
Great.
But the terminus module imported
we can now navigate to the health controller
and add a new get and point that will
return the health
of our application.
So far it always returns true
but we'll update this method in a bit to
return the actual health of our application.
Though let's inject the
health checks service
and type r m health indicator
into the health controller
and use them to check the
actual health of our application.
And lastly
let's not forget to annotate the is healthy
method with the health check decorator.
Right
let's save our changes
head of her to our terminal
and run the following
command to test everything out.
Curl get local hosts three
thousand slash health.
And as we can see in
the response it seems that
everything is working
as expected fantastic.
Before we wrap up this lesson
let's add health checks to the
workflows service application as well.
So let's start by generating a new
health module an health controller they're
using the nes jsc a
again.
Nest g module health
and nest g controller health.
And then replaced the contents of the health
controller with the same code we used in
the virtual facility
application.
And similarly let's
replace the contents of the
health module with the same
code we used once again
in the virtual
facility application.
And that's it perfect.
As we can see our health
modules are currently identical
so we could technically
extract the common code
into a shared library
and reuse it in
both applications.
However as our
application grows.
Will probably want to
add more health checks to
each application and
they will start to diverge
therefore
will keep them separate.
Health checks are vital to
any back and application
and especially important
for microservices
we need to always be aware
if any single service goes down
to do any variety of
reasons so we can have
fail safes and place
to recover the service.
Making sure we don't lose
any transactional data etc.
Although these topics are out of the
scope of this course having health checks
already in place is a great
starting point for our application.