Nats is a lightweight
high performance open
source message broker
for distributed systems
loud native applications and
microservices architectures.
It provides a simple
yet powerful a p i.
At allows us to easily
build distributed systems.
The nats server
is written in the go
programming language
but Clay client libraries
to interact with the server
are available for dozens of
major programming languages.
Nats supports both at most
once and at least once delivery.
It can run anywhere from large
servers and cloud instances.
Through edge gateways
and even Internet of things
i o t devices.
Ness gs provides several built-in
message broker integrations including nets.
We decided to
use it in this course.
Because it's easy to set up
and natively supports request
response communication style
making it simple to migrate.
Given that we're currently using http
for communication between our services.
Note that almost every
transport strategy supported
by nastiest js can be used
for both request response
and event based
communication styles
but some of them are better
suited for one or the other.
Will dive deeper into
this topic in future lessons.
All right so let's get started by
installing the nes js microservices package
that will use to add support for
microservices to our nest chest application.
So far
we didn't need this package as we
were using http for communication
between our services
which is supported
out of the box
by ness Jess court.
Let's also install the nats driver that
will use to connect to the nats server.
Once the installation
process is complete.
Let's open up the
docker compose yaml file
and add a new service
called nets that will run beaten
server.
Let's also add a new environment variable
called natsu rl to the workflow service and
virtual facilities services
that will contain the u r l
of the nats server.
Instead of using
local host as a hosts
we used nats which is the name
of the service we defined above.
This is because docker compose automatically
creates a network for our services
and adds a dns server to it
that resolves service names
the corresponding ip addresses.
This means that we can
use service names instead
of ip addresses to
connect to other services.
Also.
Or two to two is the default port
that the nats server lessons of.
And lastly.
Let's make sure both services
depend on the nats service.
Let's save our changes.
Open up the main ts file in the workflows
service application and update the
bootstrap function to
convert our http application
we hybrid application
that supports both http
and nats entry points.
We'll use connect
microservice to connect to
the nats server and
start all microservices
restart the microservice.
Will also need to import
the transport enum
and microservice options interfaces
from the nastiest microservices package.
Note that instead
of using nest factory
create microservice.
We're using the nes
factory create method
to carry a hybrid application that
supports both http and nats entry points.
This is because we want
to keep the http health
check and points
available in or application.
Great so next up
let's navigate to the
workflows controller file
and up the the create
method to use the
message pattern
decorator.
Instead of the post decorate.
Workflows create
will be the name of the
message pattern that
will use to send messages
to the workflow service.
Will use the same message
pattern in the virtual facility
service to send messages
to the workflows service.
Let's also use the payload decorator
instead of the body decorator now.
Great
let's save our changes and head over
to the virtual facility application now.
Here.
Let's create a new constance
ts file in the source directory
and at the fallen code.
Workflows service constant.
Will represent our
injection token that will used
to inject the workflows
service client to providers.
Next.
Let's open up the
buildings module file
and import the clients module.
Let's pass the client configuration to
the clients module dot register method.
And last but not least.
Let's open up the buildings
service file in eject the
workflow service client into
the buildings service class.
Why a proxy
is a client instance abstraction the
hides the internal implementation of the
currently selected
transport strategy.
In our case it will
be the nats client.
Thanks to this abstraction
we can easily switch
between different transport
strategies without having
to significantly modifier coat.
With this provider injected
what scroll down to the
create workflow method
and updated to use the workflows service
client instead of the fetch function.
Since send returns and
rx Jess observable stream
which is useful when
streaming data between services
we need to use the.
Let's save our changes.
Open up the terminal in run the
following command to start everything up.
Docker compose up.
The test of everything's
working as expected
let's use curl to
create a new building.
Great.
As we can see the
request was successful
we can see the response
body back in the console.
Also
if we switched to the other
terminal window we can
see that a new workflow
was created as well perfect.
So as we can see.
This is how simple it can be to
convert from http to nats Ines Jess.
Now just before we
wrap up this lesson.
Let's also turned the
validation on in both services.
Recovered validation
in the fundamentals
course in case you want
to learn more about it.
So
let's open up the main
t s file in the workflows
service application and
update the bootstrap function
to enable validation.
Also
we need to update the connect
microservice method to instructed
to inherit the global pipes
from the http application.
And lastly
us to the same thing
in the virtual
facility application.
And that's it
we're all set for now.