Before we dive into the differences
between vertical and horizontal scaling
let's first define
what scaling is.
Scaling
is the process of adding more
resources to our application
to handle the increased load.
This can be measured in terms of
requests per second concurrent users etc.
Scaling horizontally and vertically are
similar in that they both involve adding more
computing resources
to our system.
They just do it
in different ways.
Vertically scaling
or scaling up.
Means more resources cpu
memory etc to a single server.
This is usually done by
upgrading the servers hardware
meaning adding more ram cpu etc.
Vertical scaling
is straightforward
but it's usually
limited to the hardware
and can be quite expensive.
Horizontal scaling
or scaling out.
Means adding more servers
notes machines to our system.
Consequently this means
that we need to distribute the
load across multiple
servers which is typically done
using a load balancer.
When deciding between
vertical and horizontal scaling
we need to consider the pros
and cons of each approach.
Or example in a database world
horizontal scaling is usually
based on the partitioning of data.
While with vertical scaling.
Killing is done
through multi-core
for example
by spreading the load between the
cpu and ram resources of the machine.
With horizontal scaling
were not limited by the hardware
but
we need to deal with
other additional complexity.
Much as load balancing
data consistency etc.
In this lesson will demonstrate how
horizontal scaling works in practice
by increasing the number
of instances of our service
using docker compose.
Note that in real world
systems you would use a
container orchestration
tool such as kubernetes
to scale your services
depending on different
metrics such a cpu usage
memory usage traffic etc.
We won't be able to
dive into kubernetes.
Since it's a bit
outside of the scope
and complexity of what we're
trying to learn in this course.
So
let's get started by opening
up art docker compose yaml file
and adding a new deploy
property to the workflows service.
But save our changes
recreate our containers
and start everything up
with docker compose up.
As we can already
see in the logs
there are multiple instances of
the workflows service running now
see
the one two three
suffixes on everything.
Next up.
Let's navigate to the
workflows service file
and declare a new private
variable lager as follows.
With this variable in place
let's update the create method to
lock that we're creating a new workflow.
Let's save our changes
had
to the terminal and create
three buildings using curl.
Now
let's switch to the other terminal
window and check those logs.
As we can see.
Instead of distributing load
between multiple instances
nats delivered the
message to all instances.
Which is known as broadcasting
but that's actually
not what we want.
Let's fixed up real quick.
In nats when subscribers register themselves
to retrieve messages from a publisher
the one to n.
Van out pattern of messaging ensures
that any message sent by a publisher
reaches all subscribers
that have registered.
Nats provides in
additional feature named
q
which allows subscribers to register
themselves as part of a queue.
Subscribers that
are part of a queue
form a queue group.
So.
How can we configure our subscribers
to be a part of a queue group that.
Well.
We can do this by passing the
queue option to the server configuration.
So let's open up the main t s file
in the workflows service application
and update the connect
microservice method
to pass the queue option
to the server configuration.
Let's save our changes
head over to the terminal and crete
three buildings once again using curl.
Switch to the other terminal window
and once again let's check those logs.
And look at that.
As we can see.
The load now distributed between multiple
instances of the workflows service great.
As we mentioned at the beginning of this
lesson in real-world systems you would use a
container orchestration tool such
as kubernetes to scale your services.
Were putting on different
metrics such a cpu usage
memory usage traffic etc.
In our case here
since we're just doing things
for demonstration purposes
we simply hard-coded
the number of instances
in our docker compose file.