In this lesson
let's dive into an learn
about the differences between
the request response and
event driven communication styles
and when to use
each one of them.
The request response message thou is
useful when you need to exchange messages
between various
external services.
With this paradigm
you can be certain that a service
has actually received the message
without the need to
manually implement
message acknowledgment
or act protocol.
Like any software
development paradigm
nothing is a silver bullet.
Try to keep in mind that the request response
paradigm is not always the best choice.
For example
trimming transporters that use
log base persistence such as kafka
are optimized for solving
a different range of issues
or aligned
with an event
messaging paradigm.
To enable the request
response message type.
Ness create to logical channels
one is responsible for
transferring the data.
While the other waits
for incoming responses.
Are some underlying
transports such as nats
this dual channel support
is provided out of the box.
Or others nest compensates by me
manually creating separate channels
that can be an overhead for this
so
if you do not require a
request response message thou
you should consider using
the event based method.
To create a message handler based
on their request response paradigm
we can use the message
pattern decorator.
While the request response method is ideal
for exchanging messages between services.
It is less suitable when your
message thou is event based.
For example.
When you just want to publish
events without waiting for a response.
In that case.
You do not need the
overhead required by
request response for
maintaining two channels.
Suppose you would like to simply notify
another service that a certain condition has
occurred in this
part of the system.
If that's your use case
then you should most likely use
the event based message style.
To declare an event handler
we can simply as the
event pattern decorator.
Nest provides several built-in
transport strategies including http.
Nats
kafka.
Rabbit m q and many others.
Each of these transport strategies
can be used for both request response
and event based
communication styles
but some of them are better
suited for one not the other.
For example
http is a request response
protocol so it's better
suited for a request
response communication style.
On the other hand
Africa is a message broker
so it's better suited for an
event based communication style.
With ness js
we can also integrate with other protocols
and message brokers by creating our own
custom transport strategies.
However
we won't be diving into
this topic in this course so.
If you're interested in
learning more about this
check out the official
nastiest documentation
in a link can be found
rebel the course video.