So far
we've covered the basics of microservices
and learn how to create a simple
microservice based
application using ness js.
We use the request response communication
style with a nats message broker
to exchange messages
between our services.
In this lesson
will be learning about how we can use the
event based communication style to create
an alarm service that
will listen for new alarms.
Let's start
by generating a new
alarms service application
using the and sgs
ally.
So a
over to our terminal
and run the following command.
Nest g app
alarms dash service.
Also let's generate a new
application called alarm stash
generator though we used
for demonstration purposes.
This application will
periodically generate
new alarms and send
them to the alarm service.
To schedule the generation of new alarms
will use the nastiest schedule package so
let's make sure we
install it with m p m i
at ness jazz slush schedule.
Once the installation
is complete
let's open up our docker compose
yaml file and add some new services.
As always you can find all code
snippets below the course video.
Will focus on the
alarms service first.
Before we can add
a new event handler.
Let's head over
to the main ts file
and follow the same steps we did in
the previous lesson to convert our http
application to a
hybrid application.
That supports both http
and nats entry points.
Note that since we haven't implemented any
health check and points in this service we
could technically use
the create microservice
method instead of the
connect microservice method.
However
to keep a consistent
with the workflow service
will stick with
connect Microsoft's.
Next
let's open the alarm service
controller file and replace
the contents of the alarm
service controller class
with the fallen code.
The event pattern decorator here
is used to declare in event handler.
The strength alarm dot
created will be the name of the
event pattern that this event
handler will subscribe to.
Will use the same event pattern
in the alarms generator service to
dispatch events to the alarms service.
Events contrary to the messages
are not expected to return a response.
Regardless of what happens
inside of the event handler
nothing will be sent
back to the center.
So let's save our changes and head over
to the alarmed generator application now.
Alarms generator will be a simple application
that will periodically generate new
alarms and sent him
to the alarms service.
In a real-world application.
This service would of
course be replaced by a
real alarm system for
example an external service.
That would notify the alarm service
when a new alarm is triggered.
Think of this service
as a mock service
that will I'll use just for
demonstration purposes.
Starting off
we can replace the main t
s file with the following code.
Since we don't need this
application to listen to http requests
we can remove the
aap dot listen call
and convert this ness application
to a stand alone application.
With this in place let's open up
the alarms generator module file.
Import the schedule module
and remove the alarms
generator controller class.
Also
let's not forget to remove the actual
alarm generator controller file as well.
Next.
Let's create eight constants t
file and add the fallen coat.
We can use this constant
alarm service to register
a new clients of the
clients module in the
alarm generator module file.
Next up.
Inside of the alarms generator
service will create a new method
called generate alarm that will
emit an event to the alarm service.
Note that to dispatch and event.
We use the emit method
instead of the send method.
To instruct a framework to
trigger this method periodically
will use the interval decorator.
And lastly
let's inject the alarm service
using the inject decorator
passing alarms underscore
service constant to it
and add the private access
modifier to the alarm service property.
Let's save our changes
and head over to the terminal
and run the following
command to start everything up.
Docker compose up.
Let's wait till everything's
up and running
and check the logs.
As we can see the alarm
services now receiving
new alarms from the
alarms generator service.
So to summarize.
We learned how to use the event based
communications thou nsg as to dispatch
asynchronous events
which when our services.
We also learned how to use
the event pattern decorator
declare an event handler.
The alarms gen narrator
service is just a mock
service that we used for
demonstration purposes.
In real world application.
This service will be replaced by a real
alarm system for example an external service
that would notify the alarm
service whenever a new alarm
is triggered.
Fortunately the concepts we've learned
in this lesson would remain the same
and will be applicable to your
future nasty as applications.