Microservices can be defined as a software
development technique that structures and
application as a collection
of loosely coupled services.
Each service is designed to perform a
single function and communicate with other
services through a well-defined
interface using a lightweight mechanism
such as and http based a b i.
Now when building more sophisticated
applications we often need to perform complex
operations that span
multiple services.
For example
when a new alarm is created
we might need to first parse the obfuscated
alarm data coming from an external system
then
pass it to the a i driven alarm
classification service to classify the alarm
and finally passed
the classified alarm
to the alarm notification
service to notify other services.
Or perhaps a user
about that alarm.
In this use case we need to come up
with a way to coordinate these services
and defined the order in
which they should be executed.
There are two common
approaches to this problem.
Orchestration and choreography.
Let's take a look at each
one of those in more detail.
Orchestration is a centralized
approach to service coordination.
In this approach we have a central component
called orchestrator that is responsible
for coordinating the
execution of services.
This orchestrator is
aware of the state of each
service and knows exactly
went to evoke each service.
The orchestrator is also risk impossible
for handling errors and reach rise.
Note that this orchestrator could be
implemented as either a separate service.
Or it could be part of one
of the existing services.
You better understand
how orchestration works.
Let's take a look at
the following example.
In this code snippet here
we can see a simple
orchestrator that is responsible
for coordinating the
execution of three services.
Parse alarm data
classify alarm and notify.
Each operation is represented
as a separate function.
Presume mobley calling another
microservice under the hood.
The orchestrator is
responsible for invoking
these functions in the
correct order and if needed
handling any errors
and reach tries.
One of the main advantages of this approach
is that it's simple and easy to do but
however services are tightly
coupled to the orchestrated.
On the other hand.
Choreography is a decentralized
approach to service coordination.
In this approach each service is responsible
for handling its own state and knows
exactly when to
invoke other services.
The services communicate
with each other using events.
The made advantage of this approach
is that it's more flexible and scalable
however
it's also more complex
in harder to debug.
Each of these approaches
has its own pros and
cons as there is no
one size fits all solution.
In some cases.
Orchestration might be a
better choice while and others
choreography might
work out better for you
it all depends on
your specific use case.
In the next lesson will implement the
orchestration approach in our application
but just always remember that this is
just one of the possible design choices.