In this lesson
will create to new services.
Alarms classifier service and notification
service that will be responsible for
classifying alarms and
notifying other services or users
about the alarm.
In a real world application
the alarm classifier
service would classify
alarms or alarm groups
using ai or ml algorithms.
This service would use a
pre-trained model to classify
alarms is either critical
non critical or invalid.
With the microservices
architecture
were free to use any programming language
or framework to implement our services.
So for example this service
could be implemented in python
and simply expose
http endpoints
or connect to a nat server to
communicate with other our services.
Similarly the notification
service will be responsible
for notifying other services
or users about the alarm.
For example
it could send an email to the building
manager or department about the alarm.
It could also send an sms
message to the maintenance team.
Since all of these functionalities are
outside of the scope of this course will
implement these services
as mock services that
will simply log the received
alarms of the console.
So.
Let's start by generating a new
alarms classifier service application
using the nes jsc alive.
So let's head over to our terminal
and run the following command.
Nest g app alarms dash
classifier dash service.
Also.
Must generate the notification service
with nest g app notifications dash service.
Next up let's open up the docker
compose yaml file and add new services.
Let's focus on the alarms
classifier service first.
Before we can add a
new message handler.
Let's head over
to the main t s file
and follow the same steps we did in previous
lessons to convert our http application
to a hybrid app
that supports both
http
and nats entry points.
Next up
let's open the alarms classifier service
controller file and replaced the contents of
the alarms classifier
service controller class
with the following code.
The classify alarm method
shown here will randomly
return critical non critical
or invalid categories
as we've mentioned earlier
in a real world application this service
would classify alarms or alarm groups using
artificial intelligence or
machine learning algorithms.
So.
Let's save our changes and head over to the
notification service application though.
Before we can add a new event handler let's
head over to the main t s file again and
follow the same
steps we just did
and convert our http
application to a hybrid one
supporting both http
and data entry points.
By the way instead of manually updating
this main t s file every time we generate a
new application we
could create a new custom
schematic that will do all
of this and summed for us.
Check out the advanced concepts course
extension link below the video in the lesson
description if you're interested
in learning more about this topic.
Next up let's open the notification service
controller file an replaced the contents
of the notification service controller
class with the following code.
Now that we are both
services and place let's
navigate to the alarms
service application
and create a constants t s file.
And then add the fallen
constant inside of it.
Will use this constant
to register a new client
with the use of clients module
in the alarm service module t
file.
Next up let's open up the alarm service
controller file in inject message broker
client using the
inject decorating.
Now using the orchestrator approach
that we introduced in a previous lesson.
Let's update the create method
here to first classify the alarm
and then notify other
services about it.
Let's save our changes
and head over to the terminal
and run the following
command to start everything up.
Docker compose up.
Let's wait till everything is up
and running and check the logs.
And there we have it
as we can see the alarm
service is now receiving
the new alarms from the
alarms generator service.
Classifying them using
the alarms classifier service
and notifying other
services about the alarm
using the notification service.
Fantastic.
Recovered quite a lot in this lesson but
hopefully you can see the power of the
orchestration approach
to microservices.
We are now able to fairly
easily manage an coordinate
the interactions between
multiple microservices
to achieve any
specific business goal.