Nats is a popular
message broker that is often
used in microservices
based applications.
However
as we mentioned
in a previous lesson
it's not the only
message broker out there
and depending on your use
case team or requirements
you might want to use a
different message broker.
Thanks to the nest
abstraction layer we can easily switch
between different message brokers without
having to make significant
changes to our code base.
The client proxy class
that we've been using so far
is actually an abstract class
that depending on the
selected transport strategy
will use a different
implementation under the hood.
Similarly we can supply
a different configuration
object to the connect
microservice method.
Specifying that we want to
use a different transport strategy
in the framework will
take care of the rest.
Of course
a more advanced scenarios if
you rely on some the features
that are specific to a
particular transport strategy.
Message acknowledgment
hatters form Matt.
Contexts objects etc.
You might need to make some
extra changes to your code base
but that's not the case for
us here in our codex great.
So in this lesson for
demonstration purposes
will switch from the
nats to rabbit em que.
Make things even simpler for us
will only update virtual
facility and the workflows
service applications and
leave other services as they are.
Otherwise we'd have to make even more
irrelevant changes to our code base making
things unnecessarily
overcomplicated and hard to follow.
Let's start by updating the
docker compose yaml file
and adding the
rabbit mq service.
Or simplicity sake.
Will keep the net service
as well just as a reference.
Also
let's make sure we make both services
virtual facility and workflows service depend
on the rabbit 'em cute
docker service right now.
Next up let's declare the rabbit mq
underscore your rail environment variable.
Great.
So before we start making
any changes to our code base.
Let's make sure we installed the
necessary dependencies for rabbit m q.
So in our terminals
let's run and p m i.
A m kewpie lib
and am kewpie
connection manager.
Once the installation
is complete.
Let's open up the main ts file
in our workflows
service application and
update the connect
microservice method
to use the rabbit mq
transport strategy.
Next
let's navigate to the virtual facility
application and open up the buildings module t
file.
Your
will update the clients
module configuration to
use the rabbit mq
transport strategy as well.
Perfect.
And once again just as a quick
reminder were only updating
the virtual facility and
workflows service applications.
Otherwise we would have
to make a lot of changes to
our code base and that's
not the point of this less.
Okay so next
let's also temporarily
disable the alarms generator
service since we won't
be needing it for now.
Let's navigate to the
alarms generator service vile
and comment out
the interval decorator.
With this change
our alarms generator won't be
generating no alarms any more.
Making our logs easier
to follow and read.
Let's save our changes
and head over to the terminal
and run the following
command to start everything up.
Docker compose up.
Once everything
is up and running
let's create a new
building using curl.
As always you can find this crow
command below the course video.
And as we can see from our logs our request
was successfully processed and a new
building and its workflow
were created great.
Oh and this lesson
we showed just how easy it
is the switch between different
message brokers using the
nest yes abstraction layer.
We also learned how to use the very
popular rabbit em que as a message broker
in our nest microservice
applications.
Just remember that nest the does make
switching transports much simpler overall.
Especially in our case.
We were already using hyper specific
methods etc from our first transport
that we are moving
away from which was nets.
This made the entire
process even smoother for us.
In cases where you
might have done something
specific such as
manipulating headers etc
you just need to spend
a little bit of extra time
transitioning those to
use your new transport
but otherwise.
Everything else we did here
would stay exactly the same.