Acknowledgement is
basically a notification
for the message broker that a particular
message has been processed and the broker
does not need to
worry about it any more.
In particular
it should read deliver the message
to this or some other consumer.
With the acknowledgment
mechanism we can ensure that
a message is not lost in
case of a service failure.
Or message processing error.
You can also guarantee data
consistency among different services.
By default rabbit em que transporter
automatically acknowledges messages after their
received by the
consumer service.
However
in some cases
we might want to manually
acknowledge messages.
Let's take a closer look at show
how all of this works in practice.
Let's open up the notification service
controller file an update the send
notification method to always throw an
error to simulate a message processing air.
In a real world system this could happen if
an email servers down just as an example.
We also have to re enable the alarm the
generator service so let's open up the alarm
generator service file an
uncommon the interval decorator.
Now next up.
We need to migrate the
notification service to rabbits q.
Let's first open up our
docker compose yaml file.
An update the notification service
to depend on the rabbit mq service.
Next declare the rabbit
em que underscore your
environment variable so
that the notification service
can connect to the
rabbit em que server.
Similarly.
Let's also do the same
for the alarms service.
With all of this and place
must navigate to the notification service
application and open up the main t s file.
Update the connect microservice method
to use the rabbit mq transport strategy.
Lastly we also have to update the
alarms service application which is our
orchestrator to use
the rabbit em que client
when sending events to
the notifications service.
So.
Let's open up our constants t s file and
first rename the existing constant to nats
underscore message
underscore borough occur.
Next let's declare a new constant called
notifications underscore service right after
the nats message
broker constant.
With that in place.
Let's open up our
alarms service module file
and update the clients module
configuration to register to clients.
One for the nats transport strategy and
another for the rabbit mq transport strategy.
Specifically for the
notifications service.
Great
now with the climb
provider registered
let's open up the alarm service controller
file in inject the notification service
client with the
inject decorator.
Just for purity sake let's also renamed
the message broker property here to nats
message broker so we can
distinguish between the two.
And the last but not least
let scroll down to
the create method
and update decode to use the notification
service client instead of the message
broker client for
sending notifications.
Let's save our changes
head over to the terminal
and make sure everything
is up and running.
As if we can see from
the logs the failed to send
notification era was
logged down to our console.
However
the message was not redelivery
to the consumer service.
This is because the rabbit mq transport
strategy as we mentioned earlier.
Automatically acknowledges messages after
delivering them to the consumer service.
So
how can we manually
acknowledge messages.
Well
we can do this by first turning off the
auto acknowledgement feature and then
manually acknowledging messages
using the channel act method.
So let's open up our main
t s file in the notification
service application and update
the connect microservice method
setting the no act attribute
to false.
With this change in place
now the message broker will
not automatically acknowledged
messages to test it out.
Let's switch over to our terminal
again and observe those logs.
So it seems that are
messages are still not
immediately re deliver
to the consumer service
but why is there.
Well in Rabat em que non acknowledged
messages are not deleted from the q and a re
deliver to the consumer service
when the consumer service restarts.
Which means that in
order to see message is
being re delivered to
the notification service
we need to restarted.
The trigger a restart
but simply update the
notification service
controller file answer save it.
Let's switch over to the terminal
again and observe those locks.
And as we can see
from the logs here.
Several previously non acknowledge messages
were re delivered to the service great.
But what if we wanted
messages to be re
delivered immediately
instead of waiting for
the service to restart.
Well
we could do this by using
the channel nac method.
For this
we need to inject the
are m q context using the
c t x puram
decorator as follows.
And then
inside of the send
notification method we can use
the channel neck method
to reject the message.
To avoid entering
an infinite loop.
Will also check to see if the
message was already re deliver.
If so.
Will acknowledge the
message and discarded.
So let's save our
changes and head over to
the terminal and observe
those logs once more.
And as we can see the message was immediately
re delivered to the consumer service
after it was reject and eventually
acknowledged and discarded excellent.
So to summarize in this lesson we learned
how to manually acknowledged messages using
the channel act and
channel nac methods.
We also learn that
in Rabat em que.
Non acknowledged
messages are not deleted from
the q and a re delivered
to the consumer service
when the consumer
service restarts.