In monolithic applications
we might use acid for
our database transactions
which stands for atomicity
consistency
isolation and durability
to ensure data consistency.
However
with microservices architectures
we don't have this luxury anymore.
Instead we need to come
up with a different approach to
ensure data consistency
among all of our different services.
For example
in our current system.
When we create a new building we first and
sir a new building into the database and
then create a new
workflow for this building
i calling the workflows service.
However
what if the workflows
services down and our
message broker fails to
deliver the message later.
What if for some
non obvious reason.
The workflow service fails to create
a new workflow for this building.
While in this case
will end up with an inconsistent
state in our system and also
we won't have a mechanism
in place to recover from this day.
We could of course wrap both calls in a
database transaction and rollback data
changes if the
workflow creation fails
but this isn't
always that simple.
If we had multiple
services involved
let's say services that must
be called and a specific order.
Some changes might be
already committed to the database
in rolling back local changes
wouldn't help us that much.
It might even put us in
an even worse situation
if some of those
rollbacks failed etc.
So how can we
solve this problem.
Well there are several
different approaches out there
but in this course will
focus on two of them.
The inbox pattern
and the outbox better.
There's also a third
technique called sagas
which is useful for designing
long running business transactions.
But unfortunately
we won't have time to
cover that in this course
but we dive into it in the architecture
and advanced patterns course extension.
As it's a much larger
and broader topic.
With these inbox and
outbox patterns we can
achieve these so-called
eventual consistency model
which means of the system state
will eventually become consistent
but as the name implies
it might take some time.
In other words
we can't guarantee that
the system will immediately
become consistent and we
need to take this into account.
Whether we could use eventual consistency
in our system or not depends on specific
use cases application
requirements and business needs
to always make sure to carefully
evaluate the pros and cons of each approach
before making a decision.