The transactional outbox pattern is a design
pattern that can be used to ensure data
consistency among
different services.
In this pattern instead
of directly calling other
services are sending
messages to the message broker
as part of the
local transaction.
We first and sir a new
message into the database table
called outbox and then.
Send it to the other services using a
separate process called outbox processor.
For example when we create a
new building in our current system
we first and sir a new building into the
database and then create a new workflow for
this building by calling
the workflows service.
With the transactional
outbox pattern.
Instead of calling
the workflows service
we were the insert a new
record to the outbox table
as part of the local database to
transaction that represents a task.
Which eventually
we'll call this service.
Lastly we would need a background job or
process called outbox processor that would
periodically check the
outbox table for new
messages and send them
to the message broker.
Don't worry if all of this sounds a bit
confusing at this point things will become
much clearer once we implement this pattern
in our application in just a moment.
Okay so let's start things off
by creating a new outbox module
in the virtual facility project.
Know that instead of generating this
module in the virtual facility we could
technically generated
in the libs folder
making it available to all other
applications in our motto repo.
It is very likely that we
may end up needing this
functionality in other
applications after all
as an exercise try to
generate a new library
yourself and move
the outbox module their.
Next
let create a new outbox entity with
a few columns in the outbox module.
And next
let's generate a new outbox service
file in the outbox module as well.
Once the file as generated
let's inject the outbox repository provider
using the inject repository decorate.
Next
let's declare a new get
unprocessed messages method
that will return all
unprocessed messages.
This method here takes
and options parameter that
lets us filter messages
by the target service.
Also
all messages are sorted
by the created at column in a
ending order.
Let's save our changes and
open up the outbox module file.
Let's import the type or a
module for feature method
and pass the
outbox entity to it.
Also will need the workflows service client
available in the context of this module
slots import the clients module and supply
the workflows service configuration there.
Great.
Note that registering this provider
here effectively means that will have two
different client instances
for the workflow service.
One provided in the
buildings module file
and one provided in
the outbox module file.
Ideally.
We create a new module
that will be responsible
for providing the
workflow service client
but for simplicity's sake.
Will leave it as is for now.
Now that we have the
outbox module in place
let's open up the building
service file and inject
the data source provider
using the standard approach.
Next
let's scroll down to
the create method
and update the code to
initialize the transaction.
With the transaction initialized
let's retrieve the buildings repository
from the query runner object.
Also.
Lets retrieve the outbox
repository so we can
insert a new message
into the outbox table.
Let's wrap everything up
in a try catch block and roll
back the transaction if
an error occurs otherwise.
Let's commit the transaction.
Now using our local
buildings repository
let's insert a new
building into the database.
Afterwards
but since
a new message
into the outbox table.
Perfect.
Now
whenever we create
a new building will also
and sir a new message
into that outbox table.
If the transaction fails.
The message won't be inserted
and so it will be never sent
to the workflows service.
The last remaining step
we have is to create a new
background job or process
called the outbox processor.
As processor will periodically checked
the outbox table for new messages and send
them to the message
broker if any are found.
We could also listened
to the postgres events to
trigger the senate process
but for simplicity's sake.
Will use a simple crown
based approach in this course.
Just know that you have
multiple choices for api since here
on how to handle this.
So let's create a new
outbox processor t s
file in the outbox module
with the following content.
With all of our needed
dependencies injected
let's declare a new dispatch
workflow event method
that will send a new event
to art workflows service.
Inside this process
outbox messages method
let's retrieve all unprocessed
messages from our outbox table.
Next
let's iterate over the messages and
send them to our message broker.
And last but not least
let's register the outbox
processor provider
in the outbox module file.
Also let's not forget to import the schedule
module in the app module file so that
our background job or process
can be executed properly.
Let's save our changes and
before we test everything else
let's make sure we also update the workflows
create message handler to use the event
pattern decorator instead of
the message pattern decorator
since we're now
using the emit method
to send event to
the workflow service.
Let's save our changes
here and head over to the
terminal and make sure
everything is up and running.
If you're seeing any
errors just double check
that you followed all
the steps we just covered
if the application is up
and running smoothly.
Let's create a new building
using curl to test everything out.
Now let's wait a little bit.
And as we can see
there's that created workflow log message
which means that our workflow service
successfully received the workflows create
event fantastic everything's working great.
Before we wrap up in this lesson
let speed things up a little bit by
leveraging type of rams entity subscribers.
As we mentioned at the
beginning of this lesson.
We could listen to the post gress
events to trigger this sending process
basically
whenever a new
outbox record is inserted.
Post
would emit an event
instructing or applique
location to send a message
to the message broker.
With type r m
we could achieve a somewhat similar
functionality by using entity subscribers
however
please note that this approach
might not be suitable for all use cases.
If you'd rather process
messages in batches
you should stick to the
cron based approach.
Will just showcase this
option as it might be suitable
for some use cases and
applications out there.
Okay so to begin with the
enemy subscriber approach.
Let's create a new outbox
entity subscriber ts file
in the outbox module
with the following content.
Let's break this class down so
everything makes much more sense.
First were adding this
class to the data source
subscribers array so that
it can listen to entity events.
The listen to method
indicates which entities
the subscriber is interested it.
Lastly.
The after insert method
is called
after the entity is
inserted into the database.
In this method.
You may have noticed
that we also immediately
dispatched the message
to the message broker.
Now with this class and place it's open up
the outbox module file and registered the
outbox entity subscriber
class as a provider.
Let's save our changes as
an head over to the terminal
and make sure everything
is still up and running.
If so
let's again create a
new building using curl.
Now
let's switch back to our terminal
and look at the logs once more.
As we can see
a new workflow was created almost immediately
after the building was created now
it worked.
So to summarize.
In this lesson we learned how to use the
transactional outbox pattern to ensure data
consistency among
different services.
This pattern is particularly useful when we
can't afford to lose messages and we need
to make sure that they
are eventually delivered
to the consumer
service hence achieving
these so called at least
once delivery guaranteed.
Before we finish
let's focus on one little caveat you
might have thought about already.
What if after sending a
message to the workflows service.
The outbox processor
process crashes
before removing the
message from the database.
In this case
when the application recovers
the message will be sent again
and obviously we wouldn't want that.
This is why the outbox pattern lets us
achieve at least once delivery guarantee
not exactly once delivery.
In other words
we can't guarantee that the
message will be delivered exactly once
but we can guarantee
that it will reach the
destination at least once.
We'll talk more
about this predicament
in the next lesson.