In the previous lesson we learned how
to use the transactional outbox pattern to
achieve the at least
once delivery guarantee.
This means our messages might be delivered
more than once and that's why we need to
make sure that our
message handlers
are idempotent.
Idempotent handlers are handlers that
can be called multiple times with the same
input and always
produce the same output.
Without introducing
any side effects.
So for example
if the workflow for a given
building already exists.
We should not create
a new workflow instead
we should simply
ignore the message.
Early if our bill adding
service crashed right
after sending a message
to the message broker
the message will be sent
again when the message
recovers leading to
duplicate workflows.
Which might of course lead us
to having data inconsistencies
duplicate etc.
In this lesson will learn how to use the
inbox pattern to solve this very problem.
The inbox pattern is
fairly similar to the outbox
pattern that we covered
in just the previous lesson.
The inbox pattern though is
more useful on the consumer side
or we have a dedicated table
called inbox.
We're source all
incoming messages.
Instead of outgoing
messages as within the
outbox pattern.
And the difference
in their names.
This consumer service
that we will create
periodically checked the inbox table for
new messages and subsequently processes.
And contrary to
the outbox pattern.
We first save the
message to the inbox table
and then return act
or acknowledge the message
to the message broker.
This way if the consumer service crashes
before sending act the message will be Rita
lever to the consumer
service again.
Hence the guarantee is known as
at least once
delivery guarantee.
However
with the use of the inbox
table we can actually easily
check if the message was
already processed or not.
Which usually lets us achieve
the exactly once delivery guarantee
if we want or need it.
All right enough theory
let's see how all of
this works in practice.
Let's start by creating
a new inbox module
in the workflows service
application with nest gmo
inbox.
Again.
Instead of generating this module
in the workflows service project.
We could technically
generated in the lives folder
making it available to
all other applications.
It is after all very likely
that we may end up needing
this functionality and
other services after all
so once again as an exercise.
Try to generate a new library yourself
and move the inbox module their.
Next.
Let's create a new in box entity with
a few columns in the inbox module.
Next
let's generate a new inbox service ts
file in the inbox module with nest g s
inbox.
Once the files generated
let's inject the data source
provider using the standard approach.
Next up
must declare a new process
inbox messages method
that will be responsible for processing
messages from the inbox table.
Note that this method is slightly
different than what we implemented in the
transactional outbox
pattern lesson.
First instead of returning
unprocessed messages.
Were passing them
to the process function.
This function will be in
charge of processing the
messages and updating
their status to process.
The reason we chose the
callback style approach here
is because we want to leverage the
transaction method from the data source class.
This method
will automatically roll back the
transaction if an error occurs.
This way
we won't even have to worry about
rolling back the transaction ourselves.
Okay so let's save our changes
and open up the inbox module t as file.
Here
let's import the type or a
module for feature method
and passing that
new in box entity to it.
Great.
Let's also make sure to
export the type are a module
and inbox service provider so we
can use them and other modules.
Now that we have the inbox module and place
let's open up the workflows module file
an import the inbox modul there.
Next let's open up the workflows controller
file in eject the inbox repository
provider using the inject
repository decorator like always.
Next
let's scroll down to
the create method
and updated signature to
accept the context object.
Will need this for acknowledging
messages in just a moment.
Inside the create method.
Let's first in sir a new message into
the inbox table if it doesn't exist yet.
And afterwards
let's acknowledge that message.
Perfect.
Now to instruct rabbit em que to immediately
re deliver the message if that sql query
fails we could wrap
everything in a try catch block
and nacht the message
in that catch block.
However
this might not be
ideal because it could
potentially cause a lot of
load on the day database
similar to brute forcing.
More on this in a moment.
Now there are two more things we need
to do before we can test everything out.
First we need to update
the workflows service
main t s file and set the
know an option to false.
This way the message broker won't
automatically acknowledge messages.
Second.
We need to create the
workflows inbox processor file
in the workflows module
with the following content.
Next
will inject the inbox service using the
standard constructor based injection.
Now
let's use this service to process
any unprocessed messages.
Next let's iterate
over all messages
and process them in parallel.
In the code here were
checking to see if the
message pattern is equal
to workflows doc create
and if so.
We're going to call the
create workflow method.
So
let's create this new
create workflow method.
And let's break it down.
First we need to retrieve the workflow
repository from the entity manager instance.
Next using the create method.
We create a new workflow entity
and then save it to the database
using the repositories save method.
Last but not least we
update the message status
to processed so that it
won't be processed again.
Since every operation is
already wrapped in a transaction.
All these changes will be committed to the
database only if all operations succeed.
Now with this class and place
let's register at the workflows
inbox processor provider
in the workflows module file.
And last but not least
let's import the schedule
module in the workflow service
module file so that our
background job or process
can be executed properly.
Excellent.
Let's save our changes
and head over to the terminal
a make sure everything
is still up and running.
If there are no heirs let's
create a new building using curl.
Let's wait a little bit.
And.
As we can see
there's that created workflow log message
which means that the workflow service
successfully processed
the message fantastic.
However
since we're running three separate
workflow services in parallel.
All three nodes will process the
same message at this same time.
This is why we should rather use bull or
bull mq repeatable jobs that support locking
and can be executed only
by a single note at a time.
Instead of the nastiest
schedule approach we're using
for simplicity's
sake in this course.
Alternatively we could
implement a locking
mechanism ourselves
using for example read us.
With the use of the
set annex instruction.
We could create a lock
it would be acquired
by a single note at a time
and once the job is completed.
The node releases
the lock using del.
We could also take
another approach
and try to split the
workload between the notes.
That every notes silex only a
subset of message as the process.
That doesn't overlap
with any other notes
instead of simply ordering all
messages by their creation date.
This way
we could process messages and
parallel without the need for locking.
However
this approach is not always
feasible so keep that a month.
In this lesson just
to finish things off will
implement a very sick
mpl locking mechanism
using the for update no
wait clause in the sql query.
This clause allows us to
lock rosen the database
and prevent other
transactions from reading them.
If another transaction
tries to read a locked row
it will fail immediately
with an error.
This way we could ensure
that only a single transaction
can process a given
message at any given time.
While this approach works
it's far from ideal as
will have to notes running
cron jobs that basically
do nothing but fail.
This is why ideally
we should instead use one of the other
approaches we just mentioned a moment ago.
Alright so let's head
over to the inbox service
file and update the process
inbox messages method
adding a new configuration
object called lock.
In this example
are going to use the pessimistic right mode
with the unlocked option set to no way.
Which means that are
sql query will contain the
for update no wait clause.
Or update causes the
Rose retrieved by the select
statement to be locked
as though as for an update.
This prevents them from being locked
modified or deleted by any other transactions
until the current
transaction hence.
This means that other
transactions that attempt to
update delete or select
for update on these Rose
will be.
Since no way is specified
if another transaction has already
locked any of the selected Rose.
Any other service
trying to read those rows
will fail immediately
with an air as well.
All right so let's save our changes
and head over to our terminal
and make sure everything
is up and running.
If there are no errors let's
create another building
using curl.
And great as we can see only one
workflow service process the message.
The other two failed with an
air fantastic everything worked.
So just the wrap things
up remember that locking
tables arose should
be used with caution.
As it can impact the performance
and concurrency of your application.
We had to do it here just
for simplicity's sake as we
wanted to cohesively wrap
everything up in this lesson
but as we mentioned earlier.
Would want to go with other
approaches like bull bull am
for example.
More importantly.
Always make sure to test whatever
locking strategy you choose thoroughly
to ensure it behaves as expected
and doesn't cause any
adverse effects on your system.
Additionally
be mindful of handling potential errors
that might occur when using no wait
to avoid application crashes
or unexpected behavior.
Also
just remember that
with the current strategy
to out of the three workflow
services will always fail with an air.
This is why for production applications
you should always choose one of the other
approaches men and
earlier in this lesson.
As they will bring you other
benefits your application as well.