Distributed tracing is a technique used in
the context of microservices architecture
who monitor and analyze
the flow of requests
as they traverse multiple
services in a distributed system.
Understanding the
interactions between services
is crucial for diagnosing
performance issues
understanding system behavior
and optimizing overall
system performance.
When a single user
request this processed.
It often involves
multiple interconnected
microservices working
together to fulfill that request.
Distributed tracing helps track the
journey of a request through the services
allowing developers and operations
teams to gain valuable insights into
how the services collaborate
and identify potential
bottlenecks or errors.
This is particularly useful in complex
systems were a single request can trigger a
cascade of events that
spanned multiple services.
To implement distributed tracing in
our system we usually assigned a unique
identifier to each
request and propagated
through the system as
the request is processed.
As identifier
is called a trace ID.
Since trace ID is going to be passed
along with the request it can be used to
correlate all the logs
and events generated by
the services involved in
processing that request.
We can then use tracing
systems to visualize the
entire trace understanding
the latency between services
identify bottlenecks detect
errors and optimize performance.
In this lesson
will focus on how to automatically generate
trace ids and propagate them through the
system in our
nest js applications.
To begin.
Let's create a new library called
tracing using the nest see ally.
Let's open the newly
generated tracing service file
and add the following code.
This method simply generates a random
you you ID that will use as our trace ID.
We need to a sinus ID only once.
When the http request
hits the application
or when a cron job is trigger.
Once we have the trace ID
we need to propagate it through the system
so that it can be used to court late all
the logs in events generated by the services
involved in processing of this request.
In this lesson
will focus on adding tracing to are alarmed
generator events processing pipeline.
So
let's head over to the alarms
generator service file and
update the generate alarm
method to generate a trace ID
using our new tracing service.
In the tattered to
the message headers
under the trace ID key.
Note that to construct
the headers object
we use the nats headers function
as we're using
nats in our system
but
if your system was using
something aside from nats
you'd want to use the
equivalent functionality there.
Now to make the tracing service
available any alarms generator module.
We simply need to import the tracing
module so let's go ahead and do that now.
Aunt perfect.
But all this and place we cannot
switch our focus to the alarms service.
Our goal now is to make sure that the
trace ID is propagated through the system
when the alarm service
processes the message.
Also let's make sure to automatically
right the trace ID to the log messages
so let's create a new
terrain sing lager class
that extends the default
console lager class
and overrides the format
context method for us.
To achieve this.
Let's create a new file in the tracing
library called tracing dot lager dot t s
and add the following code.
And
let's breakfast class down.
First we need to inject the request
context and enquirer objects.
The request context object
represents the execution context
of the incoming request.
Which will used to
extract the trace ID from.
Here we assume that
the logger will be used
only by services that
use the nats transport.
The enquirer object contains
the host object which will
used to extract the name of
the class that using the logger.
So for example
if we use the logger
in the alarm service
the enquirer object will contain
the alarms service instance.
And likewise if we inject the
logger into the alarms controller
the enquirer object will contain
the alarms controller instance.
This means that
are lager provider
will not only be request scoped
but also transient scoped.
Which means that a
new instance of the logger
will be created for
each class that uses it.
Now onto the format
contexts the method.
Here we need to extract
the trace ID from the
request context independent
to the log message.
Finally we need to register the tracing
lager as a provider in the tracing module
so
let's open up the tracing module
t s file and add the following code.
Excellent.
With this and place let's navigate to our
alarm service and update the alarms module
file to import the
tracing module.
Next
let's head of to the
alarms service controller
file and updated to
inject the tracing lager.
Replacing the existing
local lager instance.
Let's save our changes
head over to the terminal
and start everything up
with docker compose up.
Once the application
is up and running.
Let's wait a little bit
and observe the locks.
As we can see
all logs in the alarm service
controller contain a trace idina great.
However
our trace ID is not yet propagated to the
alarms classifier and notification services
let's go ahead and fixed us now.
For this will create a
new client proxy class that
internally updates the message
headers with the trace ID
before publishing a message.
So
as generate a new module first
called nats dash client.
And let's make sure to
select the tracing library
as the modules destination.
Next
inside of this module
let's create a new file called
constance with the following content.
This file simply exports a constant that
will represent the nats client provider.
Next
let's create yet another file and
call it nats dash client dot proxy
with the following content.
As we can see
where injecting the client proxy instance
which represents our message broker
and the context object
into the constructor.
We'll use the client proxy to publish
messages to the message broker
and the context object
to access the trace ID
that we attached to
the message earlier.
Also
been nats client proxy class
marked as request scoped
which means that a
new instance of this class
will be created for
each incoming request.
This is important current because
we want to make sure that each request
has its own instance of
the nats client proxy class.
Next up let's add a new method
called set trace ID
that will be responsible for updating
the message headers with the trace ID.
Here we're checking if the message
is an instance of nats record or know.
If it is.
Recruiting a new instance of
the nats record build their class
and updating its
headers with the trace ID.
Otherwise we're creating a new instance
of the nats record build their class and
updating its data and
headers with the to trace ID.
Finally
let's add a new methods called cent
and emit to mimic the client proxy a PR.
Last but not least
let's open up the nats
client module file and
register this nats client
proxy as a provider
and make sure to export.
Also
let's not forget to import the
client module here with the
exact same configuration
we have in other applications.
Great
but this in place let's switch back to our
alarm service and update the alarm service
module file to import
the nats client module.
You can also remove the nats configuration
from the clients module array.
Last but not least
let's update the alarm service controller
file to inject the nats client proxy
instead of just client proxy.
Just before we
test everything out
let's also update the alarms
classifier service to use the tracing lager
instead of the
local lager instance
so.
As open up our alarms
classifier service module file
and import the
tracing module there.
Next
let's open up the alarms
classifier service controller file
and replaced the
local lager instance
with our new tracing lager.
Let's save our changes.
Head over to the terminal
and take a look at those logs.
As we can see the trace
ID is now propagated to
the alarms class of our
services well fantastic.
The last missing piece
is the notification service.
However it uses rabbit
mq instead of nats so
we would have to create a
new rabbit client proxy class
that would be similar
to the nats client proxy
class we just created.
As this would be a lot of repetitive work
we won't be doing this in this course you
can think of this is a
homework assignment
if you want to practice
your skills and do it yourself.
So to recap
distributed tracing is a powerful tool that
enables developers and operator and teams
to gain deep insights into
complex microservices architectures.
We now have all the basic elements set
up ourselves that could be used in any real
world nastiest microservice
application you work on in the future.
Distributed tracing is so
beneficial microservices.
As it promotes
better understanding
smoother debugging
a more efficient
performance optimization.
Making get it an essential
part of building and maintaining
resilient microservices
based systems.
For production applications
consider using more
sophisticated instrumentation
tools such as oh open telemetry
in combination with jaeger
for visualization and analysis.
These tools provide a more comprehensive
solution for distributed tracing and can be
easily integrated with
nastiest applications.
And that's all for this course
but thank you again for being here
supporting sjs and learning nest with us.
We hope you learned
a lot with this course.
Make sure to check out the
entire catalogue of courses
to learn everything else
from advanced techniques
to nest fundamentals.
See you in the next one.