‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back to this new section of our course here.
‫We are going to give a couple more examples of how to apply some of the concepts that we have learned
‫earlier in the course.
‫We are going to be building here a new screen, which is going to be the course screen.
‫Let's have a look at the screen in the larger window.
‫We are going to click here in the View button in one of the course cards.
‫Let's say that, for example, we click on the Nestjs in practice course we hit view and we are going
‫to be sent to a new screen that contains here a URL segment that is specific to the course that we clicked.
‫Under the courses path.
‫We can see that this new screen, which corresponds to the course component in our front end, is trying
‫to make here an Http request hitting the endpoint slash API slash courses slash nestjs course.
‫So the URL segment that we see here on our browser bar is being used to try to fetch some data for this
‫course from the back end.
‫But we are getting here 404 not found and this is because our back end does not implement this endpoint
‫yet.
‫So let's go ahead and add the controller that is going to handle this request in our back end.
‫Switching back here to our courses controller, we are going to need to add here a new method which
‫also handles a get request, but with a different target path in order to handle the request that the
‫View Course Page is making.
‫So in order to do that, let's create here a new method.
‫We're going to call it Find Course by URL.
‫Now let's see what type of parameters does this method take?
‫First, we are going to annotate this with the get decorator and we are going to specify here what is
‫the path that we are targeting.
‫So we want to target the path slash API slash courses, slash course URL.
‫So we are going to need to add here a new path variable that we are going to call course URL.
‫Let's then inject here the course from the path into a function variable.
‫We are going to define here a variable named course URL.
‫Let's make it a string.
‫And just like before, let's use the param decorator from Nestjs to inject this path variable into the
‫course argument.
‫So now we have here the course URL.
‫Let's now quickly add here some logging to the find course by method so that we can see on the server
‫log that this was called correctly and that we managed to get a handle to the course URL.
‫Now, in order to use this course URL to fetch a course from the MongoDB database, we are going to
‫need a new method in our repository.
‫Let's open here the courses repository file and here we are going to be adding a new method which is
‫also called Find Course by URL.
‫This method is only going to take one argument, which is going to be the course URL, which is a string,
‫and with the course URL we can now query the database.
‫So let's access here the course model.
‫Let's call find here and let's pass in here the parameters for our query.
‫So we are targeting here the URL field from the course entity and we are going to be searching for a
‫URL with this particular value that we got from the Http request.
‫Let's return the output of the call to find because this is going to be a promise.
‫And in order to make it clearer that this method is returning a promise, let's declare it here in the
‫signature of the method.
‫So this returns a promise, of course, before using this method, let's quickly fix here a small problem.
‫We want to find only one model from the database and not several.
‫So let's use here.
‫Find one instead of find.
‫We can now use the find course by URL method here in our controller.
‫Let's define here a new constant called course and let's call the courses DB.
‫Find course by URL method.
‫Let's pass it the course URL and let's await for the resolution of this promise.
‫So now here at this point in our program, we have the instance of the course.
‫So we expect to be able to retrieve a course with this URL from the database.
‫If that's not the case, we are going to be throwing an error.
‫Let's test then for the truthiness of the course variable.
‫And if we did not manage to find the course in the database, we are going to be throwing a 404 not
‫found exception.
‫So let's go ahead and use the already existing exception from the Nestjs common package.
‫And let's add here an error message to the end user could not find course for URL and let's append here
‫the URL segment that we did not manage to associate to a given course.
‫Now, at this point in the program we are sure that we have here a course.
‫That we got from the database so we can go ahead and return it here as the output of this method.
‫Remember, we are returning here a primitive type, but the async await syntax is going to automatically
‫wrap this value in the promise.
‫So the output of this method is going to be a promise that Nestjs is going to use to populate the response
‫sent back to the client.
‫And with this in place, we have finished the implementation of our find course by URL endpoint.
‫Let's have a look at this in action.
‫We are going to switch to a larger window and we're going to click here on the View Course button.
‫And as we can see, we are now fetching here some data from the backend.
‫We can see here the correct title and thumbnail from the course, but we still have here some functionality
‫missing on this page.
‫We have not yet filled in this list of lessons, so that's why we have here a get request to the slash
‫API slash lessons endpoint, which does not exist yet.
‫So we are getting here a 404 not found in the next few lessons.
‫We are going to be implementing this endpoint which involves the use of a new entity, the lessons entity.
‫And we are going to be filling in this lessons table and adding some pagination functionality.