‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this lesson, we are going to add a new entity to our program.
‫We are going to configure the lessons entity.
‫We are going to be needing the lessons entity in order to build the view course screen.
‫We are going to be displaying a table that displays a list of lessons belonging to a given course,
‫and we are going to show how to add pagination logic to that table.
‫So we already have here in our program a lesson entity here in the shared folder at the top level of
‫our project, we have here the shared folder and we have here the file lesson containing the definition
‫of our lesson entity.
‫As we can see, the lesson has a description, a duration.
‫It is linked to a course and it has a sequential number.
‫So we have here an example of a one to many relation between two entities.
‫A course can have many lessons, and a lesson belongs only to one course.
‫Let's see, how can we model this relationship in MongoDB?
‫The first thing that we are going to need is to define a schema for this entity.
‫Here on the Schemas folder, we are going to be creating a new file called Lessons Dot Schema, Dot
‫TS.
‫And inside it we are going to define the schema for the lesson entity.
‫Let's start by importing here Mongoose and let's define here the lesson schema.
‫We are going to create here a new mongoose schema and let's pass it a configuration object.
‫Now I'm going to add here quickly the configuration for the description, the duration and the sequential
‫number, because it's very similar to what we have configured before for the courses entity.
‫Now here we are going to do step by step the configuration of the one to many relationship with the
‫courses entity.
‫We are going to say that each lesson has a new property which is a course.
‫Now this course is going to be a reference to another MongoDB collection.
‫Let's have a look at what this type of relationship looks like at the level of the database.
‫So switching here to our MongoDB console, we are going to open here the lessons collection.
‫And here we are going to see that each lesson has a course property.
‫Now the course property is a MongoDB object identifier that links this property to another document
‫in the courses collection.
‫So, for example, this identifier here is going to correspond to a course here in the courses collection.
‫And this in general is how we do a one to many relationship in MongoDB.
‫We are going to be using an object ID to link to a document in another collection.
‫Let's then see how can we define this relationship in mongoose?
‫So we have here a property called course.
‫Let's define the type.
‫The type is going to be a MongoDB object identifier.
‫So let's define it here using Mongoose, we are going to access here the schema type definitions and
‫here we are going to choose the object ID type.
‫Now we are going to say that this property course is a reference to another collection.
‫Let's specify here the name of the link entity, which will be a course.
‫And with this we have defined our new lesson schema.
‫Let's now plug it into Mongoose.
‫So here in the definition of our courses module, we are going to be adding here a new configuration
‫object.
‫Let's define here that the lesson entity is defined by this lesson schema that we have just created.
‫And with this in place, our program is now ready to query also the lessons collection and we will be
‫using that functionality to implement the search lessons endpoint.