‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new practice lesson, we are going to be implementing the search lessons, back end service.
‫So if you remember, the search lesson service is used here by the course page in order to load here
‫a list of lessons from the back end.
‫And we are going to be showing how to add pagination logic to this table.
‫Now we are trying to fetch the lessons from the back end via this rest call.
‫We have here a get request that has failed because the service is not yet implemented and we are hitting
‫here the service slash API slash lessons and we are passing here a series of parameters.
‫If you can see here in the URL we have here the course ID as one of the parameters.
‫We have the sort order which is ascending.
‫We have the page number which is zero, which is the first page of lessons that we want to load and
‫we have a page size of three.
‫So we want to implement a back end request using Nestjs that handles this type of request.
‫So let's see, how can we do that?
‫So we are going to need a second controller for the lessons entity, the same way that we had here,
‫a controller that was responsible only for the courses entity.
‫Let's then add here a new file in our controllers folder.
‫We are going to be creating here a file called Lessons Dot Controller, Dot TS.
‫Inside it, we are going to start writing our controller.
‫Let's start by defining here a class and let's go ahead and let's annotate this class with the controller
‫decorator from Nestjs.
‫Let's specify that this is going to handle the lessons entity.
‫Now we are going to be adding here a new method that is going to handle our Http get request and return
‫a list of lessons.
‫Let's make this an async method so that it's easy to use the async await syntax if we need it.
‫And let's call this method search lessons.
‫We are going to start by annotating this with the get decorator from Nestjs.
‫So this get method is going to be called if we try to hit an API endpoint, starting with slash API
‫just like any other controller in our application and hitting the slash API slash lessons endpoint.
‫This is the method that is going to be invoked in order to produce an Http response.
‫Let's add here the input parameters of this method.
‫We are going to be needing a course ID which will be a string and we are going to be needing a couple
‫of other parameters as we have seen in the request that was being made by the course screen.
‫We are also going to be specifying here the sort order which will be a string.
‫We are going to be specifying here the page number which we are going to make sure that at this point
‫in the program it's already a number and we are going to be specifying the page size as well.
‫Also a number.
‫Now let's see how we are going to grab these values from the Http request going back here to the Http
‫request that we are trying to handle in our back end, we can see that all these parameters are coming
‫here from the query part of the URL.
‫So after the question mark we have here these parameters that we need to retrieve as the input of our
‫function.
‫So in order to grab this type of Http, get parameters from the query part of the URL, we can use the
‫query decorator from Nestjs.
‫Let's then add it here.
‫Inside the query decorator, we need to specify the name of the parameter that we want to grab.
‫In this case it's the course ID.
‫We can then apply here a similar decorator to all the remaining parameters and we need only to specify
‫the name of the parameter that we want to read, which is identical to the variable name.
‫So the last one that we are going to be adding is going to be the page size.
‫Now certain parameters we need to transform further before using them here in the body of search lessons.
‫For example, the page number is going to come from the URL as a string, but we want to transform this
‫into a number.
‫So as we have seen, we can do that using the parse int pipe.
‫Let's then apply this pipe here in these two numeric parameters.
‫We would also like to define here a default value in case that some of the parameters are not filled
‫in by our client.
‫So for example, the sort order we would like to make it by default ascending.
‫So we have added here this default parameter.
‫And notice that because we have added here a default parameter, which is a string, this implicitly
‫assigns to sort order the string type so we can remove that and make our program a bit more readable.
‫Here on the page number parameter, we are going to do the same.
‫We are going to say that the default page is going to be page zero, the first page, and let's make
‫the default page size to have the small size of three.
‫And with this in place, we have set up the input parameters of our function.
‫So we are ready to implement our business logic.
‫Let's start by testing that the course ID has indeed.
‫Been defined.
‫So if there is no course ID, then we cannot provide any meaningful result to the client.
‫So let's throw here a bad request exception and we are going to add here the message course ID must
‫be defined.
‫Let's also add here some extra validation.
‫For example, for the sort order, we are going to make sure that the sort order is either the ask or
‫desk values.
‫So let's test for that here.
‫So if the sort order is different than the ask value standing for ascending and the same parameter,
‫the sort order is also different from the desk value for descending order, then we are going to throw
‫a new bad request exception saying that the sort order parameter must be one of these two values.
‫So with this we did here some business validation on our input parameters and we are now ready to implement
‫the database querying part of our application.
‫We are going to do that by using a new repository service that we are going to be building in the next
‫lesson.