‫Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
‫In this new lesson, we are going to finish the implementation of our Lessons controller.
‫We are going to query our MongoDB database.
‫We're going to be querying the lessons collection and we're going to be fetching a page of lessons and
‫sending it back to our client.
‫So for that, we are going to be needing to query the database with a new repository service specific
‫to the lessons entity.
‫Let's create here then in the Repositories folder, a new file that we are going to be calling lessons
‫dot repository, dot TS, and inside it we are going to be adding our repository.
‫Let's start by defining here a new class and let's go ahead and annotate it with the injectable decorator
‫from Nestjs.
‫Now this class at this moment is only going to have one method which is going to be called search.
‫And this search method is going to take several parameters.
‫So the first parameter is going to be the course ID and the other parameters are going to be the sort
‫order, the page number and the page size that I'm going to simply paste in here as they are the same
‫parameters as we have used here in our controller.
‫So all of these parameters we want to be able to pass to the repository so that we can query our MongoDB
‫database.
‫Now, in order to query the database, we are going to be needing the lessons model.
‫Let's go ahead and inject it here in our constructor.
‫Let's define here a new private property that we are going to call lessons model.
‫And let's make this a model of lesson.
‫Let's now add here the inject model annotation.
‫Otherwise we won't be able to inject the lessons model to the inject model decorator.
‫We are going to be passing here the name of the entity that we want to inject in this case, the lesson
‫entity.
‫Let's now go ahead and implement the body of the search method.
‫Let's start by adding here some logging so that we can see on the console log that this method has been
‫correctly called.
‫So here we are going to be using the lessons model to query the database, and for that we are going
‫to be calling here the find method.
‫And the find method is going to return us a promise so we can go ahead and return this as the output
‫of the search method.
‫Now to the find method, we are going to be needing to pass a series of search parameters.
‫In our case, we need to find the courses that belong to a given course ID, So let's use here the course
‫property and let's fill it in with the course ID parameter that we got here in our call to search.
‫Now all we have to do is to add the pagination logic to our query.
‫The find method takes three parameters, so the first contains the filter criteria that we want to apply
‫to the result set.
‫The second parameter defines what type of fields do we want to get from the response?
‫So let's say that we would like to do a query that only gets back a couple of fields from all the available
‫fields on the lesson entity.
‫Then in that case we could specify here using the second parameter exactly what fields do we want.
‫But in our case we want to get back the full lesson entity.
‫So let's fill this in with Null.
‫And now we only have to fill in the last parameter that we are passing to find and this is where we
‫are going to be specifying our pagination logic.
‫Let's start by specifying how many results do we want to get back.
‫We are going to be using here the limit property and we are going to say that we only want a certain
‫number of results in our result set.
‫Now we are going to specify the page that we want.
‫So for that we are going to be using the skip property which specifies how many items from the beginning
‫of our collection are we going to skip until we get to the beginning of our result data set?
‫So we are going to be taking here our page number and we are going to be multiplying it by our page
‫size.
‫So this will identify the beginning of our result, set.
‫Let's say that for example, we are at page zero, then Skip will have the value zero, meaning that
‫we want to start at the beginning of our data set.
‫If the page number would be one multiplied by the page, size of three would mean that we would skip
‫the first three results and start our data set with the fourth entry in all the lessons available on
‫the database.
‫Now, in order to complete our query, we are only missing here another property which is the sort property.
‫So this will tell us how do we want to sort our result set before starting to extract pages?
‫So in our particular case, we want to sort this by the sequential number field of the lesson entity
‫and we want to specify that the sort order corresponds to this parameter that we got here in the call
‫to search.
‫And with this we have finished the implementation of the search method so we can now use it to implement
‫our controller.
‫So here we want to inject the.
‫The lessons repository.
‫So let's go ahead and plug it into our Nestjs application.
‫We are going to first go here to our courses module and here in our providers.
‫We are going to be adding here the lessons repository.
‫And since we are here, let's also take the opportunity to add here the lessons controller.
‫So now we have configured our repository and our controller, so we are ready to finish the implementation
‫of our lessons controller.
‫We are going to start by injecting here the repository service.
‫Let's create here a new property that we are going to call, for example, lessons.
‫DB And let's make this a lessons repository.
‫With the repository we can now call the search method and we are going to be passing all the parameters
‫that we have validated here.
‫So this will be the course ID, the sort order, the page number and the page size.
‫So this call is going to return a promise so we can go ahead and return this promise directly here as
‫the result of the search lesson method.
‫And notice that because we are returning a promise here, we don't even have to make this function async
‫because this is already a promise.
‫And so because we are not using here, the async await syntax in the body of the search lesson method.
‫Then we don't need the async keyword.
‫Now before trying things out, let's quickly fix here a small problem.
‫So as you can see, we have used here the page number parameter two times accidentally.
‫Let's fix this.
‫So this last parameter should be the page size.
‫And with this, we are now ready to try out this new version of our controller.
‫Let's then select here the View Course page by clicking on the View button.
‫And as we can see, we have printed here that the current page is indeed page zero.
‫And we have here the first three results of our lessons dataset.
‫Notice that the results are indeed for the Nestjs in practice course, and if we click here on the next
‫page button, we are going to see that we have here the next page of results.
‫And if we click here back we can paginate back to the previous page.
‫So as you can see, our back end service is working correctly as expected.
‫And with this we have implemented the View course page in our application.
‫So as you can see, this was a nice little exercise to put in practice.
‫Again, all the concepts that we have learned on previous lessons and we even saw here some new functionality
‫which was the query decorator.
‫And we have also learned how to create one to many relationships in MongoDB.
‫Let's now move on to more advanced nestjs concepts.
‫In the next few lessons we are going to be talking about Nestjs authentication and authorization.
‫We are going to protect these endpoints from a security standpoint.
‫We are going to make sure that only administrators can edit the data, but every logged in user can
‫see the data.
‫We are also going to learn how to authenticate each request by linking a certain request to a certain
‫user.
‫Our solution is going to be based around Json web tokens.
‫This is coming right up in the next section of the course.