Hey everyone
and welcome to the
official nastiest courses.
In this extension
will be going through
many advanced architectural
concepts and patterns
and sgs from top to bottom.
Which should help you
get up to speed creating
enterprise great applications
with the help of nestorius
in no time.
Let's introduce the
instructors for this course.
My name Bismarck
part of the nastiest core team and together
with Camille the creator of nastiest
we're excited to have
you learning nest with us.
To get the most
out of this course
try to code alongside us and remember
that you can pause the videos at any time.
Please note that this
extension is a continuation
knowledge wise of the nes
fundamentals course
and the advanced
concepts course.
Before you start watching this course we
recommend taking a step back and checking
the official
fundamentals course.
Is you're already not
comfortable witness yes that is.
And this extension
will assume that you're familiar with
everything we've covered in that fundamentals
course an advanced
concepts course
so
let's go ahead and get started.