Before we kicked things off.
Let's start by generating an empty nest
Jess application just so we have something
that we can work with
for the following lessons.
Etc to our terminals
and enter in the
nest new command
calling our a project advanced
architecture or whatever you wish.
Once everything
finishes installing.
Let's cd or change directory
into our newly created
application by entering cd
advanced dash architecture.
With our initial start or and place let's
generate a single resource with nest g
resource that we will
call alarms just we have
something to operate
on throughout the course.
Will use the autogen
operated module
service and controller
and future lessons.
Great.
While that in place we
can now start our application
in development mode with
n p m run start Colin deaf.
And as always
our application will now be
available on port three thousand.
And so there we have it
now with our basic app set up we're
ready to continue moving forward.