A layered architecture also
known as and tear architecture
is a software design
pattern used to organize
applications into
distinct layers or tears.
Each layer
has a specific role
in communication between
layers as well defined
and hierarchical.
This design approach
promotes modularity
scale ability maintainability
and separation of
concerns and software.
A typical entier architecture
consists of the following layers.
A presentation layer
or user interface layer.
This topmost layer interacts with users
presenting data in a user friendly format.
It handles use or input displays information
and forwards request to lower layers
examples include web browsers
mobile apps and desktop interfaces.
Next up is the
application layer.
Or business logic layer.
And application layer
contains the core business logic.
A processes requests from
the presentation layer performs
business rules calcul nations
and managers data flow.
Note that it does not handle
data storage or retrieval.
Next up we have the domain layer
or data model layer.
The domain layer represents decor entities
in business objects of the application.
And encapsulates business logic
independently of data storage technology
defining the fundamental
rules of the applications domain.
And lastly we have the data
access layer or persistence Claire.
The data access layer handles
data storage and retrieval operations.
It interacts with databases file systems or
external services to save and fetch data.
Shielding the rest of the
application from data storage details.
Note that entire architecture
can also be extended with
additional layers such as
caching or messaging layers.
Based on specific
application needs.
Some benefits of and
entier architecture include.
Maintainability.
The separation of concerns in different
layers simplifies application maintenance and
updates without
affecting other parts.
Reuse ability.
The modular nature
allows component reuse
across multiple projects
and lastly security.
Clearly defined layer communication enhances
security by restricting direct access to
sensitive data
and functionality.
In ness jazz the three laird architecture
is the default architecture that is
generated when you generate
a new new nestorius resource.
We also call this the
traditional architecture.
As it is the most
common architecture used
in ness Jess applications.
It has also the architecture that we
have been using in previous lessons
and course extensions.
As that's the essentially what ness
js documentation and examples use.
The three layers are
the country rollers layer
which handles incoming requests
and returns responses to the client.
The services layer
which consists of the
business logic of the application
and the data access or persistence layer
which handles data storage and retrieval.
If we switch over to r i d e
we can see that our application is
already structured and this exact way.
We have a controller and a
service but we don't have a
data access layer since the
nest g resource schematic
doesn't generate one for us.
We would usually fill this gap with a
type or and module or a prison module
or really any other module that
handles data storage and retrieval for us.
The three tier architectural
works really well
for medium to large scale
applications that require
a clear separation of concerns
modularity
and scale ability.
Is a good choice when the
focuses on organizing the
application into layers
with defined responsibilities.
When you are team prioritizes a more
decoupled and domain centric design.
You may want to consider a
different architecture such as the onion.
Or hexagonal
architectural patterns.
These architectures are well
suited for complex domain model and
and domain driven design.
Allowing the application to evolve
independently of external factors.
Don't worry
we'll be diving into both of these
architectures in the following lessons.