Hexagonal architecture
also known as ports
in adapters architecture
is a software design
pattern that aims to create
a highly decoupled
and testable application
by emphasizing the
separation of concerns
between the core business logic
and external concerns
such as databases
user interfaces and frameworks.
The key concert
in hexagonal architecture
is the use of ports
and adapters.
Hence the ports
in adapters name.
Ports are interfaces that represent
the entry points into the core application.
They defined the contract for interactions
with the external world and represent the
applications use
cases and boundaries.
The core domain
exposes these ports
allowing external concerns
to interact the application
in a standardized way.
Adapters implement the interfaces
or ports defined by the core domain.
They serve as the bridge between the
core application and the external concerns.
Adapters are responsible for translating
the language of the core domain into
something that external
systems can understand
such as data persistence
mechanisms a p eyes
or user interfaces.
This architecture revolves around
the idea of dependency inversion
which means that high-level
modules such as the core module
should not depend on low level
modules such as those external concerns.
Instead both should depend
on abstractions known as ports.
This inversion of dependencies enables
the court to remain independent an isolated
from externa systems.
Making it easier
to test maintain
and adapt the application.
Some benefits of hexagonal
architecture are decoupling.
This architecture
promotes loose coupling
between the core domain
and external concerns.
Allowing changes to occur in
one area without affecting others.
Test ability.
By defining clear interfaces
reports for interactions
it becomes easier to test
the core domain in isolation
without relying on
external systems.
Flexibility.
Hexagonal architecture
allows for the replacement
or modification of external
concerns or adapters.
Without impacting
the core domain.
Making it more adaptable
to different technologies tax.
Isolation of core domain.
The quarter domain is the
focal point of the application
enabling developers to
focus on expressing business
logic without being
influenced by external factors.
And lastly
domain centric design.
This architectural pattern
encourages a strong focus on the
core domain and the business from else.
Leading to a more expressive
and maintainable domain model.
If we look at the
following diagram.
We can see that the
traditional three tier
architecture with controller
services or business logic
and data access layers
of all the arrows
pointing to the right.
Indicating that the flow
of control is from the left
to the right.
But what if we inverted
dependency between
the business logic and
the data access layer.
The business logic layer will still interact
with the data access layer but it will
do so through an
interface or port.
This is the core idea behind
hexagonal architecture.
The business logic layer is
isolated from the data access layer
and vice versa.
Business logic laird
defines the interface or port.
In the data access layer
implements it as it is our adapter.
So to summarize
hexagonal architecture focuses
on a strong separation of concerns.
Dependency inversion
and clear interfaces known
as ports for interactions.
It promotes a
domain centric does zine and provides
better test ability and flexibility.
On the other hand.
Three-tier architecture
relies on horizontal Larry
but might not achieve the same
level of isolation and test ability
as hexagonal architecture.
The choice between the
two depends on the specific
requirements and
complexity of your application.
For smaller applications three two your
architecture might be entirely sufficient.
While hexagonal architecture
is typically more suitable for
complex applications that
require an even more decoupled
and domain centric design.