In this lesson
will be looking at how
we can take advantage of
hexagonal architecture in
our nest years applications.
So
what sort of by heading
over to our ID he
and take a look at the
code we have at the moment.
Inside of our alarms directory we
can see that we have a controller
a service and a module class.
As we know the controller
is responsible for handling
incoming requests and returning
responses back to the client.
The services in our code base contained
the business logic of our application
and the modules represent
the bounded context
defining the dependencies and the
components that belong to each module
so nothing new here safari.
All right so let's
kick things off.
By creating for new folders
inside of the alarms directory.
Named application.
Domain main.
Infrastructure
and presenters
and let's stop your
for a second to explain
each of these folders
and what they represent.
The application folder here will
contained the application services
besides handlers and other
application specific components
which all represent
the application layer.
It will communicate with the data access
components message brokers and other
external systems
through interfaces alt ports.
The domain folder will contain
the domain models value objects
domain events in
other domain specific
components which all
represent the domain layer.
The infrastructure folder
will contain the data access
components message brokers
and other external systems which
represent the infrastructure layer.
It will implement the
interfaces aka a ports
defined by the
application layer.
And the lastly the
presenters folder
will contain the controllers gateways and
other user facing components or a p eyes.
Sometimes
the presenters folder is also
called the user interface folder.
Sometimes just interface
all stick with presenters.
Since it seem to be a
bit more self explanatory.
Note that this is just one way
of structuring your application.
You could also structured differently
depending on your needs and preferences.
A generally boils down to how
granular you want everything to be
within your liars.
Okay so back to
our task at hand.
Less move the alarm service and alarms
module files to the application folder.
Next up.
Let's create a new
directory called http
inside of the presenters folder
and let's move the
alarms controller.
As well as the detail
folder inside of it.
This http dirac lottery.
While now represent
the http layer
of our bounded
context called alarms.
All of the import statements should
automatically be updated by our i do eat but if
they're not make sure
to update them manual.
Also before we proceed.
Let's remove the entities folder
as will be creating a new one soon.
Now.
Inside of the domain folder.
Will create a new file called alarmed
at t s with the following content.
This class will represent
our domain model.
Will be adding more logic here in the
future but for now let's keep it simple.
So as we can see the alarm
severity doesn't exist yet.
So let's go ahead and create a
new file called alarm severity that ts.
Inside of the domain
slash value dash objects folder.
With the following content.
Great.
But
what does value objects
been here in the first place.
Well
a value objects definition
originates from domain driven design
or ddd.
A value object.
Is an immutable object that represents
a descriptive aspect of the domain
with no conceptual identity.
To value objects are equal
when they are the same value
not necessarily
being the same object.
Value objects should be
immutable in side effect fruit.
Now at this and place.
We can add the missing import
statement to the alarm t s file.
Also
inside of the factors
directory let's create an
alarm factory file with
the following content.
Perfect.
Now at this in place
it's navigate to the
alarms controller
and remove all
methods except for create
and find all.
Just to keep things simple.
As will only be using these two
methods in the following lessons.
Similarly let's navigate
to the alarms service
and remove all the unused
methods there's well.
Let's stop here for a moment
to discuss a few thanks.
So since our data
transfer objects details
are now located inside
the presenters folder
and belong to the
presentation layer.
We can't really reference
them and let's say
the application layer.
We could in theory
move them here
to the application folder.
However they contain
validation decorators
and they represent the shape of
the data that is sent over the network.
Which is a shape
specific to the http a p i.
So.
As purists
we should keep them
and the presenters folder.
Otherwise other transport
layers for example grpc.
Would have to
referenced them as well.
Which will be even
more confusing.
So what can we do here.
Well we can either use the
any type for the time being.
Or create yet another
class called for example
payload or command
and use that here instead.
Since in this course.
Are going to eventually introduced
command and query classes later.
Let's go ahead and create
a new directory called
commands and side
of the application layer.
And inside of this folder.
Let's create a new file
called create alarm command.
With the following content.
Let's save our changes
and use this type instead of the
create alarm detail in the alarm service.
Next let's make
sure to update the
alarms controller to
construct the create alarm
command object and
pass it to the create method
instead of the
create alarm d to you.
Also let's update the
create alarm d t o to
contain two properties
required to create an alarm.
Name.
In severity
both which are strings.
And last but not least
it's open up the alarms module and registered
the new alarm factory as a provider.
As will be using it
in future lessons.
Let's save our changes and if we head over
to the terminal and run the application
we should see that
everything's working as expected.
So far so good.
As we can see our application is now structured
differently than before which was the
traditional set up we see
industrious applications.
Were slowly heading towards
the hexagonal architecture
or not quite there yet.
We still need to define
the interfaces are ports
and implement them via adapters.
Don't worry of this all
doesn't make much sense yet
it'll become clear clear
and the following lessons
as we build everything out.
Piece by piece.