In this lesson
will continue working on our application
but what a hexagonal architecture and mind
and create the
interfaces known as ports
defined by the application layer as well
as the adapters that will implement the.
Ports defined the contract for
interactions with the external world.
While adapters implement
these contracts and sir
serve as a bridge between
the application layer
and the external systems.
Before we proceed.
What's the first installed the
dependencies that will need in this lesson.
For demonstration purposes
are going to use the type or m library
to implement one of the repositories
in the p g library
to connect to a.
Crests sql database.
Back to our task at hand.
Let's create a new folder and the
application directory called ports.
And side of it.
Let's create a new file called alarm
repository with the fallen content.
This here is our first port.
Which defines the contract
for the alarm repository.
It defines to methods.
Find all in say.
The find all method
will return a list of all alarms
while the same method
will save a new alarmed
the database in return
of that saved alarm.
It's worth noting
that both the class and
the methods are abstract.
Meaning that they don't
have an implementation.
This implementation will
actually be provided by
the adapters which will
get to and just a moment.
Note that instead of using abstract
classes we could use interfaces here
but the reason we chose
to use abstract classes.
Is that they serve as
injection tokens and ness jazz.
While interfaces.
Are purely typescript constructs and are
wiped out during the transportation process.
Essentially.
This means that they would
not be available at runtime.
Making classes a much
better choice for us to use.
Now
onto the adapters.
Inside the
infrastructure folder.
Let's create a directory
named persistence.
This folder.
Will contain the adapters that will lead
us interact with different data sources.
In our case
will be using a
postgraduate sql database
and interacting with
it via type of ram.
As well as an in-memory database
for demonstration purposes.
Note that type r m or post crests are not
required by any means you're welcome to use
any or 'em or
database of your choice
to achieve hexagonal architecture
in your destiny as applications.
Oh
let's create to new folders
respectively in memory for
the in-memory database adapter
and or m
for the type of r m
database adapter.
Let's start with the
type r m adapter.
Inside the are and folder
let's create a new file called alarm
entity under the entities directory
with the following content.
This class will represent
our database table it will be
used by type or m to map the
data to and from the database.
Next.
Let's create a new file
while the alarm repository
under the repositories
directory with the
following content.
Here
were simply delegating the calls
to the native type r m repository
which is injected
into the constructor.
However
we can see that some of
the lines are highlighted read.
This is because our type r m
repository it returns the entity.
Our persistence model
while our application
layer expects the domain
the model which is alarm
instead of alarm entity.
So we need to convert the entity
with the domain model
and the opposite.
Let's go ahead and do that now.
To achieve this.
Let's create a new map or file called alarm
app or she s under the mappers directory
and give it the
following content.
This alarm mapper class
exposes to static methods
to domain
and to persistence.
The to domain method converts
the entity to the domain model.
While the to persistence method
converts the domain model to the entity.
Nothing too fancy here
but most importantly.
We need to ensure
that the severe property.
Which is represented as the
value object in our domain model
is converted to a regular string
and the other way around
when converting from an entity
to the domain model.
Back to our repository.
Let's use our new alarm mapper
to perform these conversions.
Great.
Last but not least.
We need to create the new or and
persistence module file under the.
M directory with
the following content.
Using the accustomed providers
syntax here were telling nest
as to use the or ram
alarm repository class
whenever the alarm
repository token is requested.
Were also exporting the
alarm repository token.
Let it can be used by
other models as well
this is where we bind the port
to an adapter.
Excellent.
Now
let's create the in
memory adapter.
Is going to be a lot of repetitive work
here so let's go ahead and copy everything
over from the or ram directory
to the in memory director
but of course
will need to make a few changes.
Let's start by first opening
up the alarm entity file
and remove the type r m
annotations as we won't need
any of that in the context
of an in-memory adapt.
The alarm mapper
remains the same so technically we
could move it to the shared directory.
But since for more sophisticated
adapters a might be different
will keep it here instead.
Next up onto the repository.
Let's open up the alarm repository file
and remove the inject repository dependency
what's also renamed this class
to in memory alarm repository.
Inside the body of this class.
Let's create a new map that will
act as our in-memory database.
With this new map and place.
Let's update the find
all and saved methods.
Last but not least.
Let's rename the or and persistence
module to in memory persistence module.
Also
let's make sure to be named the module
to in memory alarm persistence module.
In remove the type r m import.
Antarctic.
Now we have to adapters
that implement this same port.
Now onto the fun part.
Let's see how we can
use them in or application.
First and
of the root of the
infrastructure directory.
Let's create a new file
called alarms
infrastructure module
with the following content.
This module is responsible
for exporting the correct
persistence module based
on the driver that we pass in.
Both the in-memory
alarm persistence module
and or
export the alarm repository token.
We can easily swap
one for the other.
With that in place what's
navigate to the alarms module
and declare a new static method.
Called with infrastructure.
Here we're using the
modules composition pattern
will allow the
consumers of our modul
who pass in the infrastructure
module that they want to use.
This is a very powerful pattern
that allows us to decouple the
infrastructure from the application layer.
Next up.
Let's open up our alarms service
and inject the alarm positively provider.
Let's also inject
the alarm factory.
And great with both
dependencies and place.
Let's update our find
all and create methods.
The create method now uses the alarm
factory to create a new alarm domain model
and then passes it to the
alarm repository to be saved.
Now onto the find all method.
The find all method
here simply returns the
result of the alarm
repositories find all method.
Excellent.
There's just a few more
quick things we need to do
before we can test everything
out on our application.
Or stop in the source directory.
Let's create a new
folder called common.
And inside of this directory
let's create a new file
called application boots
rep options dot interface
with the following content.
This interface will
represent the options
that we can use to
configure our application.
Next let's generate a
new module called core
using the nes jsc ally.
Let's open up this newly
generated module and
let's define a new for
route static method.
Essentially here
depending on the
driver that we pass in.
We're either going to import the type
r ram module or import nothing at all.
Next.
Let's open up the
app module t s file and declare
a new static method there as well.
And let's call it register.
This register method accepts the
application bootstrap options object
and passes it to the core
module for route method.
As you can see
it also passes the driver to the alarms
infrastructure module use method.
Which returns the correct
infrastructure module
based on the selected driver.
It's also not forget to remove
the previously important
alarms module that lacks
this infrastructure module.
Finally.
Let's update the main ts file to use the
register method and voila were all set.
For now
let's use the in-memory driver
i will switch to the typo or
m driver in just a moment.
So now.
Let's head over to our terminals
and start up the application.
As we can see
our application is up
and running slots test
everything out using a
few simple curl commands.
Excellent both the create and find
all methods are working as expected.
So but switch over to the
type r m driver now to test data.
In order to do that first we're going to
have to create a few things so let's start
by creating a docker
compose yaml file in the root
of our project with the
for following content.
As a note here
make sure that the
password matches the one that
we used in the for route
method of the core module.
Now back to our terminals.
Let's run
docker dash compose up
dash d to start up that database.
Once our database
is up and running.
Let's update the main t s file to use the
type or ram driver instead of in memory.
Let's save our changes again
and head over to the terminal
and observed those logs.
As we can see
the type of
ram module has been
successfully initialized meaning
that our application is now
using the type r m driver
and a real database.
As test it out using those
same curl commands.
And it works
fantastic.
So just to recap everything.
We've created a simple application
that allows us to create an fetch alarms.
But are simple application
is much more than that.
We've also decoupled
the infrastructure from the
application layer using the
modules composition powder.
With that simple path pattern.
We can now simply switch between different
infrastructure implementations without
haven't changed the
application layer itself.
In our case.
We simply switch between
an in-memory database
and a postgres
database via type around
but hopefully you can see this
newly gained power you have
of now changing between
entirely different infrastructures.
Database cases.
If you needed to have
such a powerful flexibility
in your future
nest applications.