Onion architecture and hexagonal architecture
are both architectural patterns for
designing software applications
with a focus on decoupling
maintainability
and putting the business logic
at the center of the application.
Both patterns are
technically almost identical
even though they have
different names and are presented
by different visual
representations the or diagrams.
If we look at an onion
architectural diagram.
We can see the different
layers of an application
and as you might have
guessed the name of the
architecture actually originates
from this diagram itself.
The innermost layer
is the domain layer
which contains the domain
model and the domain logic.
This layer is surrounded
by the application layer
which contains the
application logic.
The flow of dependencies
follows an inward direction.
With the use of the
dependency inversion principal.
Were outer layers
depend on inner layers
but the inner layers remain
unaware of those outer layers.
That being said this
diagram has led to a lot of
confusion and the software
engineering community
because the user interface components
as well as the data access components
are positioned
in the same layer.
This made many engineers
draw incorrect conclusions.
That the onion architecture.
Is an entirely secure
because you are components
can direct lately interact
with the data source
but that's simply not true.
The diagram here is just a visual
representation of the architecture
and it doesn't mean that the
components that are on the same level.
Or visually located in
the same onion layer.
Are actually able to
interact with each other.
Layers are not meant
to group components but
rather emphasized the
direction of dependencies.
If we look at a hexagonal
architecture diagram an
start drawing concentric
circles around components.
Will quickly notice that the
diagram actually reminds
us of the onion architectural
diagram doesn't it.
This means that conceptually
with architectures are
essentially the same.
Although they may be applied
slightly differently and practice.
Furthermore.
The naming conventions and some
design decisions we made in this course
might vary from what you may have noticed
another other projects and that's okay.
Important thing is that you
understand the core concepts
and principles behind
the architecture.
Now you're able to
take advantage of them
in your future
necessary as projects.