Domain driven design
also known as ddd.
As a software
development technique that
concentrates on the domain
model and domain larger.
As Eric Evans
puts it in his book.
Domain driven design tackling
complexity in the heart of software.
The structure in language of our code
should match that of the business domain.
This concept is called
the ubiquitous language.
Fundamentally.
Ddd is about creating a
language that connects the
implementation to the business
experts in there knowledge
so essentially words and
phrases from the domain.
Are directly used in the codex.
Therefore
we could use this language to
construct a rich model for our domain
describing all of the objects and interactions
between them using a language that is
understood by both
the business experts
and the developers.
For this week follow the strategic design
process that may include several tools and
techniques such as
domain storytelling.
Events storming
and context mapping.
Our goal with this process is to identify
the core domain and the subdomains.
Into to find the bounded contexts
and the context maps in her system.
To express the domain
ma model in our code
we typically fall of the tactical
design process that uses
a set of building blocks to
construct the domain model.
These are entities
value objects.
Aggregates
repositories services.
Factories
and domain events.
Let's take a look at each of
these building blocks in more detail.
Entities are objects that have a
unique identifier and a life cycle.
They are mutable and
can be modified over time.
Entities have a conceptual
identity meaning that even if
their attributes change
they are still the same entity.
Also.
Entities are not equal to each other
even if they have the same attributes.
For example
an alarm with the same name and
severity is still not the same alarm
it's a different alarm entity
with the same attributes.
Value objects on the
other hand are immutable
and don't have a
unique identifier.
They are equal to each other if
they have the same attributes.
In our system
we used value objects to
represent the severity of an alarm.
Aggregates are a cluster of objects
that are treated as a single unit.
They ensure that all
the objects within the
aggregate are always in
a valid inconsistent state.
In aggregate represents a
transactional consistency boundary
meaning that changes to the
objects within the aggregate
should be made in
a single transaction.
In other words any modifications to the
state of one entity within the aggregate
should be done within the
context of the aggregate itself.
Repositories are used to
persist and retrieve aggregates
they provide an abstraction
over the data access layer
and allow us to work with
aggregates without having to
worry about the underlying
data access implementation.
We actually already used repositories in or
application to persist and retrieve alarms.
Services
are used to to encapsulate
domain logic that doesn't
belong to any particular
entity or value object.
Or example
we can have a service that is responsible
for sending notifications to the users
when a new alarm has created.
We must be careful when using
services because the heavy use of services
can be a sign of an
anemic domain model.
And anemic domain model
is an anti pattern where the domain
model doesn't contain any domain logic
and is essentially just a
bunch of getters and setters.
Factories
are used to encapsulate the
creation of complex objects.
They are particularly
useful in scenarios where
the creation of objects
involves complex validation
initialisation
or the coordination
of multiple steps.
Factories help us to keep
the domain model clean
and focused on business logic while offloading
the responsibility of object creation
to dedicated factory classes.
And lastly we have events
which are used to communicate and capture
domain specific information about actions
or domain model changes
that have happened in the past.
Of events play a crucial role in enabling
loose coupling scale ability and eventual
consistency and
distributed systems.
We distinguish
two types of events.
Domain events and
integration events.
Will talk more about
events in future lessons.
So we've covered quite a
lot of broad concepts here
but to recap.
Ddd is not a technology
or a methodology.
It's essentially a set of
principles and patterns
that can be applied
to any software project.
It's also not a silver bullet.
It's not going to solve
all of our problems
but it can help us build
better software and
tackle the complexity
of solve our projects.
As we mentioned above
have we actually already
applied some of these
concepts and previous lessons
and will continue to implement
and learn more about all of them
as we build our applications
throughout the
rest of this course.