Commands query
responsibility segregation.
Or shorthand secure us.
Is a software architectural pattern that
separates the concerns of reading data
queries
and writing data
commands into separate models.
The core idea behind
secure us as to have
different models and
approaches for handling read.
And write operations in a system
rather than combining
them into a single model.
In traditional architectures
and crud systems.
The same model is often used to
handle both read and write operations.
However
as applications
grow and complexity.
Requirements for reading and writing
data can diverge signify currently.
This can lead to issues related to
performance scalability and maintain ability.
With seek your s the applications data
model is divided into two separate parts.
The command model which handles
write operations aka data modification.
This model enforces business
rules and validation logic
to ensure that data changes
are correct inconsistent.
And the second
being the query model.
Which handles read
operations a gay data retrieval.
The query model is
optimized for reading data
and often involves d
normalized data structures or
specialized views that cater
to specific read use cases.
This separation allows
for efficient querying in
improves the overall
performance of the read operations.
The secure as approach
offers several benefits such as.
Performance.
It allows us to optimize the read
and write operations independently
for example.
We can use different data stores
for the read and write models.
This allows us to choose
the right tool for the job
and optimize the data stores
for their specific use cases.
Scale ability.
Secure us lets us scaled the read and write
operations independently for example a
nice use case is a
flight booking system.
Where the read operations
are much much more frequent
than the right operations.
And lastly.
Maintainability.
Secure us allows us to evolve the read
and write my models independently as well.
However
like anything else in
the engineering world
seek you are s also comes
with some drawbacks such as.
Complexity.
Secure as certainly adds an additional
complexity to a system making it harder to
understand and not suited
for simple applications.
And also
eventual consistency.
The read and write models are
typically eventually consistent.
Meaning that the changes
made to the right model
are usually not immediately
reflected in the read model.
While this isn't a
drawback for say.
It's something that we he'd be
aware of when using secure us.
Seek you r s is also used in
combination with event sourcing
and event driven architectures.
Both of which will dive
deeper into in future lessons.
In the next lesson
will take a look at
how we can implement
you
us in our very an application.
Let's get started.