In this lesson.
Will take a look at how we can implement
command query responsibility segregation in
our application with
the use of the nest
as secure as package.
First we need to install
the required library.
Once the packages installed
let's navigate to the app module file
and import secure s
module that for route.
From the necessary as secure
as package into our imports array.
With this module registered
we can now start implementing the command
inquiry handlers in our application.
Let's start with the
command handlers.
Inside the existing
commands directory.
Will create a new file called create
alarm command handler dot t s
next to the existing create
alarm command cs file.
This file will contain the command
handler for this correspondent commands.
Let's break down this class so
everything makes more sense.
First
we defined the create
alarm command handler class
in implement the i
command handler interface.
The class
needs to be decorated with
the command handler decorator
with the corresponding command
class past and as an argument.
This decorator
cells and nest to register this class as a
command handler for the specified commands.
The i command handler interface requires
us to implement the execute method.
This method
will be called when the
command is dispatched.
The original command object will be
passed in as an argument to this method.
Inside the execute method.
We can perform any business logic
that is required to handle the command.
So falling what we've done
already in the alarms service.
Let's create a new alarm model
and save it to the database.
To achieve this will
need to dependencies.
Alarm repository
and alarm factory.
With these
dependencies injected.
We cannot update our
execute method as follows.
Perfect.
Now that we have the
command handler implemented
let's register it in the
alarms module file.
Next up.
Let's inject the command
bus into the alarm service
and use it to dispatch they
create alarm commands
when the create
method is called.
We can also remove the
alarm factory dependency
here as we no longer
use it in this class.
Note that we could rename
this class to use the facade
suffix instead of service
to better reflect its purpose.
But for the sake of
simplicity will keep it as is.
With this change in place
let's try to create a
a new alarm with curl
and see if it works.
As we can see the alarm
was successfully created and
we could see the log
message in the consul great.
Now that we have the
command handler implemented.
Let's take a look at how we
can implement be query handler.
First up will need to
create a new directory called
queries and side of the
source slash alarms directory.
Inside this directory.
Let's create a new file called
get alarms dot query dot t s
that will contain
the query class.
We're going to keep this
query simple in this course
but in real world application
we would typically pass
some parameters to this query
to filter the results.
For example
we could pass in the
limit or offset parameters
to implement pagination.
Similarly
we could pass in the sort parameter
to specify the saw sorting order etc.
Just know that you have these abilities
if you need them in your applications.
With this and place
let's create a new file
of get alarms query handler
that will contain
the query handler.
A query handler is very
similar to the command handler.
It needs to be decorated with the
query handler decorator in implemented
with the i query
handler interface.
The execute method here
will be called when the query
is dispatched and like previously
the original query object will be passed
and as an argument to this method.
Inside the execute method.
We can perform any business logic
that is required to handle the query.
In our case I'll start by
injecting the alarm repository
using the standard
constructor injection.
With this dependency injected we can
now update our execute method as follows.
Great.
Now
let's head of her to the
alarms module t s file an
register the query handler
in the providers a wreck.
Next let's navigate to the alarm service
file and eject the query bus provider here.
Using this provider
we can now dispatch
the get alarms query query
in the find all method.
And believe it or not that's it.
Let's save our changes.
Head over to the terminal
and let's test everything out.
As we can see the query
handler was successfully executed
and we could see the alarm
lessen the response great
it works.
So to summarize in this
lesson we've learned how we
can implement command
query responsibility segregation.
Aka secure s in or application
with the use of the nes
js secure or as package.
We're still just scratching
the surface as we
don't have any event
handlers implemented yet.
Nor separate read
and write models
will learn more
about all of that
in the upcoming lessons.