Event driven
architecture or edi a.
Is a software architecture
powder that revolves around
events as the main driving
force for communication
between different
components of a system.
It promotes the
production detection
consumption of and
reactions to events.
And event.
Can be defined as a signal
different change in state.
Such as user actions data updates
messages from external services
or errors.
For example things such as
a user creating a new account.
A new order being placed
or a new alarm being created
etc.
Event driven architecture typically
consists of three main components.
Event producers.
Event consumers
and an event bus
a k a event burger.
Event producers
are responsible for publishing
events to the event bus.
They act as the
source of events.
Event consumers subscribed
to events from the event bus.
They act as the sink of events.
The event bus itself is a
communication channel
that connects event
producers and event consumers.
And event bus acts
as a message broker
that receives events from producers
and distributes them to consumers.
It can be a message queue.
A centralized event service
or a message broker itself.
A vendor of and architecture
has several advantages
such as.
Loose coupling
between components since consumers
don't need to know about the producers
and vice versa.
Scale ability
since we can easily add more
consumers to increase the throughput
and processing capabilities.
And a synchronous processing.
Since consumers can
process events a synchronously
without blocking
the entire system.
However
as with everything in life
and software engineering.
A venture of and architecture
also has some drawbacks such as.
Overall complexity
since maintaining a sophisticated event
driven system can be quite challenging.
Data consistency complexity.
Since events are
processed a synchronously.
This usually means we're
dealing with eventual consistency.
And transactional integrity.
Since it can be quite difficult
to implement transactions
at span across
multiple services.
Overall
a vendor of and architecture is a very
powerful approach to building distributed
scalable
and flexible system second efficiently
handle complex business logic
in real time processing.
On the other hand
it also comes with some challenges
that need to be carefully considered
before deciding to use it
with any particular project.
So make sure to weigh
the pros and cons against
any system you're
considering adding it to.
As you should
with any architectural approach.