In this lesson.
Let's start by talking about
what we will be building
before we dive and everything.
Will start off by creating
our first event which
will represent the
creation of a new alarm.
Then
we'll create an event handler
that will subscribe to that event
it will be used to perform
additional processing.
To keep things simple
are going to to implement both the read
and right sides of the system in the same
application so we won't
need a message broker
to communicate
between different services.
Don't worry
that is something that will
cover in an upcoming less.
Okay
let's get started.
First we'll need to
create a new directory
called events inside
of the domain directory.
Inside of this directory.
Let's create a new file named
alarm created dot event that he s
that will contain
the event class.
As we can see
the event class
here is quite simple.
It contains a single property called alarm
that represents the alarm that was created.
This property is marked as read only
to prevent any accidental modifications.
Instead of passing the
alarm object directly.
Who could also pass the alarm ID
and then fetch the alarm from the
database inside of the event handler.
However.
As we want to eventually introduced
the event sourcing pattern this course.
Will need our events
to be fully self contained.
This means that they should contain all
the information that is required to reflect
the state change that
occurred in the system.
We distinguish
two types of events.
Domain events
and integration of its.
Domain events are events that
are relevant to the domain model.
They represent the state changes
that occur within the domain
and our case the alarm
created event is a domain events.
Integration events are usually
a lot thinner than domain
events and they are used for
cross service communication.
Okay so back to our task at hand
to process this event
will need to create a new file called
alarm created dot event dash handler dot ts
that will contain the
event handler class.
But where should
we put this file though.
Does it belong to the application
layer or the domain layer.
Well it depends.
Handling the domain events is
generally an application concern.
The domain meyer should
only focus on the domain logic.
Meaning.
Things that a domain
expert would understand.
Not application
infrastructure like handlers and
side effect persistence
actions using repositories.
For instance when
the alarm is created
we might want to publish a
domain event to propagate
that info to other
aggregates or even raise
application actions
like email notifications.
At the same time
some domain event handlers could be
considered as part of the domain model.
Especially if they simply
described the domain specific policy
on how to react to
a particular event.
However
such event handlers couldn't
interact with components
from upper layers such
as repositories services etc.
With all that being said in our case will
put the event handler in the application
layer and that's what you will usually
end up doing in your projects as well.
Just try to always keep in mind
what layer the files you're
working on should be placed him.
So first.
Let's create a new
directory called event
handlers and side of
the application directory.
Inside this directory
let's create a new file called
alarm created event handler.
With the following content.
The event handler is very similar
to the command inquiry handlers
it needs to be decorated with
the events handler decorator
and implements the i
event handler interface.
The reason why the event
handler annotation is a plural.
Is that we can use it to subscribe
to multiple events at once.
The handle method here will be
called when the event is dispatched
and the original of an
object will be passed
and is an argument to
this method as always.
Great.
All right so with this in place.
Let's head over to our
alarms module file and
register the event handler
in our providers of wreck.
Last but not least.
Wanting to dispatch the event
when the alarmists created.
To do that one needs to head over to the
create alarm command handler file an import
the event bus from the nes jazz
slash seek your arrest package.
With this and place.
You can now dispatched
the event by calling the
this dot have been
passed up publish method.
Please note that this isn't the
best way to dispatch events.
Domain events should
be dispatched from the
aggregate route not from
the command handler.
Will cover that in the
upcoming lessons.
For now let's save our changes
head over to the terminal
and start the application
by running the n p m rum
start depth commands.
When the application is up
and running we could use the
curl command to send a post
request to the alarms input.
If we switched to our other terminal
window we should see that are alarm created
event handler has been triggered and
the event has been successfully processed.
Excellent.
So we've successfully created
our first event and event handler.
In the next lesson will continue experimenting
with events and we'll see how we can
use them to implement
the read side of our system.