Eventual consistency
as a principal applied in
distributed computing
and distributed systems.
Were different nodes within the system
may exhibit temporary inconsistencies.
Allowing them to have varying
views of the data at any given moment.
This consistency model allows
the system to continue functioning.
Even during network partitions
or delays in message delivered.
Whereas eventual consistency
sacrifices consistency in the short term
it achieves consistency
and the long-term.
Drunk consistency
on the other hand.
As the safety guarantee that any to know
roads that have received the same set of
updates will be
in this same state.
Eventual consistency is a concept
closely related to the cap theorem
also known as brewers they're.
The cap theorem described
the tradeoffs that arise
when designing distributed
systems and states
and it is impossible for
a distributed system to
simultaneously provide all
three of the following guarantees.
See for consistency.
Meaning that every read received
the most recent right or an error.
A for availability.
Meaning that every request
receives a response without
guarantee that it contains
the most recent right.
And lastly p for
partition tolerance
meaning that the system
continues to function
and provide availability
inconsistency guarantees
even in the presence
of network partitions
i e
communication failures that prevent
some notes from talking to others.
The cap theorem asserts that he distributed
system can achieve any to of the three
guarantees but not
all three simultaneous.
Eventual consistency is the outcome
when a system prioritizes availability and
partition tolerance over
immediate consistency.
C n p
and the cap theorem.
This means that notes may
have temporary inconsistencies.
In the context of secure us
eventual consistency is achieved
by separating the read
and right sides of our system.
The right side is
responsible for handling the
commands and updating
the state of the system.
Meanwhile the read
site is responsible for
handling the events and
updating the read models.
The read models are eventually
consistent with the right models.
This means that the
read models are not
updated immediately
but rather a synchronously
at some later time.
This is particularly useful for systems
that have a lot of reads and few rights.
Be it
a flight boom booking system.
E-commerce system and even
some social media platforms.