In this lesson
we're going to implement
the read side of the system.
The sake of simplicity
we will use the same application for both
the read and right sides to avoid the need
for setting up a message broker
to communicate between services.
In a real world scenario
we would want to have
a separately deployed
service for the read side
which would subscribe to the
events published by the right side.
In this course
will be keeping things simple
will be wanted you to be aware that ideally
you would want to have that separation.
All right so let's get started.
Or the read side
will use the mongo db database to
store the normalized views of the data.
To integrate with mongo db.
Will use the nes js mongers package
and install by running the fallen command.
Once the installation
is complete.
Us up the our docker compose yaml
file to include the mongo db service.
Let's save our changes
head over to the terminal ants
thirty mongo db service by
running the docker compose up
dash d
read dashti be command.
Next let's navigate
to our core module file
an import the mongoose module
when the driver is set to aura.
Great.
So now if some one
selects o r m as the driver
the system will use mongo
db for reads and posts.
For rights databases.
While with the in-memory driver
it will use the in-memory collection for
both the read and right sides of our system.
Now to better understand why having a
separate read only data source may be useful
let's add a few more
attributes to the alarm entity.
Okay so we added three new
attributes to our alarm entity here.
Triggered at.
Which is the date and time
when the alarm was trigger.
Is acknowledged a boolean flag indicating
whether the alarm has been acknowledged.
And items.
Which as a list of alarm items or
alarm triggers that triggered the alarm.
Since we don't have
the alarm item entity yet
let's go ahead
and create it now.
With this entity and place.
Our right side database
schema will have to tables now.
Alarms
and alarm underscore items.
The alarm underscore items table will
have a foreign key to the alarms table.
Indicating which alarmed the
specific alarm item belongs to.
Let's now create the the normalized alarm
schema for the read side of our system.
Inside the new scheme as folder.
Let's create a new file called
materialized alarm view schema dot t s
and at the following
code inside.
As we can see
the materialized alarm view
schema embeds the items attribute.
Which means that the
materialized alarm view document.
Will contain all the
information right away.
Without the need to
join the alarm items table
which will help speed up
our read operations and.
While this is still a very basic example
it's somewhat demonstrates the benefits of
having a separate
read only model.
In a real world scenario.
Entities consists of
many more attributes
and that is where
secure as really shines.
For example
in alarm entity could have
a meta data attribute which
will contain a lot of
information about the alarm.
Such as the
location of the alarm.
The name of the device
that triggered the alarm
and the name of the supervisor
who acknowledge the alarm etc.
This information might be required by other
services the operate on reported alarms
let's say to perform
there own business logic.
But only a few attributes
are required to just
the alarm on the you why.
This is just an example
of how having require
data baked in could really
help our performance.
Okay so before we move on
let's also update the in-memory
driver to contain a new alarm item entity.
Let's also update
the alarm entity.
Who contain some new attributes.
Excellent.
But this change in place our
infrastructure layer is all set.
There are a few more repetitive tasks we
need to do before we can start implementing
be read side of
our system though.
Let's start by heading
over to our domain layer
unless create a new domain
class called alarm item
and add the
following code inside.
As you may have
already noticed with ddd
everything is strictly organized
and layers don't
leak into each other.
Infrastructure related annotations
are only used in the infrastructure layer.
Data transfer objects with validation
rules reside in the presentation layer
etc etc.
While this does make our code base
more verbose an easy to navigate.
It also requires a lot of boilerplate
code in introduces a lot of redundancy.
That's why it's always important to
make sure that the benefits of using ddd.
Outweigh the drawbacks
for any specific use case.
Alright
let's head over
to the alarm t s file
an update the alarm class to
contain the new attributes as well.
We're also going to move the
name and severity attributes
out of the constructor signature
and just keep the ID parameter there.
With these properties
and place will declare
to new public methods.
Acknowledge and add alarm item.
The acknowledge method was simply
set the is acknowledge flagged true.
And the ad alarm item method
will add a new alarm
item to the items or array.
Great.
Let's save our changes an
open up the alarm factory file now.
In here.
Atop up the the method signature
to accept to new arguments
triggered at
and items.
Next up.
Let's update the create method
to assign the
triggered an attribute
to the alarm instance.
Also let's not forget to
iterate over the items array
and at each item to the alarm.
Excellent.
Now onto the map or classes.
First
let's focus on the o r m driver.
In the to domain method
let's make sure we assign all
alarms attributes to the alarm object.
And last but not least.
At map alarm items
to the domain model.
Great.
Now
let's scroll down to the
to persistence method
and update to map
all new attributes.
Let's save our changes and real quick
do the same thing for the in-memory driver.
Perfect.
Please note that the reason we have to
update so many files as because we are
supporting two
different drivers.
If we were to use
only one driver.
Which is the case in most
real world applications.
We would spend a lot less
time on is repetitive tasks.
Were showcasing the
power of all these advice
Vance architectural
patterns in this course
so that's why we have a
few of these additional steps.
Alright so at that
out of the way
let's now move onto
the application layer.
Currently
our crate alarm command
exposes only two attributes.
Name
and severity.
That's updated to expose
the new attributes as well.
Great.
Now
inside the create an
alarm handler class
let's update the execute method
to pass the new attributes to the
alarm factory create method as well.
Last but not least.
Let's update our create alarm d t oh
class to expose these new attributes.
We could also add some
validation rules here.
And and a real world application
you would surely want them.
But since validation
isn't a focus of this course
will skip this step.
But please refer to the
nastiest fundamentals
course if you need a
refresher on validation.
Alright excellent.
Lastly
let's save our changes and head
over to the alarm controller file
an update the create method
to pass the new attributes to the
create alarm command constructor
and we should be all set.
There's just one
final step though
we need to let type r m
know about this new entity.
So let's go ahead and add the alarm
item entity to the type r m for feature re.
In the or and
persistence module file.
And finally our application
should be able to compile again.
Just a double check
let's open up our terminal
and first recreate our
containers so we don't have
any old entries in the database.
We can achieve this with docker
compose down remove orphans.
And then do docker
compose up dashed d again.
If we switched to the
other terminal window.
Let's see if we haven't
missed anything.
Far everything looks good to go.
If you're seeing
any errors here.
Make sure you follow
all the steps above.
All of the code we've
manipulated and the
file names can be found
below the course video
as always.
Since our application now
uses two different data stores
will split our repository to to
individual abstract classes.
Find alarms repository
and create alarm repository.
Also
note that our find a
alarms repository or return
objects that fulfill the
alarm breed model interface.
So for this
inside the domain folder.
Let's create a new
folder called read dash
models and inside of
it was create a new file.
Called alarm dot Reed dash model
dot to yes.
This class
will represent the read model which is
optimized for read intensive operations.
Such as queries
reporting and presenting data
to users or external systems.
It is distinct from
the domain model.
Which is optimized for right intensive
operations in a cab absolutes the core
business logic and
behavior of the domain.
The main purpose
of a read model.
Is to improve query
performance and provide a more
efficient way to access
data for specific use cases.
By
normalizing.
Aggregating or
tailoring the data to fit the
specific requirements
of a read operation.
Read models can significantly
reduce the complexity and time required
to her tree of information.
While in the case of our
demonstration application
the read model hairs almost
identical to our domain model.
In real world applications
this would rarely be the case.
So even though it may
seem as if we introduced a lot
of unnecessary redundancy
in or application here.
Is most likely won't be the
case in production apps.
Where read models domain
models and even database
schema are often very
different from one another.
Alright so let's
get started here.
Let's open up the
alarm repository file
and update the classname
to create alarm repository.
Let's also remove
the find all method
since we don't need it anymore.
Lastly.
Let's rename the file itself to
create alarm repository it up to yes.
Next to this file.
Let's create a new port.
Called find alarms
repository dot ts
and defined the find
alarms repository interface.
The difference between these two
is simply that one
is responsible for writing data
and the other as
responsible for reading it.
Also as we mentioned earlier.
Bind alarms repository
will return objects
that fulfilled the alarm
read model interface.
We'll also need
another port for inserting
materialized alarm views
into the read side database.
So let's create a new file called
up sir materialized alarm repository.
And define the upsurge
materialized alarm repository interface.
Let's save our changes and head
over to the get alarms query handler file.
An update its constructor to
inject the find alarms repository port.
Let's also make it return
alarm read model now as well.
Otherwise
everything i should
remain the same.
Now.
Onto our infrastructure liar.
Let's start with the in-memory driver
as it will be a lot easier to implement.
Burst
that's open up the in-memory
alarm repository class
and make implement both
the find alarms repository
an upsurge materialized
alarm repository porch it's.
Since will be using the same
class for both reading and writing.
Let's declare a new property that will
represent the materialized alarm views.
Next.
Let's update the find all method
signature to return alarm breed model.
Also.
Let's update the method
body to return an array
of values from the
materialized alarm views map
and lastly
let's add the missing
upsurge method.
Great.
Now onto the module file.
Let's open up the in-memory
persistence module file.
An update the providers array to provide
the find alarms repository and absurd
materialized alarm
repository ports.
Beer
we're using the use existing property
to tell nasty use the same instance of the
in-memory alarm
repository class for all ports.
Was also not forget
to export them to.
Great.
Now onto the or am driver.
This one's going to
be more complicated
as will be using mongo
db for real ring data.
We've made a lot of
changes so far but don't worry
we're making great
progress we're almost there.
Let's start by first opening
the our him alarm repository
and remove the find all method.
Next
let's rename the class two
or m create alarm repository.
And lastly
let's also update
the name of the file
to be create alarm
repository t s.
Next to this file
let's create a new file
called fine alarms
repository that ts
and defined the or oram
find alarms repository class.
In this file
were using the
inject model decorator
to inject the alarm mongoose model into
the or ram find alarms repository class.
Inside the final method.
Raising the find method to retrieve all
documents from the alarm collection.
We don't need to perform
any mapping here as the alarm
schema his idea cynical to
our alarm rate model class.
Remember
this was actually the goal of using a
separate data source with d normalized data.
Were starting to see some of
the benefits of that already great.
Now
but this repository in place
let's create a another poor
implementation for inserting
materialized the alarm views
into the read side database.
Let's create a new file
called absurd materialized
alarm repository dot ts.
Unless the find the or 'em up cert
materialized alarm repository class.
Similar to the
previous repository.
Were using the inject model decorator
again to inject the materialized alarm view
mongoose model
entered this class.
Inside the upsurge method here.
You can see that we're
using the find one in update
method to answer a new
document into the alarm collection.
Unless there's one that already
exists with the same ID in the collection.
Then
we updated.
We don't need to perform any mapping here
as the materialized the alarm view schema.
Is identical to the
alarm read model class.
Now let's open up the o r
m persistence module file an
update the providers of rate
provide newly created ports.
Like before.
A again not forget
to export them.
And lastly
we need to import
the mongoose module
or feature method and
pass the alarm schema to it
as an argument to register
the model as a provider.
Excellent.
Were almost finished now.
The only thing
we have left to do
is to update the alarm
created event handler file
to insert the the
normalized alarm document
into the materialized
alarm view collection.
So
let's open this file
and inject the absurd
materialized alarm repository
report into the alarm
created a vet hammer class.
Next up.
Let's update the handle method
to insert the d normalized alarm
model into the read side database.
And that's it.
As stated in the comment here
in a real world application
we would have to ensure that
this operation is atomic
with the creation of the alarm.
Otherwise we could end up with an alarm
that is not reflected in the read model
for example because the
database operation failed.
Leading to an
inconsistent state.
But.
How can we even implement this.
Well
if we had a message broker and place to
communicate between the right in read side.
We could use act and neck to inform
the broker about the success or failure
of the database operation.
If the database operation failed
the message will be re
cute and retreived later.
If the database
operation succeeded.
The message will be
removed from the q.
So to achieve this
we could also leverage
the transactional outbox
and inbox patterns.
They are both unfortunately
outside of the scope of this course
as they are quite involved.
But we wanted to make
sure we mentioned them
and that it would be ideal to include some
of these patterns in your application here.
If you're interested in learning
more about those patterns.
Check out our other course
extension called microservices
where we learn about
an implement them.
Alright so back to
our task at hand.
Let's run the application and see
if everything works as expected.
Once the application
is up and running.
Let's open up another
terminal window and send a post
request to the alarms and
point to create a new alarm.
You can find the curl command
below the course video as always.
And there we have it
as we can see
our alarm was
successfully created.
Now let's switch to the other terminal
window and take a look at the logs.
Great
no heirs.
So going back to
our curled terminal
let's said the get request
the alarms and point
to retrieve all the
materialized alarm views.
Were going to use the
Jason underscore p p tool here
to auto format
the Jace an output
making it easier to read.
Your operating system
doesn't support this to feel
free to admit that part of the
curl command shown here.
But fantastic as we can see
we received one alarm item back
with the embedded alarm items.
We had to set up quite a bit of code
in this lesson but we did a great job.
So to summarize
in this lesson we've
learned how to implement
the read side of the
seek your us patter.
Using nest years and mongo db.
Upon receiving an event
our system automatically
creates a d normalized alarm view
and stores
in the read side database.
While this approach works and is
commonly used in many applications.
It introduces a lot of redundancy
and can lead to inconsistencies
if not implemented correctly.
Also
we end up with
multiple sources of truth.
Which can be hard to
maintain down the road.
This is why the seek your as pattern usually
goes hand in hand with event sourcing.
Where instead of having
the right side database.
We store all events
in an event store
and use these events to
build the read side database.
This approach is of course
more complex to implement
but it does have many benefits.
Don't.
We'll be covering this approach
in the next few lessons.