Event sourcing
is an architectural pattern utilized in
software development and distributed systems.
Where this state of an application is
determined by a sequence of events.
Rather than storing
the current state
as a single record
in a database.
In event sourcing
each change to the application state
is captured as and of mutable event.
These events represent
meaningful actions or
facts that have occurred
within the system.
Instead of updating
the state directly.
New events are
appended to an event store
in chronological order.
This is fundamentally different
from the traditional approach.
Where the current status stored in a database
and updated whenever a change occurs.
Some key characteristics
of event sourcing are
immutable events.
Events
cannot be altered
or deleted once store.
Ensuring an audible record of all changes
made to the application state over time.
Event store.
Events are stored
in an event store.
Which is an append
only log of events.
The event store is the single
source of truth for the application state.
And state reconstruction.
The application state
can be reconstructed by
replying all the events
from the event store.
This allows for a comprehensive historical
view of the application stay and supports
features like time
travel debugging
and auditing.
Some benefits of
event sourcing are
auditability.
Event sourcing provides
a complete history of all
changes made to the
application state over time.
This allows us to easily audit the system
and understand how the status of vault.
Where aires might have occurred
etc.
Time travel debugging
gives us the ability to replay events
and enables developers to time travel
and debug the application
at any point in the past.
Simplifying issue
diagnosis and resolution.
And lastly
scale ability.
Event sourcing allows
us to scale the read and
right side of the
application independently.
So while event sourcing
has many benefits
as anything else it also
comes with some drawbacks.
One being complexity.
Event sourcing is a
complex pattern that
requires a lot of boilerplate
code to implement.
This can make the project difficult to
understand and maintain so always consider the
tradeoffs before
using this pattern.
And also
eventual consistency.
The read side of the application is
eventually consistent with the right side.
This means that there
might be a delay between
the time and event is
written to the event store
in the time it is processed
by the read side.
As we mentioned
in a previous lesson.
Event sourcing is often used in can
injunction with the seek you are as pattern.
Which we have of course
started implementing in this course.
In this case
the right side of the
application is responsible
for storing events
in the event store.
While the read side is responsible
for reading events from the event store
and updating the
read model accordingly.
In the next lesson
we're going to move past
theory and the pros and cons
and learn how to actually
implement event sourcing
in our and sgs applications.