In events store
is designed to be the source
of truth for the state of a system.
It is an append only
log of events that can be
used to reconstruct the
state at any point in time.
Now event store is nothing
more than just a fancy
name for a database that
stores events which means
we can practically use
any database we want.
As long as it meets all the
requirements for our application.
For example we
could use mongo db
post grass Cassandra or
even a kafka message broker
with persistent storage
which is an event log.
While kafka was not specifically
designed for event sourcing.
Its features and characteristics
it a suitable choice for
managing events streams
and event driven architectures.
Although
there's a few things to keep
in mind when you said kafka
for example who would need to ensure
we have the correct ordering of events etc.
There are also specialized databases that
are designed specifically for event source
such as the events store
be.
A provides a number of useful features
out of the box such as storing events
in ordered streams and providing
a way to filter them by type.
Storing their meta
data and much more.
On the downside
events thirty db as not as
popular as other databases
so might be difficult to find
resources and support when needed.
In this lesson
will learn how to implement
event sourcing in our
nest js application using
mongo db from the ground up
but just remembered that you can use
any database of your choice of the future.
Since we're already using
mongo db for our read side.
We won't even have to install
any additional dependencies.
Remember the concepts and
patterns will cover in this lesson
are applicable to any data store and
can be easily adapted to your needs.
All right.
Let's get started.
Let's first at a new docker
service to our docker compose file.
Will call it
event dash store.
It's important to note
here that even though we
already have a mongo
db service in our dockerfile.
We need to add a new one
that we use specifically
for storing events.
Remember
this is because these
two databases which
facilitate the read side
and the events or side.
Are fundamentally different
and serve different purposes.
Also as we already mentioned in previous
lesson in a real world application the read
side and right side services would and
ideally should be deployed separately.
Instead of being part
of the same application.
In this course we've
decided to keep them together
in this project for
simplicity's sake of horse.
Is to avoid introducing concepts that
are relevant to what we're trying to learn.
Such as mon repos code
sharing microservices
message brokers etc.
If you're interested in want to
learn more about these topics.
Find out more in our dedicated
microservices course extension.
Back to our docker
compose file here.
What's also different bought
this service that we just added
is that we're using
a different port.
Two seven oh one eight
because otherwise
we'd run into conflicts.
And we're also using a different
command to stay dart the mongo db server.
Or passing the
rebel set flag
to enable replication and
specify the name of the replica set.
Vf event store rebel set.
This is required as will
be using mongo db change
streams to listen for
changes in the event store
and the only work
with replica sets.
Were also mounting a new file
called events door mongo a net.
The docker entry point in it db
directory.
This file will be executed
when the container is
started it will be used
to initialize the data a's.
Let's go ahead and create this
file inside of the new scripts director.
We don't need to pass
any configuration here
since will only have a
single note in the replica set.
With this service and place.
We can now run docker compose
up dashti to start the events thorpe.
Great.
Now that we have our
events or up and running
what's navigate to
the core directory and
create a new file they're
called core constance
with the following concept.
We will use this constant
to register a separate
mongo db connection
for the event store.
The reason we're doing this is because
we want to maintain two different mongo db
connections that
our application.
One for the reside
in one for the event store.
That achieve that we need to
give them different namespaces.
Next
let's head over to
the core module file
an import the mongoose module.
Know that we're passing the
connection name option here.
Give this connection
a different namespace.
Or also setting the direct
connection option to true.
As we need to connect
to local replica sets.
Without this option enabled.
You may run into errors when running your
events door inside of a docker container.
Also since in this course we won't be
implementing an in-memory events store
we just imported the
mongoose module in a
static configuration
object of the core module.
If you want to practice everything you
learned in the hexagonal architecture section.
You can try to implement a swappable
in memory of Ben store on your own.
Right moving on.
Now that we have our
events door connection setup.
Let's create a new module
called shared that will
contain all the shared
code for our application.
You may be asking
yourself why are we going to
use the existing common
folder for this purpose.
Well the reason is
that this is a common pattern
in ness Jess applications.
Because the common directory.
To be met the for
containing interfaces
abstract classes.
Commonly used pipes
guards interceptors
and basically any components that
can be shared across multiple modules
and at the same time.
All of which do not belong
to any specific module.
Whereas shared on the other hand will
mostly contained components registered and
exported from a
dedicated shared module
that were going to
create and just a moment.
While these concepts
may seem similar
they're are actually
quite different.
However if you find
this confusing you can
always use the common
directory for both purposes
as long as you're consistent
with your naming conventions.
Will take over to our terminal
and call
ness gee mo
shared.
Once the modules created
let's open up the
share directory
and inside of this folder
let's create to new directories.
One being domain
and the other
of infrastructure.
Well first focus on the
infrastructure directorate
let's open it up
in and ordered have
everything nicely organized.
Let's create a new directory
called prevent store in side of it.
This folder
will contain all the code
related to the event store
implementation including
the event store class itself.
So let's stop your for a
brief moment and think
about what we need
to implement for first.
We need to declare an
event mongo schema that
will represent the events
stored in the database.
Will also need serializer
Andy serializer to convert
events to and from Jason.
To connect our in memory
events stream to the event store.
Only need to implement a
publisher class that will hook up to the
you are as module.
And finally.
Need a class that
will be responsible for
storing and retrieving
events from the database
the of maga event store itself.
Perfect.
Now that our game
plan is all clear
was actually start
implementing everything.
Let's first create a new
file called event schema
inside of the scheme us folder
and add the following content.
This is a pretty straightforward
schema definition bullets
break it down to make sure
things become even more clear.
Erst
were using the schema
decorator to specify that we want
to enable the created at
timestamp for this schema.
Which means that every
time a new of venice created.
This created at field will
be automatically populated
with the current date and time.
Our class will contain
the following properties.
Stream ID.
The ID of the stream to
which the event belongs
this usually equals the
aggregate ID which can
be prefixed with the
aggregate type as well.
Type
the type of the event.
Position the position of
the event in the stream.
And data
which is the event payload.
Below were also creating a unique
index on the stream ID and position fields.
This is essential
as we want to make
sure we'll never have to
events with the same
position in the same stream
which could occur
if we had multiple operations
happening at the same time
on the same aggregate
and in parallel.
By creating a unique index x.
Are making sure that
the database will ruin air
if we try to insert an
event in the same position.
As acquaintance preventing us
from corrupting our event stream
and leaving us with
a consistent state.
Now
this position will also represent
the version of the aggregate.
The will need to make sure that
we always incremented by one
when we append a
new of it to the stream.
Will see how to do
that and just a moment.
So with our schema and place.
Us navigate to the domain folder and here
let's create a new file called version dot
t s inside of the value
objects directory.
Version will be a simple
primitive a number
but by wrapping it in a value objects
were adding some additional semantics to it
making it more explicit
and self explanatory.
So inside of the virgin file
as add the fallen content.
And that's it.
Next let's create a new
aggregate route t s file
in the domain folder and
add the fallen content.
All right so what we have here as a
base class for our aggregate roots.
It extends the aggregate route class
provided by the nest g as secure as package
and as a virgin property to it.
This property is private and can
only be accessed via the getter
and updated through a
private set version method.
Are also setting
the initial version
two zero.
Lastly.
Let's create a new folder called interfaces
in it's out of this folder will create
the serializable
of vent t s file
with the fallen content.
Now let's break it
down the line by line.
Starting from the
bottom to the top.
Where defining the serializable
event interface that will
represent an event that can
be stored in the event store.
It will contain the same set of properties
as our mongoose event schema.
Stream ID
type position and data.
However
the data property will be
serialized version of the event.
Will see how to serialize the
event payload and just a moment.
Above it
we're defining the serialized event payload
type that will be used to infer this
serialized type of a
given of at payload.
It's a recursive type
that will iterate over all the properties
and if a property has a to jaison method.
It will in further return
type of that method
as the serialized tight.
Long story short
serializable event
describes the shape of the
event that can be
stored in the event store.
We need to serialize the
event payload before storing
it in the database to auto
unwrap any value objects
and convert them to their
corresponding primitives.
Back to our
infrastructure folder
let's create a new directory
called serializer years
and its side of this
folder will create the event
serializer ts filed
with the fallen content.
This class here will be responsible for
serializing domain of and instances into a
format that can be
stored in the event store.
A provides a single serialized
method that accepts two arguments.
The event instance and the aggregate
route instance that dispatch the event.
Inside the method body.
Were extracting the event
type and aggregate ID
and there were returning
a serialized event object.
To determine the position
of the event in the stream.
Were simply incriminating the
current version of the aggregate by one.
Also were using the to jaison method which
is missing to serialize the event paler
so let's go ahead and
create that method now.
What this method does is that it iterates
over all the properties of the event
and if a property has
a to Jason method
it will call it a
return the result.
Otherwise it will
return the original value.
All it looks fairly complicated
it's actually pretty simple.
Excellent.
Now that we have our event serializer in
place let's create a new file called mongo
event store and add
the fallen content.
This class here will be responsible
for persisting events in the event store.
The provides a
single persist method.
That accepts
either a single event
or an array of events and then
saves them to the database.
Were using the insert
many method provided by
mongoose to insert
multiple documents at once.
You can see there's also
a try catch block to handle
any errors that might have
occurred during the insertion
of are now.
It only aboard the transaction.
So in the code here
were checking if the error
code is equal to eleven thousand.
This is the error code that mongo db
returns when a unique constraint is finally.
If that's the case.
Where logging in error message and printing
the air message out to the console.
Will use this error code to
detect for stale aggregates
basically this is the scenario
that were described earlier.
Were there can be multiple parallel
operations on this same aggregate
but
we want to ensure that only
one operation can succeed.
Perfect.
Now that we have our events store and place
the only thing that's left is to connect
our newly created events door to the event
bus so let's go ahead and do that now.
We'll start by creating
a new publishers folder
and inside of this folder
will create the event store publisher
ts file with the following content.
This class here
implements the i event publisher
interface provided by nest js secure us.
This interface in forces us to
define the published method.
Which accepts two arguments.
The event instance in the aggregate
route instance that dispatched the event.
Inside the method body.
We are serializing the event with the use
of the event serializer be created earlier
and then were persisting
in the event store.
There's also the an
application bootstrap method
that will be called by ness js when
the application is bootstrapped.
Inside of this method.
Where setting the events bust
out publisher property to this.
Which means that the event possible use our
event store publisher to publish events.
While this is all we need for our application
with also add a new publish all method
that can accept an array of events
and and published them all at once.
We won't need this in
our current project but it
might come in handy in
your future applications.
The only difference here compared
to the regular published method.
Is that we're updating the
position of the event into the stream.
Are doing that by by
adding the current version of
the aggregate to the index
of the event in the array
and an incriminating it by one.
Know that this is very important to
ensure that the events in the array
are stored in the correct order.
Excellent.
Finally
lets wire everything up
by creating a new shared
infrastructure module file
with the following content.
Here
we're just registering all the
providers we created earlier.
Finally.
Let's import the shared
infrastructure module
into our shared module
and then very exported.
And last but not least.
Let's import the shared module into the
alarms infrastructure module and again
reexport it
and then we're all done
rate.
Before we test everything out there are
still a few things we need to change in our
alarms module to integrate it with
the events store that we just created.
First.
Let's navigate to
the domain folder
and open up the alarm t
s class and make it extend
version aggregate route
from our shared domain.
Since were no extending the versioned
aggregate route class we need to make sure that
we're calling the super
method in our constructor.
Next.
Let's head over to the alarm factory
and after creating a new alarm instance
let's call the apply
method of the aggregate.
Passing in the alarm
created event instance.
You can see that were also
setting the skip handler option to true
in order to skip the execution of
the local in aggregate of and handler.
Don't worry we'll talk more
about this in the next chapter.
Finally
lets navigate to the create
alarm command handler.
And let's update its
dependencies first.
We're not going to need the
event bus nor create alarm
repository providers so let's
go ahead and remove them.
Instead
we're going to need the event publisher
so let's go ahead and inject that here.
Inside of the
execute method here.
Let's remove the saving logic and
event bus published call and instead
let's use the event publisher
to merge the publisher context
with the alarm
aggregate instance.
Now this one's important.
Merging the publisher contacts
with the aggregate instance
will allow us to use the
apply method of the aggregate
to apply the event
to the aggregate
and then commit the
changes to the event store.
This is a crucial
step as otherwise
the event would never
reach the event store.
So with all of that
let's save our changes
and test everything out.
Let's open up our
terminals and make sure that
our application has
bootstrapped successfully.
If so.
Let's switch of the other terminal window
and let's create a new alarm by sending a
post request to the
alarms endpoint.
Once again we're using
the jaison pp tool to format
the output but you can
omit it if you need to.
Great so it seems
everything's working.
Let's switch to the other terminal
window endless checked locks.
As we can see here
there are no heirs
our event was successfully
persisted into the event store.
However
there's no sign of the alarm
created event in the logs.
Mimi the alarm created
event handler was not execute.
Also.
We try to fetch the alarms.
Will see that our newly
created alarm is not there
but why.
Well
while we did published
the event to the event store
we didn't get set up
watchers that would listen for
new offense inserted into
the Margaret e b collection
and execute the
corresponding handlers.
But not to worry
we'll do all of that
in the next lesson.
If you've been following
along so far great job keep it up.
If you're seeing any heresy here
make sure you didn't miss
any of the code snippets
or files that we added
throughout this lesson.
All of the code
can be found below the
course video as always.