In the previous lesson
we have created a new events or
an integrated it with our application.
Dispatched events are now
automatically persisted in the event store.
But that's when the magic stops.
Conceptually.
Our events are flowing out of the
application but they're not flowing back in.
This will be even easy to
see why it's happening if
we had a separate application
for writing and reading.
Not to worry
we'll get things working
here and just a moment.
Now when it comes
to processing events
there are two
different strategies
push
and pull.
In this course.
Are going to implement the pushed
strategy with collection watchers meaning
we're going to watch for new
mongo db documents or events.
Whenever a new document
is inserted into the collection.
Our application will receive a signal with
the new document payload past in with it.
Then.
We can use that document
to recreate the event instance
and add added to the event bus.
In the poll strategy
on the other hand
instead of subscribing
to the collection watchers
who would periodically pull
the database for new events
to determine what
events are knew.
We would need to keep track
of the last processed event.
For example by storing
the version of the aggregate
in the read database.
Then.
It would query the database.
Or all events with a position greater
than the version of the aggregate
which corresponds to
the last process event.
Alternatively we could use
a cursor based approach
and just track the number
of events processed.
This is a slightly
simpler approach
as our application can
process events at its own pace
but it's also less efficient.
As we're constantly queering
the database for new events
even if there are none.
Whether you choose
the push or pull strategies
depends on your use cases
the frequency of events
type of the database
your are using
whether it supports
change streams or not
etc.
But in our case
let's jump right in
and implement the push
strategy with collection watchers.
Let's start by creating
a new file called
events bridged at t s in
the events store folder
let's add the
following code inside.
And let's break it down the
line by line.
Our events bridge class
implements to interfaces
an application bootstrap
and an application shut down.
And the an application
bootstrap life cycle hook.
Or creating a new change stream and
were subscribing to the change event.
Whenever a new event is
inserted into the of cent store
the change event will be omitted and will
call the handle event store change method.
In the poll based approach
instead of using a change stream
as we're doing here
we would periodically pull
the events store for new events.
We keep track of what
events we already processed.
We would need to store at the
last processed event or cursor
in a separate collection.
Back to our code
in the an application and
shut down the life cycle hook
were disclosing the change
stream to prevent memory leaks.
Inside the handle event
store change method
we extract the inserted event from
the chain stream insert document object
and were d serializing.
Note that the change true insert document
object exposes the t x n number prob forty
which represents the
transaction identifier.
If you need multi document
transactions in your applications.
You can use this property
to achieve atomicity.
For example
if we inserted multiple alarm related
events as part of a single transaction.
All events would have the
same transaction number
or txn accent number value.
Now before we can push
the event to the event bus
we need to d serialize it.
So let's create a new file called event the
serializer in the d serializer as folder
let's go ahead and
add the fallen code.
This simple class takes an
event and DC realizes it by
mapping the event data object
to the corresponding of a class.
For example
if we have an event with
the type alarm created event.
Will map it's data tribute to the
alarm created event class instance.
Let's declared the
first missing method.
Get event class by
type.
In this method
we return the corresponding class
reference based on the event type.
As we can see this
isn't the most scalable
approach but will show
a better one later on.
And finally.
Lets declared the last
missing method here
instantiate
serialized the event.
This one might
be a bit confusing
let's go ahead
and break it down.
We have to input arguments here.
The first one is the
event class reference
and the second one
is the event data object.
The object are create method.
Creates a new object
with the specified prototype.
In our case the prototype object
is the event cls stop prototype.
Then
we're using the object
out a sign method
to copy the properties from the data
object to this newly created object.
Finally
were returning the new object which
is an instance of the event cls class.
This is all required so that we
can push the event to the event bus.
The event bus expects an instance of the
event class not just the plain object to
recognize what
event handlers to call.
Great
so let's save our changes head
over to the events bridge t s file
and let's inject the newly
created event d serializer class.
With this dependency injected.
Let's scroll down to handle
events store change and
let's d serialized the event
and push it to the stream.
And that's it.
We've successfully implemented the
push strategy with collection watchers.
Before we test everything out.
Let's make sure we register our new events
bridge and event d serializer classes in
the shared
infrastructure module.
The last but not least
let's open up the alarm
created event handler
and update the handle method signature
to take the serialized event payload
of type alarm created event
as an input argument.
Let's also update the i
event handler type argument
to use this same type.
The reason why we're
doing this a simple.
Our event handlers received
the serialized the vents now
but not real domain of and
instances with value objects etc.
That's why we also have to tweak
the execute method just the litter bit.
And voila
were done so let's go
ahead and test everything out.
Let's head over to our
terminal and in a separate tab
let's create a new alarm.
Let's switch to the
other terminal window
and as we can see
the event handler has been
successfully invoked fantastic.
Just a double check if
our newly created event
is also reflected in
the read side database.
Let's try and fetch all alarms.
And as we can see
our newly created
alarm is they're great.
But now that we've
come full circle
we fixed the missing
link from the last lesson
we're now able to create
events in our event store
but now we can also access that information
on the read side of our application
are making great progress.