In the previous lesson
we've seen how he can d serialize
events and pushed them onto the of at bus.
However
to map serialized events to
their corresponding event classes
we had to manually register each
event class in the event to serializer.
Get event class by type method.
While this might not be a big deal for
smaller applications it can become a bit
tedious when the
number of events gross.
And this lesson
we'll see how we can auto wire
event classes using custom decorators.
To begin.
Let's create a new file
called event cls registry
inside of the
event store folder.
Let's add the
following code inside.
As we can see here
this is a simple class that
provides to static methods
add and get.
The ad method is used to register an
event class and the get method is used to
retrieve an event
class by its name.
Since both methods are static
we can use them without
instantiating the class
so we can live outside
of the nes js container.
With this in place
let's create a new directory called
decorators inside of the shared folder
and let's create a
new file they're called
auto wired event
decorator dot t s.
Here we're going to create
a custom class decorator
it will be used to auto register
a target class in the event
a less registry.
Were achieved this let's
add the following code.
Great.
Now
let's head over to the alarm created
event ts file must add the auto wired event
decorator to the
alarm created of a
class.
Last but not least.
Let's open up the event d serializer ts
file and let's update the get event class by
type method to use the
event seal as registry.
And that's it.
Now regardless of how many
events we have we can simply
add the auto wired event
decorator to the event class
and it will be automatically
registered to the event cls registry.
To see everything
action
etc or to our terminal and test
everything out by creating a new alarm.
Let's switch to the
other terminal window
and as we can see the event handler
has been successfully invoked fantastic.
With everything
we've done this lesson
we now have the ability
to automatically auto wire
classes instead of manually
doing this over and over again
great.