In the previous lessons
we learned how to
dispatch events from
version aggregate.
Store events in the event store.
Subscribed to events
using collection watchers.
The serialize events and
pushed them onto the event bus
and lastly.
Listen to events from the event bus and
update the read side database accord Langley.
While what we've accomplished so far is
amazing and we were really made a lot of
progress we're still missing
one important piece of the puzzle.
How can we make updates
to our existing aggregates.
We can't retrieve their read
model representation from the
eventually consistent read side
database because as we know
it's not guaranteed
to be up to date.
We also don't have a dedicated right side
database because we're using the events
store as our single
source of truth.
When you're in this situation
this is where the concept of
rehydrating aggregates comes into play.
The rehydrating
aggregates concept is the
process of reconstructing
an aggregate object
by replaying the events that have
been previously stored in the event store.
When we say hydration
we're referring to the process
of populating and objects
fields or properties with
data from a storage medium.
In the context of aggregates.
Rehydration is the
reverse process.
It's about taking
the stored data
in using it
to restore the aggregate
object to it's previous state.
The rehydration process is critical for
maintaining the consistency and integrity of
aggregates in a ddd
driven application.
By carefully reconstructing
aggregates from their stored state
and enforcing domain
rules during this process.
We ensure that the system remains
faithful to the underlying business logic.
It's important to note that while
rehydration is a central concept in d d d.
It's implementation details can
vary based on the technology stack
any architectural choices
made in any specific project.
All right now that we've gone
over some of the high level concepts
let's get down to business.
To begin.
Let's open up the
monga events door t s file
and inject the event
d serializer class.
Will use this class to d
realize events
from the event store.
Next up let's create a new method
here called get events by stream ID.
Inside of this method.
Let's first retrieve all of the
events from the event store
and then filter
them by stream ID
and then sort them
by their position.
Next let's check if there are any events
corresponding to the provided stream ID
and if not.
Let's make sure to
throw an exception.
Lastly.
Let's the serialized the
events and return them.
Great.
Now
let's create a new application
directory inside of these shared folder.
Inside this directory.
Let's create another
folder called ports.
Your
will create a new file called
events stored up to yes
and then let's add
the fallen code.
This port will be used to
abstract the event store
implementation details away
from the application layer.
Back to our mongo
events or rts file.
Let's make this class
implement the events store port.
Let's save our changes
navigate to the shared
infrastructure module t s file
and let's register
the event store port.
Using an existing mongol
events store provider.
And let's not forget to export
the events to report as well.
Great.
With this in place.
A ton of her to the
aggregate route ts file
and let's declare a new method
called load from history.
The parrot
aggregate route class already
has a load from history method
but it expects an
array of domain events
not objects following our
customer serializable event shape.
What the function does here
is that it iterates over
the provided events and
applies them to the
aggregate object one by one.
Using the apply method.
The apply method
invokes the corresponding event
handler method on the aggregate object
which in turn.
Updates the aggregate state.
It also determines which of at handler
method to invoke based on the events type.
We'll see how all of this
works and just a second.
Also notice that it does not
set the aggregate version
which is something we
need to do manual here.
As an additional know
we assume hear that events are sorted
by their position in ascending order.
So make sure that that is the case for your
application to if you want to use his coat.
You may need to have
it handled differently.
Let's save our changes
navigate to the shared
application folder
let's create a new file they're
called aggregate rehydrated up to us.
Here let's add
the following code.
Will need the events the report to
retrieve events from the event store
and the event publisher to merge
the aggregate object with the event bus.
Next
let's create a new
method called rehydrate
and let's break it
down line by line.
First we retrieve all the events for a
given aggregate from the event store.
Next we merge the aggregate
class with the event publisher
so that we can dispatch
events from objects of this class.
Then
we create a new
instance of the aggregate
and pass the aggregate
ID to its constructor.
Lastly
reload the aggregate from history
using the method we've just created
and then return it.
Are a great slot save our changes and
head over to the shared module t us file.
Here.
Let's register the aggregate
rehydrate or class as a
provider and also once again
let's not forget to exported.
Perfect.
We now have all the
building blocks and place
let's put them to good use.
But before we can do that.
We need to first expose
a new and point from r
a p i that lets us operate
on an existing alarm.
Let's open up the
alarms controller ts file
and let's add a new
and point called patch.
Alarms Colin ID
slash acknowledge.
This endpoint will be used to
acknowledge and existing alarm
for example
when a supervisor confirms that an
alarm is valid and has been investigated.
Let's save our changes
head of rid of the commands
folder and let's create
a new file they're called
acknowledge alarm
dot command up t s.
Here
let's add the following code.
With this in place
let's open up the
alarm service ts file let's
add the missing
acknowledged method there.
This acknowledge method
will be used to dispatch the acknowledge
alarm command to the command bus.
Now before we move onto
the command handler part.
Let's switch to our domain layer must
add a new alarm acknowledged of venn.
Note that here we're
using the auto wired
event decorator to
otter wire the evac class.
Next let's open up
the alarm aggregate
let's update the existing
acknowledge method to
dispatch the alarm
acknowledged event of vent.
In this method.
We simply apply the alarm
acknowledged event events
to the aggregate.
Okay so let's stop
here for quick moment.
Where's the logic that actually
acknowledges the alarm.
Well we don't have it yet
and that's something
we'll implement right now.
As we mentioned in
the previous lessons
the apply method
invokes the corresponding
event handler method
on the aggregate object.
Which in turn updates
the aggregate state.
So.
Let's add a new event
handler method called
an alarm acknowledged
to create that very method.
To make it even more type-safe
we can use the
following technique.
Now if we updated
the event class name.
The corresponding event handler method name
would be updated automatically as well.
Before we move on.
There's one missing handler
we should add here as well.
Above the an alarm
acknowledged event method.
Let's add the following handler.
This event handler will be executed
by the load from history method
when we rehydrate the
aggregate from history.
Were all sat in
this file for now.
But
we need to do a few more
things than some other
files to make everything
work as expected.
Let's navigate to the alarm severity
unless at a missing to Jason method.
Great.
Now if we go back to our alarm.
We can see that the errors gone.
Excellent.
With our aggregate updated
let's navigate to the commands
folder in the application layer
and alongside the acknowledge
alarm command ts while.
Let's create another file
are called
acknowledged alarm dot
command dash handler dot yes.
Your
let's add the following code.
Or now we're just logging
the command and that's it
slots improve their.
Using the aggregate
rehydrate or dependency.
Let's rehydrate
the alarm aggregate
based on the commands
alarm ID property.
Next up
let's acknowledge the alarm.
Next
let's call commit to publish
events to the event stream.
And finally
let's return the alarm instance.
Great.
Let's save our changes and head
of her to the alarms module t s file.
Your.
Let's register the acknowledge alarm
command handler class as a provider.
The last but not least
only need a corresponding event
handler to update the read model.
So
let's create a new alarm.
Event handler file in
the event handlers folder
and let's add our
usual boilerplate code.
Inside of the handle method.
Let's use the up sir
materialized alarm
repository dependency
to update the read model.
Excellent.
Before we test everything out
let's make sure we register
the alarm acknowledged of
at handler class as a
provider in the alarms module t
file.
While here
let's also update the
alarm created event handler
since it now might be airing out
due to the newly added
to jaison method in the
alarm severity value object
we added a moment ago.
All right and that's it.
With everything
we've done in place
let's give it a try.
So let's head over to
our terminal and make
sure that our application
is up and running.
Since there are no heirs
let's open up a separate
terminal window.
Unless retrieved
the list of alarms.
Let's grab one of
them by their alarm ID
and let's acknowledge a
curling alarms slash
the ID we copy.
And make sure that
we do a patch request
to hit that new and point we
just created a moment ago.
Fantastic no errors.
Let's switch over to the
other terminal window
and verify if there
are any errors there.
Perfect no errors
here as well run a role.
Also we can see here that both
acknowledged alarm command handler
and alarm acknowledged event
handler providers were executed.
Just a double check.
Let's retrieved that
list of alarms again.
And there we go we
can see that the alarm
has actually been
acknowledged or code works.
If we look
the is acknowledged property has been
set to true for the given alarm we did it.
So we covered quite a lot in this lesson
but we managed to successfully give her
application the
ability for rehydration.
Allowing us to actually make
updates to our existing aggregates.
Great work if you've been following along
and have your application locally as well.
There might be some minor
nuances as we mentioned earlier
in this lesson for your
specific applications use cases
but.
The majority of
everything we've done here
can be used for most any system.