In the previous lesson.
We learned how to rehydrate
in aggregate from history.
By replying all events
from the stream.
This approach works well
for aggregates with a
small number of events.
However
as the number of events grows the rehydration
process can become time consuming and
quite inefficient to
address this issue.
We can use a technique
known as snapshots.
Snapshots are a way to reduce the need to
replay the entire event log every time you
want to reconstruct the
current state of an entity.
A snapshot.
Is essentially a point in time
representation of an entity state.
It captures the relevant
data that represents the
entity state at a certain
event or event sequence.
Instead of replying all the
events from the beginning of time.
You can use the snapshot
as a starting point
and then apply only the
subsequent events to reach
the desired current state.
Snapshots are
particularly useful
when dealing with aggregates
the have accumulated
a substantial number
of events over time.
Making state
reconstruction from scratch
a very resource
intensive operation.
While this might not be the
case in our application so far.
Snapshots are still a very useful
technique to learn and understand.
As at some point
your system might
benefit from utilizing them.
For example.
Imagine that we have
an aggregate that has
accumulated more than one
thousand events over time.
A good example of
such an aggregate
would be a shared live document
that is edited by multiple users.
Be at a Google doc
or a Google sheet.
Each set of changes made by a
user would be represented by an event
being an accumulation of
all changes made by that user
with and a single session.
Long lived documents would have a
substantial number of events over time
with additions deletions
of text images tables etc.
If we wanted to rehydrate
such an aggregate.
We would have
to reply all events.
However
if we have a snapshot
that captures the state of
the aggregate after let's
say one thousand events.
We can use that
snapshot as a starting point
instead of a base aggregate.
And then apply only the
subsequent one thousand event it's
to reach the
desired current state.
With this technique we
can significantly reduce
the time it takes to
rehydrate aggregate.
On the other hand.
Storing snapshots is yet another
concern that we would have to take care of.
Making our system
even more complex.
So make sure to always keep that in
mind and make sure that your application
really need snapshots
before implementing them.
As adding snapshot in our
application here would be overkill
but you might find
them useful in your own
projects so we wanted to
make sure dimension them
so that you keep them in
mind for your future projects.