A saga
is a pattern used to
manage and coordinate the
execution of long running
business processes
or distributed transactions.
A saga can be thought of
as a process or a workflow
that orchestrates the execution
of multiple commands and events
across different
aggregates or services.
It ensures that the
entire sequence of actions
either succeeds or fails
as a whole
preserving the
integrity of the data.
In event driven systems
sagas are typically
implemented as a state
machine that react to events
and issues commands to
other aggregates or services.
Since the necessary as secure as packet uses
are x j s to control the flow of events.
We can use the powerful are
extra Jess operators to combined.
Buffer
and coordinate events emitted
by different aggregates or services.
Sagas can also represent
processes that span multiple steps
and might take a significant
amount of time to complete.
For example
a saga could be used to implement a
multi-step onboarding process for new users.
Each step of the process.
Will be represented by a
command and an event.
The saga would react to these events in
issue the next command in the sequence.
The saga would even be responsible
for handling timeouts and failures.
Ensuring that the entire process
either succeeds or fails as a whole.
This is why it's important
that the state of a saga
needs to be persisted
in a database.
Allowing it to survive
system failures and restarts.
In this lesson
for going to implement a very simple time
based saga with the business requirement
that are new saga will react
to the alarm created event.
In issued the
notify facility
supervisor command
in the instance
where three alarms
from the same facility
or create did in a
five second window.
Something must be
really wrong at that facility.
Were making sure
some one has notified.
Alright
so let's get started
let's head over to our ID
and create a new notify facility
supervisor command class.
Inside of the alarms application
commands folder.
Next up
let's create a new sagas folder
inside of the alarms
application directory.
And also create a new cast
getting alarms saga t s file inside it
with a fallen content.
Now let's break everything down
here as there's quite a lot happening.
So first you might have
noticed that we're using
the saga decorator to
Mark the start method
as a saga.
The start method
as a function that takes an
observable of events as an input
and returns an observable
of command as an output.
The events dollar sign
observable is a stream
of all events emitted
by the application.
In our case we're using
the of type operator
to filter out only the alarm
created event events.
Next.
Were using the group by operator
to just for
demonstration purposes
group events by alarm name.
In a real world application
also if we had the meditative
field here as we surely
would with real facilities.
We would ideally want a
group events by their facility ID.
Were keeping things simple
and is real world
as we can hear.
Next we're using the buffer
timer operator inside of roadmap
to buffer all events admitted
with and a five second window.
Setting the maximum
number of events two three.
Then we're using the
filter operator to filter
out emissions that contain
less than three events
and finally
we're using the map
operator to map the buffered
events to the notify facility
supervisor command.
You might have noticed that there's a lot
of comments here in the coat as our alarms
currently don't have
a facility ID property.
Since this is the
focus of this lesson.
Are going to skip this part in assume that
all alarms belonged to the same facility.
You could add the meta data attribute your
alarm's as an exercise though if you want.
Okay moving on
so before we can use our saga
we need to register the saga
in the alarms module ts file.
Let's save our changes
head over to our terminal
and let's create multiple
alarms in a short period of time.
Let's switch to our
other terminal window
and as we can see the
saga has been executed
and and notified facility supervisor
command has been dispatched
excellent.
Let's try again
and now create alarms
with some delay between
them to make sure
the saga doesn't trigger.
As we can see the saga hasn't been
executed this time great it's working.
However
since we don't have a corresponding
command handler were getting an error
so let's fix that real quick.
Let's head over to the alarms
application commands folder
and let's create a
new file they're called
notify facility supervisor
command dash handler that
s.
Unless add the
following code inside.
You might have noticed the
note we added in the code here
and this is because we don't have an
email or text message service implemented
in our project.
Of course any real
world application
we would use a
notification service here.
In our case
we're just going to log something else
that we know we have hit this hanlon.
All right so now that we
have this class and place
less register at any
alarms module js file.
Let's save our changes
head over to our
terminal and let's create
multiple alarms in a
short period of time again.
Let's switch to the
other terminal window
and as we can see the saga has been
executed and then notify facility supervisor
command has been processed by
the handler we just created fantastic.
So
we already demonstrated how we can
use saga to construct time-based workflows.
Well this is a common use case.
Were not yet merging
different streams together
which could come in
very handy especially
when dealing with
large distributed systems.
Also
joining events dreams
might be particularly useful
when implementing
compensating transactions.
If you're not familiar with
compensating transactions
they are the car concept
that transactions can
potentially be reversed by
processing another transaction
with the opposite effect.
In our case.
Let's look at an example
just to experiment
where we created yet
another saga that triggers
a command every time
an alarm has created
and it has not been
acknowledged within a minute.
Let's take a look and
see how we could do that.
Let's head over to the
saga directory and create a
new unacknowledged
alarms dot saugatuck t s file.
And inside
let's add the following code.
Now
inside of the start method.
Let's use the of type
decorator to filter out
only the alarm acknowledged
event events first.
Next
let's do the same for the
alarm created event events.
Now
let's make use of both streams.
So essentially what we're doing here
is that we are waiting for an alarm to be
acknowledged
within fifteen seconds.
Know
we lowered the time to fifteen
seconds for demonstration purposes
since waiting for a
minute would take too long.
To do so
we're using the race operator that takes
two or more observables as input and returns
an observable that
amidst the first value
from any of the
input observables.
If timer amidst first then
we know that the alarm
has not been acknowledged
within fifteen seconds.
Also.
You can see that we're using the filter
operator to filter out only the alarm
acknowledge events that
correspond to the alarm
created event that we
are currently processing.
We are accomplishing this
by comparing the alarm
ID above events it's.
When the alarm has acknowledged
were using the first operator to emit only
the first value from the input observable
and then we're using
the merge map operator
to map value to an
empty observable
that never admits.
This way we're essentially
ignoring the alarm created event
as as already been acknowledged.
And last but not least
let's add the map operator.
Here were simply logging
the alarm name and
issuing the notify facility
supervisor commands.
Note that this mapping
function will only be executed.
If the alarm has not been acknowledged
within fifteen seconds since the predefined
empty observable never admits.
All right so let's save our changes and
head over to the alarms module t s file.
Here
let's register the unacknowledged
alarm saga class as a provider.
Great.
Now at this and place
let's head over to our terminal
and let's create a new alarm.
But this time
let's not acknowledge it yet.
Instead
let's wait for fifteen seconds
and let's see what happens.
As we can see in the terminal.
The saga
has been executed and then notify facility
supervisor command has been dispatched.
Excellent.
Let's try again and this time
let's acknowledge the alarm before the
fifteen seconds passes to see what happens.
Let's switch to the
other terminal window
and let's wait again
for fifteen seconds.
And as we can see
nothing happened this time
the alarm has been acknowledged
and our saga didn't trigger
everything's working
as expected great.
In this final lesson we have
learned about what sagas are
and how we can implement them to tackle
some interesting in common use cases that
come up in our nest
Jess applications.
Also if you've been
following along and made
it to this point in the
course congratulations.
We have reached the end of the
advance architecture and patterns course
but
our nest j as journey
is never finished.
We hope you enjoyed all the complex topics
and subjects we dove into in this course
and hope they benefit you
greatly in your future ness projects.
Also
stay tuned for more upcoming nest years
courses on a variety of different topics
and make sure to sign
up for the newsletter
to stay up to date on
everything ness jazz.
See when the next one
and thanks again for
helping support ness js.