‫Hello everyone, and welcome to the Nestjs in practice course.
‫I'm Vasco from the Angular University and I will be your instructor for this course if you don't know
‫Nestjs yet.
‫It's like Angular but for the backend.
‫So with Nestjs we can design our nodejs backend using a lot of the same concepts that we use also in
‫our angular frontend.
‫So things like modules, pipes, services, ET, all of those concepts we can reuse also to design our
‫NodeJS backend.
‫Nestjs also has the advantage that it's very similar to some popular backend development frameworks
‫that you might already know from other ecosystems, such as, for example, the Java Spring framework
‫from the Java ecosystem or the ASP.Net MVC Framework from the Cdash ecosystem.
‫Nestjs is very similar to those popular backend development frameworks because it also has an object
‫oriented, decorator based API that allows us to structure our backend by dividing everything into different
‫types of services such as controllers, repositories.
‫And we can also define our data validation business rules directly on our domain classes using decorators.
‫In this course, you are going to learn from scratch how to design and develop a nestjs backend that
‫is going to take the form of a rest API that queries a MongoDB database.
‫So we are going to be using the mongoose ODM or object to document mapping library for querying the
‫database.
‫If you are not familiar with NoSQL databases or the MongoDB database, please don't worry because we
‫are going to explain everything from scratch.
‫So for this course, no prior knowledge is assumed for Nestjs, MongoDB and Mongoose.
‫In this course we are going to cover in detail the Nestjs backend development framework.
‫We are going to start by providing you with a complete Crud example of data modification and querying
‫in a MongoDB database using Nestjs.
‫And then we are going to move on to some more advanced features.
‫We are going to add authentication and authorization to our Nestjs backend using Json web tokens.
‫We are going to learn how to design our backend by dividing it into multiple types of services such
‫as controllers and repositories.
‫We are going to learn in detail all the nestjs concepts, including services, modules, guards, pipes.
‫ET cetera.
‫We are going to learn in detail how to do custom error handling using nestjs and we are also going to
‫learn how to do data validation using a decorator based approach.
‫For that, we are going to be leveraging the built in Nestjs validation pipe.
‫At the end of this course, you will have learned everything that you need in practice in order to create
‫a backend using common rest principles, query a MongoDB database design and develop your backend using
‫common patterns such as controllers and services.
‫You will learn how to do decorator based data validation, custom error handling and you will know how
‫to secure your backend using authentication and authorization based on Json web tokens.
‫So you will have learned everything that you need in practice for creating a production ready Nestjs
‫backend.
‫So I hope that you will enjoy the course.
‫I want to thank you for watching.
‫If you have any questions about the course, please let me know in the comment section below.
‫And without further ado, let's get started learning Nestjs together.