‫Hello everyone, and welcome to the Nestjs In practice course in this course we are going to give you
‫a complete guided tour of the Nestjs framework.
‫Let's get started setting up your development environment.
‫Let's head over to the Angular University GitHub page and from here let's grab the code that we will
‫need for the course.
‫So if we scroll down, we are going to see here a search box.
‫Let's type in simply nestjs and we are going to see here the first entry should be the Nestjs course.
‫Let's now scroll down and confirm that this is indeed the correct repository.
‫Now we are going to grab this code and we are going to install it in your development machine.
‫There are two ways of doing that, either by cloning the GitHub repository or by downloading the branch
‫that we need as a zip file.
‫So the branch that we need at the start of the course is not the master branch.
‫The master branch contains the final code at the end of the course.
‫The branch that you are looking for right now, it's going to be the one dash Start branch.
‫So this is the initial point of the course that we need to grab.
‫If you are coding along as we go through the lessons now, we can download this branch here using this
‫button here, download a zip or if you prefer to use git, we can also clone this repository and switch
‫to the one dash start branch.
‫Now, before installing the lessons code, we need to make sure that you have on your development machine
‫the latest version of Node, so you should head over to nodejs.org and download the current version
‫and not the long term support version.
‫So tools such as the angular CLI tend to work better with the latest version of Node.
‫So once you have node installed on your machine, the only thing that you need is an ID.
‫However, if you want to conveniently switch between the multiple branches that you will need at the
‫beginning of each course section, then I also recommend you to install git on your machine.
‫Git is however optional.
‫You can always download the code as a zip file as we will see.
‫Now, in order to edit the code, we are going to need an integrated development environment or IDE.
‫This course is going to be filmed using the Webstorm, which is an excellent ID that you can download
‫here as a free trial.
‫If you prefer a free IDE, then you can also use Visual Studio code, which is also an excellent IDE
‫and it's completely free.
‫Either way you will have Node and an IDE ready to go in your development machine.
‫Now that we have these essential tools in place, let's switch over here to the Nestjs repository and
‫let's get the code by, for example, cloning the repository.
‫Remember that you can always download it here as a zip file.
‫Either way, once you have the code in your machine, we are going to open it with your IDE of choice.
‫So here we have opened the Nestjs course repository using Webstorm.
‫Now if you downloaded the code as a zip file, you already have the correct code version.
‫However, if you downloaded the code via git by cloning the repository, then you will need to switch
‫branches at this point.
‫So for that let's open here a terminal that in Webstorm can be opened with Alt 12 and let's do a git
‫branch command to see that indeed we are in the master branch now.
‫We will need to switch to the one dash start branch and you can do so in the following way.
‫You are going to run the command git checkout one dash start.
‫Let's now run git branch again and confirm that indeed we are in the one dash start branch containing
‫the code that we need at the beginning of the course.
‫Now, before doing anything else, I recommend that you install all your dependency pieces right now
‫at the beginning of the course.
‫You can do so here on the folder Nestjs course, which is the root of the repository.
‫You need to make sure that you are in the folder that contains here the root package.json file.
‫And from this folder you are going to run the command NPM install.
‫Now this is going to take a moment, but all your dependencies that you need for running the small frontend
‫that we are going to be using are going to be installed once your frontend dependencies are installed.
‫I recommend that at this point in the course you install also your backend dependencies.
‫This way you will have all your dependencies installed with the correct version so that we can focus
‫on the development of our API.
‫In order to install the backend dependencies, you need to CD into the rest API folder, which is this
‫directory here that we can see at the root of the repository.
‫So inside this.
‫Directory, you are going to find a second package.json which corresponds to our back end.
‫So as you can see, this is a separate node project nested inside here, our root repository.
‫So from inside this rest folder we are going to run a second NPM install command.
‫This is going to pull down all our backend dependencies and with this we have all the correct dependencies
‫installed with the right versions.
‫Notice that both the back end and the front end dependencies have package lock Json files.
‫It's important that you don't delete these files and that you run the installation using the versions
‫that are specified inside them.
‫This way you will be sure that everything works during the course.
‫Okay, so we are now almost ready to start.
‫Let's just give a quick test to our front end to see if it's working.
‫So from the root of our project, which should correspond here to the Nestjs course folder.
‫So it's this folder here at the root of your repository.
‫We are going to run the following command NPM start.
‫This is going to start the angular CLI in development mode and the angular development server is going
‫to be serving this small application that you see here on the screen.
‫Now during the course we will review certain parts of this application which is built in Angular, but
‫we are not going to build the application itself.
‫Instead we are going to focus on building the back end after a moment.
‫The angular CLI server is going to be serving here.
‫Our application on Port 4200.
‫Let's have a look at the application.
‫We are going to switch here to a larger window and we are going to see that we have here a login page.
‫Now we will be implementing authentication and authorization later on in the course.
‫Right now we are going to use here the side menu and we are going to navigate here to the courses page.
‫Once we click on courses, we are going to see here the all courses page with a loading indicator.
‫Now this is our application for which we are going to build our rest backend using Nestjs and MongoDB.
‫Let's open here the dev tools and see what is going on here.
‫We are going to open here the network tab and we are going to reload our application to see what type
‫of network requests are being made.
‫So as you can see, when the page starts up, we are doing here a request to slash API slash courses
‫and we are getting here a timeout, which means that our backend is not yet working.
‫So we are going to build this backend step by step and provide here to this screen a list of courses.
‫So this very simple slash API slash courses endpoint is going to be the first endpoint that we are going
‫to build in this course in the following few lessons.
‫Now, one last recommendation while taking the course, it's very important that here when you start
‫your front end to use the command NPM start, so please don't use NG serve directly because your project
‫will not work.
‫The NG serve command alone will not be sufficient.
‫We also need to pass it some extra configuration options like we see here on the screen.
‫So please always run NPM start while starting your front end server.
‫And with this we are all set up and ready to go.
‫Let's get started writing our first rest Nestjs endpoint.
‫This is coming right up in the next few lessons.